<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rant on Bounded-Error Log</title>
    <link>//blog.vero.site/category/rant</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rant on Bounded-Error Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2015 23:55:52 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//blog.vero.site/category/rant/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Points on Photography</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/photography</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2015 23:55:52 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/photography</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Uncohesive blog content, posted as part of a &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/commitment&#34;&gt;daily posting streak I have openly committed to&lt;/a&gt;; standard disclaimers apply. Whew, made it by a few minutes…)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This essay was partly inspired by but mostly orthogonal in purpose to dzaefn’s essay on a similar subject, &lt;a href=&#34;https://zyxyvy.wordpress.com/2012/04/09/humans-photographs-and-names/&#34;&gt;Humans, Photographs, and Names&lt;/a&gt;. I agree with many of its points, although I deviate in that I think it’s more important for my Facebook picture to identify me than to inform about me (there’s the rest of Facebook, plus my maybe half a dozen other sites, for doing so). Part of the problem for me there, and part of the reason I hang on to my nine-letter random handle from fourth grade, is that my names, first and last, are so commonplace. Among the people who share them (according to DuckDuckGo) are a New York Times tech writer, more than one computer science professor, a photographer, a couple doctors, and some guy who did some sort of graphics work for a short clip and two movies. This means that, to somebody not already in my social circles trying to match me to my account, my Facebook photo is my primary tool for disambiguating myself from all these other people, and I don’t think there is anything that could do that job quite as precisely as a picture of my actual face and body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, I agree enough to be bothered by having a profile picture suffering from “the whole extent of photographic informational void”. I always planned to add some GIMP layers to the photo to indicate context and content more precisely. Except I procrastinated and it got more and more awkward to do this as time went by, since as far as I know, normal people update their profile pictures only to reflect more recent events, especially when they’re important. Like, you know, &lt;em&gt;graduating from high school&lt;/em&gt;? So yes, I’ve been waiting to do this for an entire year now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eh, to hell with awkwardness. That’s the spirit of this daily-posting exercise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Fun fact: The code in what I’m about to set as my profile picture, if I don’t procrastinate even more, is real IOI 2014 code I submitted successfully (for &lt;a href=&#34;https://betaveros.wordpress.com/2014/07/26/one-line/&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;rail&lt;/code&gt;, as previously featured&lt;/a&gt;; the visually selected fragment was the key fix for the final bug I fixed). Except I actually had to manually retype my code printout to get the picture because I lacked the foresight (sound familiar?) to save an electronic copy of my IOI submissions.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, I’m glad this isn’t a smiling photo because I feel like it’s easier to appreciate happy posts from a person whom one associates with a serious face, than serious posts from a person whom one associates with a happy face, and I want both types of posts to impact people when I post them. I could be overgeneralizing from my own feelings though. If you are reading this and want to chat me feedback (as way more than one of you has been doing), I’d welcome more data points on this issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s not what I &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; wanted to rant about in this post, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impact Minus Two Weeks</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/impact-minus-two-weeks</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2012 20:14:12 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/impact-minus-two-weeks</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wait, are you serious? Under two weeks left, is that what it’s come to?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happened to my majestic plans to go over every functional equation I failed on, ever? Or to go through a super-intense geometry-immersion period and actually try to develop some of that crazy “intuition” thing? And I have &lt;em&gt;finals&lt;/em&gt; coming up too! I just finished a ludicrous deadline-extended geography project that I am absolutely confident is the crappiest paper of my entire school career so far! And despite a semester of (slacking) classes, my Spanish is still only barely at a usable level! Exclamation marks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t panic… let’s focus on the positive. I am absolutely prepared with my stationery. I bought three spanking new 0.4mm pens that say “Can write for 1000 meters!” because all of my current ones are annoyingly thick and constantly having almost-but-not-quite run out, plus three new mechanical pencils and enough matching 2B lead to last me through college. All the pencils and lead are Pentel. I haven’t done any research, so if something terrible happens in Argentina I know what company to blame, and I am writing it here so I won’t confuse the brands. Also, in view of what happened to SCH’s carry-on baggage last year (luckily there was no geo on Day 1), I got an extra compass I hope won’t be needed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bilingualism</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/bilingualism</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2012 22:11:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/bilingualism</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, as triggered by my confrontation with the Chinese book report (remember? whatever the answer is, it’s okay): a reflection on my incompetence at dealing with two languages, and why this matters, or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can think in both languages. It’s a natural product of our school environment. The two languages often have to complement each other; most of the nerdy terms or globally relevant allusions are English-exclusive (I couldn’t talk coherently about SOPA in any language other than English!), but a lot of cultural and geographical staples around here are Chinese only. And sometimes there are unexpected holes where an innocuous-looking phrase simply has a few too many connotations to translate perfectly (the example I always get stuck on, and have yet to solve satisfactorily with anything short of a full sentence recasting, is “appreciate”.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adventures in Crappy Markup</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/crappy-markup</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2012 21:39:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/crappy-markup</guid>
      <description>There are two big elementary and middle school competitions around this part of the globe. Well, “big” according to “I’ve heard of it”, which is by no means an accurate measure of, well, anything. I don’t go out of my way to look for them any more, even though… hold on, am I still eligible? Whatever. But in any case, diverting any unnecessary energy from the olympiad-proof-training is probably not a good idea now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technological Fails</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/technological-fails</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2009 18:05:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/technological-fails</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;warning&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: My 2009 self wrote this (except for the insertions by my 2013 self). It is preserved for historical interest and amusement, and does not reflect my current beliefs or attitudes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strange things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A (****) of a Lot of (****)</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/a-lot-of</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2008 21:41:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/a-lot-of</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;warning&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: My 2008 self wrote this. It is preserved for historical interest and amusement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arvorie has just spammed my email account with three emails, two of them talking about palindromes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What? The fat in your head?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My latest hard cryptogram, used with a substitution cipher:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>