<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>self-analysis on Bounded-Error Log</title>
    <link>//blog.vero.site/category/self-analysis</link>
    <description>Recent content in self-analysis on Bounded-Error Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 16:01:01 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//blog.vero.site/category/self-analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Olympiads: The Infinitely Overdue Retrospective</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/olympiads</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 16:01:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/olympiads</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I put this question in my FAQ, because at least two people have asked me this question, and that’s how frequent a question needs to be to be on my FAQ: I got an IMO&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; gold medal in 2012, as a ninth grader, and an IOI gold medal in 2014, as an eleventh grader. I could have kept going to either, or even decided to try taking the IPhO or something, but I didn’t. Why not?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The short answer: It was a rough utilitarian calculation. By continuing, I would probably displace somebody else who would gain more from being on an IMO/IOI team than I would. Besides, I wanted to do other things in high school, so I wasn’t losing much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the short answer actually captures most of my thinking when I made the decision back then, and it’s not really new; I said as much at &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/time&#34;&gt;the end of 2013&lt;/a&gt;. But behind it was a lot of complex thoughts and feelings that I’ve been ruminating over and trying to put into words for the better part of a decade. Hence, this post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a natural question that precedes the frequently asked one that I have never been asked, something I am now realizing I never honestly asked myself and never tried to answer deeply: Why did I participate in the IMO and the IOI in the first place?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music II</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/music-ii</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 15:50:43 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/music-ii</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I first made myself commit to posting weekly, I was trying to make myself spend a little time every day of the week thinking and writing and whittling away at old drafts. Instead I’m here at 10:40 PM basically starting a brand-new post. Oh well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I last &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/music&#34;&gt;blogged about music in 2013&lt;/a&gt;. I tagged two other posts with “music” since then, but neither is particularly deep: &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/8-songs&#34;&gt;8 Songs for 18 Years&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/drop-in&#34;&gt;Drop-In Filler&lt;/a&gt;. Let’s continue the tradition of self-analysis part IIs from nowhere…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I meditated a little bit in &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/conversations&#34;&gt;Conversations&lt;/a&gt; about “lacking experience or interest in a lot of the commonly discussed culture.” I think this applies to me and music as well, although not as fully. Back in Taiwan, when mentally bracing myself for coming to the U.S. for college, I sometimes worried about not knowing enough about pop music and bands and not listening enough to popular albums, and having trouble integrating into the culture for this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turns out, among the communities I wandered into and friends I made, it was a more frequent obstacle that I didn’t know enough about classical music and composers. Whoops. Some of the names rang faint bells from either music class or conversations with high school friends who did do classical music, but I could not identify or remember any styles or eras, and would remember composers only by unreliable first letters or unusual substrings of their names.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gaming</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/gaming</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 16:55:32 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/gaming</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s another weekend, isn’t it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m out of deep things to say. I don’t usually have deep things to say. Sorry to anybody who subscribed hoping for more things like the last post. This is basically going to be a personal stream of consciousness post. But it’s a stream with a long ancestry, since I apparently wrote 400 words about it in a WordPress draft four years ago. This was way back before I even started writing post drafts in Markdown on my computer instead of directly in WordPress, so I guess it must be an interesting topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Four years ago, Brian&lt;sub&gt;2012&lt;/sub&gt; was suddenly struck by how many of the people he knew were such serious gamers. But let’s go back even earlier, shall we?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A long long time ago, when I was in elementary school or so, my parents had some sort of reward system where I had to do productive things, like study or do chores or write diary entries or practice the piano or something, to earn time on the computer for games. “Gaming time” was a currency. I enjoyed saving up lots of thirty-minute increments and knowing I had the freedom to using them slowly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That much I remember; the details of how it worked are very fuzzy and I’m not sure what I played in those thirty-minute increments either. I think there was Neopets and Runescape and Club Penguin. (My Neopets account still sees sporadic activity, because I get really really bored sometimes…)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;I reached the highest bank account level today (after almost exactly 12 years, apparently) &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/Jb9zyWcjRw&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/Jb9zyWcjRw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Brian Chen (@betaveros) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/betaveros/status/749362619044077568?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;July 2, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conversations</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/conversations</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 13:10:21 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/conversations</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the most unexpectedly different facets of life during my internship has been the meals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not talking about the food; it’s certainly different in a fantastic way (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/DropboxTuckShop/?fref=ts&#34;&gt;Dropbox’s food (link to Facebook page)&lt;/a&gt; is like something out of a high-end restaurant), but I knew that before coming already. Also of note is the way I started eating ∞% more ramen over the weekends than I did over the entire school year at MIT, because here I can’t buy that many groceries without them spoiling and am amazingly lazy in this new environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, this (deadlined, so not that well-thought-out, but whatever) post is about conversations at meals, which happen basically every lunch and some dinners when my team eats together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve never had any regular experience like it. Of course I’ve had many meals at home with family, but they feel different because, well, it’s family and we have so many topics in common. I went to the same school for twelve years and we didn’t generally use a cafeteria; we just ate at our desks in our classrooms, or while doing things like attending club meetings or taking makeup tests. Sometimes if people felt like it they would push desks together to eat, but eating by oneself was totally normal. (At last, I feel like that was what it was. It seems so far away now that I don’t trust my memory, which is pretty sad… I faintly suspect I would have this experience in a more stereotypical American high school. But this is mostly just based off the cafeteria in &lt;cite&gt;Mean Girls&lt;/cite&gt;, a movie I only watched in its entirety on the flight here, which is weird because I know I’ve seen the “The limit does not exist!” part much much earlier. /aside)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And at MIT? “Time is an illusion. Lunchtime doubly so.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am glad for these conversations over lunch because I get to know my team more personally (and don’t have to awkwardly eat alone in the bathroom), but they’ve also given me a lot of time to ponder my (lack of) conversation skills.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[insert name here]</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/insert-name-here</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2016 15:31:22 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/insert-name-here</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(I’m making random short posts to entertain certain people during spring break.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since air-dropping into this crazy cultural salad bowl of a place, I’ve met a lot of people whose names get mispronounced. All sorts of long vowels and short vowels and consonants and word boundaries that jump across languages unpredictably. As a result, people often acquire nicknames or alternative names to get called by, whether actively, passively, or somewhere in between.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In contrast, my name is easy and boring. Now, I rather doubt I’d want an exciting name, in the sense of a name that everybody mangles in excitingly different ways. I’m not exactly dissatisfied with people calling me “Brian”. It just strikes me that I think I’ve gone my entire life without a meaningful nickname or even meaningful derivative of my name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(I’m ignoring the transposition. Why am I ignoring the transposition? I’m not sure I can rationally justify that, but thinking about it makes me cringe, which is the reason I’m delicately avoiding explicitly writing out what nickname I refer to by “transposition”. I will just say it is rather uninspired… and also, perplexingly to me, used by accident a lot…)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zootopia</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/zootopia</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 14:27:21 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/zootopia</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(So. It’s spring break. Two-week-late post, and somehow by the end it’s all aboard the angst train again?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two Sundays ago, I mobbed with a small group of MIT furries to watch &lt;cite&gt;Zootopia&lt;/cite&gt;, the recent highly-reputed Disney movie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Before anything else, first there were the previews. I was impressed that every single one of them — there were six or so — was about an upcoming movie featuring anthropomorphic animals front and center. Let me see if I can remember all of them… in no particular order, &lt;cite&gt;Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles&lt;/cite&gt;, &lt;cite&gt;The Secret Life of Pets&lt;/cite&gt;, &lt;cite&gt;The Jungle Book&lt;/cite&gt;, &lt;cite&gt;Storks&lt;/cite&gt;, &lt;cite&gt;Finding Dory&lt;/cite&gt;, and &lt;cite&gt;Ice Age: Collision Course&lt;/cite&gt;. &lt;ins datetime=&#34;2016-04-09T05:10:42+00:00&#34;&gt;edit: Oh, also &lt;cite&gt;Angry Birds&lt;/cite&gt;.&lt;/ins&gt; Wow, I said, they know their audience.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went into the movie with a vague impression that &lt;cite&gt;Zootopia&lt;/cite&gt; was more adult-oriented than most Disney films — not in the naughty way, but in general making a lot of jokes and invoking a lot of parallels that I think only adults might have the experience to get. My suspicions were confirmed a few lines into the movie, where there was a joke about taxes I cracked up at but can’t imagine that children a few years younger would have found funny. If you the reader haven’t watched it, I hope that was vague enough not to ruin the start for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(To be fair — and, uh, some parts of the internet are kind of big on this fact — the film also at one point enters a nudist colony. Fortunately (?), &lt;a href=&#34;http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/AnimalsLackAttributes&#34;&gt;Animals Lack Attributes&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humor aside, I think the movie also deals with some weighty and nuanced themes, ones that would take more life experience to fully appreciate than the themes of most Disney movies. The social commentary is very clear. Possibly bordering on too blatant for my tastes — even though the whole movie is kind of Funny Talking Animals, there are some animal species for which it’s really easy to guess which human demographic groups they might be symbolizing, to the point where I can already imagine the other side of the debate. You won’t need a PhD in literature to figure out the parallels; you wouldn’t even need an AP English Literature class. But, I think, it still works. It’s like &lt;cite&gt;Animal Farm&lt;/cite&gt; on training wheels.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Fiction (Part 2.5)</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/more-fiction-2-5</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 20:27:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/more-fiction-2-5</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is not Part 3. It’s just two things I thought of tacking on to &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/more-fiction-2&#34;&gt;part 2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What can I say? Part 2s are easy blog post fodder; Part 2 appendixes are even easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One, there’s one other wall I run into often during those rare attempts when I get motivated enough to try to write a story: naming characters is hard. At least, it provides an excellent motivational roadblock whenever I even consider committing a story to paper, a point before I’ve actually written anything at which I think “maybe I should give up and go on Facebook instead” and proceed to do so. Aggh. And I think there’s more than one reason for this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
I have trouble coming up with names to some degree. Sure, it’s easy to browse BabyNames.com and look for choices, but a lot of the names there are really weird and contemplating them for every unimportant character kind of rips me out of the immersed mindset.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Reading great stories in English class and elsewhere may have gotten me feeling like every name ought to be a deep meaningful allusion, or at least pun fodder. I feel like I will regret it if I write a story and, a few months and/or chapters down the road, realize I missed a better name or the name I chose has some undesirable connotations in context or provides an atmosphere-ruining coincidence.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I think the real kicker is simply that some part of me is terrified of the awkwardness of giving a character the same name as anybody I know, because then they might read the story and wonder if the character is somehow based on them. And too many of the names that I consider common enough to not lure readers off into looking for hidden meanings are used up that way. This is obviously worst if the character is an antagonist. But it seems just as awkward if the character is a protagonist in accord with everything I’ve written, i.e. a paper-thin character blatantly created for escapist purposes. I am already kind of terrified I might ever meet anybody with the same name as one of my mentally established characters even though I haven’t actually written anything about him. And there’s a well-established convention of &lt;a href=&#34;http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/OneSteveLimit&#34;&gt;not reusing a first name in a work&lt;/a&gt;, so this gets even harder with every work; I’m just as worried, what if somebody thinks this character is related to the other character in that story I wrote in second grade? Oh no!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s like not reusing variable names in a programming language where everything is in the same scope. Positively nightmarish.&lt;/p&gt;
And I actually discovered some evidence this is a thing in my past: I found some stories I wrote in 2004. They are possibly the most extreme exemplification of &lt;a href=&#34;http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/WriteWhatYouKnow&#34;&gt;Write What You Know&lt;/a&gt; imaginable: the main character, Michael, goes to school and makes friends. That’s all.
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/illustration.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/illustration.png&#34; alt=&#34;Illustration courtesy Brian2004&#34; width=&#34;540&#34; height=&#34;543&#34; class=&#34;size-full wp-image-3223&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
Illustration courtesy Brian&lt;sub&gt;2004&lt;/sub&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I kind of want to share these stories, but fast-forward a few years and you’ll see that a classmate named Michael entered my grade and we stayed in the same grade until we graduated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi, Michael. You’re probably not reading this, but the character I created in 2004 is not in any way based on or inspired by you, especially not this image. And unlike later in this post where I name a character after myself, I’m not being sarcastic, really.&lt;/p&gt;
See, this is awkward.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self vs. Other</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/self-vs-other</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2015 23:59:54 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/self-vs-other</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My mom says I blog too much about myself. I am completely guilty of that and this post is mostly not an exception. Sorry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not that I wouldn’t like to write posts about others and for others. But I know more about myself so obviously there’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/WriteWhoYouKnow&#34;&gt;more I can write about myself&lt;/a&gt;. It’s kind of a habit, and it’s been a very personally helpful habit. I discover lots of things when I write introspectively. But I’m a very weird person and a lot of the insightful things I discover when doing this are things I doubt I can generalize to other people. I tried getting a lot of my friends to join HabitRPG when I discovered it, but it was nowhere as effective on them as it was on me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What else could I blog about? What else do people blog about?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;World-event-inspired topics?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Management</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/management</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2015 23:35:50 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/management</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;All through high school I had really high standards for myself. Not the grades, mind you (I admit, humblebrag, my grades were always uncomfortably high, probably as an expected but still sad byproduct of this process (yes, I’m actually complaining about grades being too high. I don’t want my report card to have lots of Bs or Cs, but I really didn’t need to pour enough resources into schoolwork that I graduated as valedictorian, when there were so many other personally and socially meaningful things I could be dedicating effort into creating — but that’s a subject for another post (humblebrags all the way down. Somebody get some internet pitchforks and poke some sense into me))), but simply how I managed my time for doing homework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my opinion: not very well. I always spent too much time surfing the internet and doing things less urgent than homework, then ended up sleeping at midnight or one o’clock or whenever often to finish what I should have done earlier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet, compared to many of my friends (definitely not all, though), that’s not late at all and the amount of buffer time I had between finishing work and having it due was positively luxurious. But then, I suppose, I didn’t have the same amount of math homework. But to counter my excuse, I had additional responsibilities such as practicing olympiad problems and preparing weekend presentations and translating the school newsletter. So I don’t actually know if my workload was significantly lighter than average or not, ergo I don’t know whether my time management skills were significantly better than average or not. It seriously doesn’t feel like they would be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And allegedly, even when I’m procrastinating, it’s more productive than my friends’ procrastination, maybe even &lt;a href=&#34;http://paulgraham.com/procrastination.html&#34;&gt;Paul Graham’s good type of procrastination&lt;/a&gt;. Often when I gripe about how much my former self procrastinated they will ask me what I’ve been doing and, after hearing the answer, tell me this. What have I done to put off homework? Oh, I did some olympiad math problems, committed to my GitHub projects, read a bunch of programming blogs, organized my old chemistry notes from two years ago, and surfed the Stanford Encyclopedia of Philosophy. Yeah. Total waste of time. Meanwhile certain friends surf 9GAG whenever they get the chance. (Which is not to say that I don’t procrastinate in obviously unproductive ways sometimes — I surf reddit, YouTube, and TVTropes of course. Sometimes I even just read my own blog or dig through old folders in my computer. I’m weird. But anyway.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bilingualism II</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/bilingualism-ii</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2015 23:16:46 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/bilingualism-ii</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;我本來還想把這一篇用英文跟中文各打一次來實際比較看看，但這已經被困在草稿匣夠久了。一直做重複、吹毛求疵、沒有效率的修改本來就是我寫心情文時的弊病，如果再要求修改時要保持兩種語言版本的同步的話，大概寫到天荒地老都寫不完。（如果讀者沒有讀過我最近亂發的文章，故事都是這樣的：我覺得我在草稿匣累積了太多寫一半的文章，所以在畢業後，我&lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/commitment&#34;&gt;在六月十一號決定從那天開始每天發文，直到我出國&lt;/a&gt;，目的是強迫自己把那些草稿寫完，中間還亂發很多其他我本來大概不會寫下來的東西。其實還滿有成就感的。另外，如果你的中文沒有很爛的話，如果你在任何地方認為我寫的中文不流暢或是可以寫得更好，請毫不留情的留言批評。這也是一件我發現我在寫中文方面很缺乏的經驗，我會很感謝。當然，根據以往經驗，懇求讀者留言沒什麼機會成功。）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you came to this blog or this post hoping to read English, sorry not sorry. It’s only fair, really, given how many people on Facebook can’t read the massive English textwall posts I’ve spammed them with for so long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;常常有人訝異我的英文這麼好。有時候這些人還會問我怎麼學的－－碰到這種問題我都不知道要怎麼回答。喔，很簡單啊，只要選擇在一個主要說英文的國家出生，然後跟一群從國外回來的同學一起讀有80%的課是用英文上的學校連續讀十二年就好了。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;偶爾也有人知道我是雙語部的或在不同的情況下認識我，反而會覺得我的中文比他們預期的好，例如我的駕訓班教練。其實我在雙語部還是上了十二年的國文課，進度理論上跟其他學校一樣（「理論上」三個字要強調），我也跟身旁很多親戚朋友用中文溝通了更久。比奧林匹亞競賽的經驗應該也讓我認識的上普通國語教學學校的學生，比其他雙語部同學認識的多。所以這應該也不奇怪吧。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;但是。其實我對這兩個語言的精熟度其實還是差很多。日常對話沒問題，不過我對英文細枝末節的部分瞭解的比中文多太多太多了。家裡有不止一本「常見英語錯誤」類的書，我小時候會當小說讀－－我是一個很奇怪的人。在學校課程中，我編輯自己或他人的英文文章是一天到晚的事情，什麼奇怪的句子跟構造都碰過、想過、修理過。還有些時候，我會很自然的寫出一個英文單字，然後發現我不知道為什麼自己會知道這個單字的意思，但就是有一種感覺告訴我，對，subsist的意思就是「存活於只有最基本的需求被滿足的情況」。跟中文比較：有時候，直覺也會告訴我有某一個成語是可以用的，但我只能清楚想到這個成語的兩、三個字。聽起來很「對」，不過我就是想不到第四個字是什麼，或是怕前三個字換成錯別字，再加上懷疑整個成語意思根本不是我模糊腦袋裡現在浮現的，因為我認得這些字字面上的意思，但無法說服自己為什麼它們合在一起可以解釋成這種意思，最後只好放棄，用國小白話文的措詞就好了。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
「總覺得，我在用任何偏離國小程度的白話文的詞彙的時候都是假裝的。」
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我在舊一點的草稿寫出了這個句子，不過那一串「的」字讓我覺得怪怪的，現在想想，沒有人跟我討論過寫出這種或其他奇怪的句子時應該怎麼辦。哪一些「的」可以省略？有辦法把句子重寫（recast）避開嗎？還是不管它，我覺得它聽起來很奇怪純粹是錯覺，多讀一點中文就會發現根本沒什麼大不了的？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;使用兩種語言的方法也差很多。看看這個部落格就知道了。我相信我在學校雙語部外的大部分台灣朋友不會試著去理解我關於自己長篇大論的英文作文，但長篇大論的文章還是我最認真表達自己的地方。反觀我的中文短文，都通常是那種搞笑、釣讚、裝弱的文。（不，我真的很弱。）我不時會發現自己在網上逛到一個陌生人的心情文，看得津津有味。我們之間的關係頂多是朋友的朋友的朋友，我只知道我跟他應該都喜歡數學這個共同點罷了，但因為語言，我在那些瞬間覺得自己瞭解他勝於瞭解幾乎所有在我身邊講中文的朋友。我自己怎麼看這件事都覺得不合理，有點慚愧。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我回去讀了&lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/bilingualism&#34;&gt;我第一次寫的關於雙語的文章&lt;/a&gt;，可能有一點過火：後來證實，在我的朋友中似乎真的有會純粹為了抒發感情而寫七言律詩的人。而且，我講中文的朋友圈裡，文學類佔的比例本來就應該比他們在整個社會裡佔的比例少很多。在學校跟在生活裡，吸收英文多於中文（而且數學多於英文）是我做的選擇，只是我自己不知道選擇的中介點好不好罷了。是否，我花在跟講中文的親戚朋友互動的力氣不夠？&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Fiction (Part 2)</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/more-fiction-2</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2015 23:47:49 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/more-fiction-2</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/more-fiction-1&#34;&gt;Part 1 was here&lt;/a&gt;. This is still part of the &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/commitment&#34;&gt;daily posting streak I have openly committed to&lt;/a&gt; and standard disclaimers still apply. Just as in &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/fiction&#34;&gt;my original post&lt;/a&gt;, back to the flip side — let’s see what I have to do to &lt;em&gt;write&lt;/em&gt; fiction to my own satisfaction. And this time I have a guide: the list I made in the first part of this post. Could I create fiction I would enjoy reading?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1: I enjoy calling things before they happen…&lt;/p&gt;
2: …I also enjoy the Reveal for questions when the author has done something clever I didn’t catch…
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, obviously, I can’t predict things in my own plot. But I can develop riddles in the plot, set up expectations and drop subtle clues and use Chekhov’s Tropes. Can I?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Fiction (Part 1)</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/more-fiction-1</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2015 13:41:12 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/more-fiction-1</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m going to do it again! I’m going to break a post into parts to milk it for the &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/commitment&#34;&gt;daily posting streak&lt;/a&gt;. Desperate times call for desperate measures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is mostly a self-analysis post though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WARNING: &lt;a href=&#34;http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/JustForFun/TVTropesWillRuinYourVocabulary&#34;&gt;This post contains many, many TVTropes links.&lt;/a&gt; If you are like me and need to be productive but are &lt;a href=&#34;http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/TVTropesWillRuinYourLife&#34;&gt;liable to being sucked into TVTropes&lt;/a&gt;, maybe you should find a way to commit to not clicking on any of these links, or just stop reading. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://xkcd.com/609/&#34;&gt;obligatory xkcd&lt;/a&gt; is kind of long and also featured on one of the TVTropes links I’ve already made, so I’m not going to embed it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/fiction&#34;&gt;blogged about this before in 2013&lt;/a&gt; — how I felt that the analysis trained into me by English class was dulling my ability to appreciate and write the types of fiction I really enjoyed. After thinking about it I realized the mismatch goes deeper than that. Because the things I seek the most in fiction are escapism and entertainment. I like simple fiction with obvious (though maybe not &lt;a href=&#34;http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/Anvilicious&#34;&gt;that obvious&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;a href=&#34;http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/AnAesop&#34;&gt;Aesops&lt;/a&gt; and extreme economy of characters via making all the reveals being of the form “X and Y are the same person” (which does not quite seem to be a trope but may be an occurrence of &lt;a href=&#34;http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/ConnectedAllAlong&#34;&gt;Connected All Along&lt;/a&gt;, with the most famous subtrope being &lt;a href=&#34;http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/LukeIAmYourFather&#34;&gt;Luke, I Am Your Father&lt;/a&gt; (which is &lt;a href=&#34;http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/BeamMeUpScotty&#34;&gt;a misquote&lt;/a&gt;!), and is also one common &lt;a href=&#34;http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/StockEpilepticTrees&#34;&gt;Stock Epileptic Tree&lt;/a&gt;, so maybe this isn’t the best example), because not only are such reveals fun, they make the plot simpler. What can I say, it works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The qualities of being thought-provoking or heartwarming are only bonuses for me; needless &lt;a href=&#34;http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/JigsawPuzzlePlot&#34;&gt;complexity in the number of characters or plots&lt;/a&gt; is a strict negative. Sorry, I don’t want to spend effort trying to remember which person is which and how a hundred different storylines relate to each other if they don’t build to a convincing, cohesive, and &lt;em&gt;awesome&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/TheReveal&#34;&gt;Reveal&lt;/a&gt;, and often not even then. And I like closure, so I feel pretty miserable when writers &lt;a href=&#34;http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/KudzuPlot&#34;&gt;resolve a long-awaited plot point just to add a bunch more&lt;/a&gt;. Because of this I am ambivalent about long book series; most of my favorite works of fiction have come in long series but starting a new one always gives me &lt;a href=&#34;http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/CommitmentAnxiety&#34;&gt;Commitment Anxiety&lt;/a&gt;. Even when there’s closure, when I finish an immersive movie or book I’m always left kind of disoriented, like I’ve just been lifted out of a deep pool and have to readjust to breathing and seeing the world from the perspective of a normal person on land. I like when I’m reading good fiction, but I don’t like going through withdrawal symptoms. If I want to read complicated open-ended events, I’ll go read a history textbook, because at least the trivia might come up useful some day; if I want tough problems I’ll just look at real life and think about the possibility of college debt and having to find a job and everything. (If it wasn’t obvious yet, this is why I hyperbolically hate on &lt;cite&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;/cite&gt; often.) Even worse than all of this is multiple paragraphs full of scenery and nothing else, unless of course parts or maybe all of the scenery are &lt;a href=&#34;http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/ChekhovsGun&#34;&gt;Chekhov’s Guns&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some part of me is embarrassed to admit this because I’ve been educated for so long about deep literature that makes social commentary or reveals an inner evil of humanity or whatever. But then again, I don’t really need an education to appreciate the simple, fun fiction I apparently do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So: there are a lot of famous classics or mainstream works I can’t really enjoy too much, or in some cases, at all. And yet, sometimes a random story or webcomic will appear and I just won’t be able to stop reading. Why? I decided to try making a list of things I like in fiction:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Standard Deviations</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/three</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2015 19:30:42 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/three</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A PSYCHOLOGICAL TIP&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever you’re called on to make up your mind,&lt;br /&gt; and you’re hampered by not having any,&lt;br /&gt; the best way to solve the dilemma, you’ll find,&lt;br /&gt; is simply by spinning a penny.&lt;br /&gt; No — not so that chance shall decide the affair&lt;br /&gt; while you’re passively standing there moping;&lt;br /&gt; but the moment the penny is up in the air,&lt;br /&gt; you suddenly know what you’re hoping.&lt;/p&gt;
— Piet Hein
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;By the way&lt;/em&gt;, apparently spinning a penny is a terrible randomization process; studies have shown they &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.smithsonianmag.com/science-nature/gamblers-take-note-the-odds-in-a-coin-flip-arent-quite-5050-145465423/&#34;&gt;come up tails &lt;strong&gt;80%&lt;/strong&gt; of the time.&lt;/a&gt; Tossing or flipping is better but there’s still a faintly biased &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.stat.berkeley.edu/~aldous/157/Papers/diaconis_coinbias.pdf&#34;&gt;51% chance it lands with the same face it started with (PDF link)&lt;/a&gt;. Entirely irrelevantly, is the meter amphibrachic? Nice. I’m sorry, but the impenetrable English names they give to metrical feet just sound so cool.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As May 1 has been coming up, I’ve been half-seriously giving this advice to others who still haven’t decided. But I knew this wouldn’t work for me. I knew where I intuitively wanted to go all along.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reasons holding me back were more… reasonable. Mostly the money. Call it an id-superego conflict.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t know if the difference between my choices would mean I’d have to take out loans, or work a lot during college, or both. I don’t think either of those things would be difficult. I think tech internships over the summer could just cover the parts assigned to parental contribution (which I’m not going to let my parents pay, unless they start earning &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; more money than expected) and I think I have the skills to get those internships. But of course that’s a tradeoff. Maybe there will be something more self-actualizing or more helpful to my future career that I could do during the summer. I’m not so sure that I’ll find the same drive to program for a job instead of for a personal project I really want to use myself, or for putting off something more boring. I don’t know yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Get it? Drive? Program? Um, never mind, I guess that’s a hardware problem.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>College Questions (unprotected ver.)</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/college-qs</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2014 19:54:05 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/college-qs</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post, or most of it, was published password-protected once because… well, I explain that below. (To the one person who actually bothered asking me for the password, just so you know, I did add and rewrite parts. More than a few.) I forgot how distinctly powerful a disincentive a large 2300-word block of text is to the average person, especially when the subject of half of those 2300 words is teenage angst (I’ve already linked to &lt;a href=&#34;https://xkcd.com/1370/&#34;&gt;xkcd 1370&lt;/a&gt; in enough places so I’m not even going to embed it here) interweaved with an insufferable amount of rationalist jargon. This will probably filter my readership more than sufficiently already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have still decided to protect one detail of the thought process, though. But even after that, I guess I do care more about how many people read this than I do for most of my other posts, so here’s a primitive attempt to gauge interest; if you choose anything beyond the first choice, I would also appreciate if you leave a comment, even if you don’t think you have anything to add:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ins datetime=&#34;2017-11-24T18:33:34-0500&#34;&gt;
edit: This poll has been removed, it wasn’t very interesting anyway.
&lt;/ins&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven’t posted for a long period again, but I don’t feel too bad about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, until I look carefully at my blog draft folder and remember that I have 90%-finished drafts about the two debate competitions I went to (November 2013 and March 2014), and winning the previous Mystery Hunt (January 2014), and my summer trip to Penghu (July 2013). Which will probably never get posted out of awkwardness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I’ve been busy, completely righteously busy, with college apps to write and algorithm classes to teach and speeches to write and a math club to sort-of lead and all the typical homework besides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then (for those of you who don’t have me as a friend on Facebook) I got accepted to MIT and Caltech early.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And for a few days after that, I checked Facebook about sixteen times a day for the Class of 2019 group discussion, except for one day when I really needed not to, thanks to the power of committing to my HabitRPG party to do something. I am increasingly learning that procrastination is something that has to be actively and strategically fought. But that’s not what this post is about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;College.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fiction</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/fiction</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2013 11:54:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/fiction</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“I like fantasy books! I used to read a lot of Eoin Colfer.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What does that mean, &lt;em&gt;used to&lt;/em&gt;? You don’t read anymore? That’s so &lt;em&gt;sa-a-a-ad&lt;/em&gt;…”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our teacher and I had this conversation during our first English class, and I realized I agreed with her. Well, no, of course I still read: news articles, r/AskReddit threads, and the books we get assigned in class. But not fiction, almost. As I later mentioned to my teacher, I followed Sam Hughes’ &lt;a href=&#34;http://qntm.org/ra&#34;&gt;Ra&lt;/a&gt; avidly (something I highly recommend). That was it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does my present self still think of Eoin Colfer? Although I adored the &lt;i&gt;Artemis Fowl&lt;/i&gt; books when I was younger, my interest faded, but not before I had recommended it to my sister. The conversation spurred me to get out the seventh &lt;i&gt;Artemis Fowl&lt;/i&gt; book, which I had stopped reading halfway through a year ago, and finish it. It was still true that I didn’t like it as much, because I couldn’t feel the high stakes strongly in the book and I found that the joking asides compounded the problem. But a few days later, when we took a trip to the Taipei library, I found the eighth book and borrowed it, plowing through nine-tenths of the book before we left. The ending seemed to be happy but still felt counterintuitively poignant for me. In any case, I had closure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what’s the lesson? Authors vary in output too. I was naïve to suppose that because I found this book boring, I had outgrown all books that were even vaguely similar. In the same trip, I also borrowed a bunch of other random fantasy books, plus a realistic fiction book about a teenage pregnancy, just for kicks. It turned out to be surprisingly good. In a week, I read four books, cover to cover, despite a typical load of homework and chemo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any excuses I made before about not having enough time simply don’t hold water. Still, I have yet to figure out if this sort of reading is sustainable, because not every book is so engrossing. Far from it…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/music</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2013 23:13:54 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/music</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Isn’t it weird to suddenly talk about this topic?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t think that I have ever talked about music any more than briefly in passing. It might be confusing to my &lt;em&gt;finger quotes&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;audience&lt;/em&gt;, and I worry I’ll seem inconsistent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, a foolish consistency is the hobgoblin of little minds. If you wonder, “I didn’t know that you sang and played the piano, or you liked music in that way — or, at all…” please note that I didn’t know either.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comments</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/comments</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2012 18:46:21 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/comments</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;warning&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: My 2012 self wrote this. It is a little dated and does not entirely capture my current beliefs and attitudes, although I have to say it’s not too far off either. As of 2018, &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/me-and-facebook&#34;&gt;Me and Facebook&lt;/a&gt; is more relevant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/orange-comment.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/orange-comment.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;orange-comment&#34; width=&#34;458&#34; height=&#34;85&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-1383&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Here’s a guilty secret: I like getting feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not restricting myself to painstakingly thoughtful comments that attempt to &lt;em&gt;build upon&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;transform&lt;/em&gt; the post to form an interesting conversation, the kind English teachers are hellbent on promoting. Sure, I get the most kicks out of those, but I’m not picky. Even single-digit pageview bars or a handful of Facebook “like”s give me buzzes of excitement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a guilty feeling, because I also think that that these are unimaginably cheap internet currencies and should not qualify as “meaningful” under a rational mindset. I strongly suspect visitors accidentally click on my blog and leave after five seconds without taking in anything, because I do that all the time to other people’s blogs and sites. Sometimes it is out of boredom, sometimes it is because I actually have something of higher priority to do than indiscriminate reading, sometimes it is simply because I cannot read the language. I’ve seen plenty of people like posts on Facebook based on the poster, only occasionally taking into consideration the first word of the post in question, before actually reading them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, the proliferation of “liking” on Facebook bothers me. I don’t expect everybody to reply meaningfully to everything when they just want to express approval lightly. However, when I see that tiny minority of people handing them out to people in their own threads like programs at a concert, I become indignant. Under their influence, what was originally a straightforward, meaningful badge of appreciation becomes a handwavy gesture that carries virtually no weight, and then I don’t know what to do when I see something I like &lt;em&gt;seriously&lt;/em&gt;. Will clicking that button still express the feeling strongly enough?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I accept that, in our stressful world, a few instant effortless gags that take ten seconds to fully process and approve deserve a place. Nevertheless, the number of people who seem to want to make the “like” a completely passive and automatic action is almost physically painful:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scheduled Blogging</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/scheduled-blogging</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2012 11:43:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/scheduled-blogging</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some bloggers have a regular schedule for posting and forcing themselves to meet the deadlines. In essence, something like “updates every Thursday.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, I think this is a bad idea, because it forces me to write. If my day is boring and uneventful as it quite often is and I still have to crank out a post, it would not be a post that readers would enjoy. Better once-a-month enthusiastic, interesting posts then an ugly stream of tedious drudgery for the visitor to wade through every time, stuff like (quoting one random ancient post):&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bilingualism</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/bilingualism</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2012 22:11:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/bilingualism</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, as triggered by my confrontation with the Chinese book report (remember? whatever the answer is, it’s okay): a reflection on my incompetence at dealing with two languages, and why this matters, or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can think in both languages. It’s a natural product of our school environment. The two languages often have to complement each other; most of the nerdy terms or globally relevant allusions are English-exclusive (I couldn’t talk coherently about SOPA in any language other than English!), but a lot of cultural and geographical staples around here are Chinese only. And sometimes there are unexpected holes where an innocuous-looking phrase simply has a few too many connotations to translate perfectly (the example I always get stuck on, and have yet to solve satisfactorily with anything short of a full sentence recasting, is “appreciate”.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fairy Tale</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/fairy-tale</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2011 18:10:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/fairy-tale</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;warning&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: My 2011 self wrote this. It is selectively preserved for historical interest and amusement from a lot of similar, chronologically nearby posts. I am not as angsty any more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t know where to start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First there was a headache. No biggie, sleep it off. But it’s easy to lose yourself&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pain, the random gusts of nausea, confusion, irritation… it’s another person in this body, speaking a foreign language I can’t even begin to fathom&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;playing by his own rules, won’t let you figure them out. his kingdom, and there’s not even a way to surrender or take the path of least resistance. Every path looks the same from here&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;blackness, vagueness, shadows, defying all interpretations&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Normality</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/normality</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2011 19:51:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/normality</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;warning&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: My 2011 self wrote this. It is selectively preserved for historical interest and amusement from a lot of similar, chronologically nearby posts. That’s all. I am not as angsty any more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So. I was hoping I could blog for once without predictably explaining something about how this doesn’t mean anything about future posts or activity or anything, but apparently I can’t get started without a lame start like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eight months have passed since I started my fight with leukemia. Yes it has been a rough eight months, full of unpredictable pain, nausea, diet restrictions, and freakishly-sized needles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been waiting for I don’t know how long for everything to go back to “normal”, but now that I look back I can no longer imagine the idea. The world, outside, still seems to be rushing at its insane pace towards maximum chaos. Economic and natural crises still seem to be always around the corner. But in here, in the hospital ward, or at home, it’s a really different feeling. I feel completely disconnected. Nothing changes; every day is waiting, waiting, waiting for the future, for a better moment or feeling or achievement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For what, really?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lost</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/lost</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2008 20:09:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/lost</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;warning&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: My 2008 self wrote this. It is selectively preserved for historical interest and amusement from a lot of similar, chronologically nearby posts. That’s all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a life and I still don’t know what to do with it. I like making powerpoints, programming, typing tests, made-up hyperbolic IQ tests, Gmail, and odd things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All that animation has gone to my nerves. And Bookworm Adventures pining. Best word so far: VORACIOUS, which earned me a blue gem tile, which froze somebody. I want to design games for PopCap too, because then I get to play the ones they already have for free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lolcode:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>