<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>motivation on Bounded-Error Log</title>
    <link>//blog.vero.site/tag/motivation</link>
    <description>Recent content in motivation on Bounded-Error Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 15:44:20 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//blog.vero.site/tag/motivation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Musings on Time Pressure</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/musings-pressure</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 15:44:20 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/musings-pressure</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I hate doing things under time pressure, but I have to admit I do a lot more things when time pressure exists. One of the things is writing. Another is posting the things I write. They aren’t very good, but they’re better than writing that doesn’t exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(in case you forgot, I’m still posting this pretty much only because &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/no-excuses&#34;&gt;I made myself post once every weekend&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s interesting that I can impose time pressure on myself by declaring commitment devices by fiat and it works. Other people have developed other methods of doing this — I recently discovered &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.themostdangerouswritingapp.com/&#34;&gt;The Most Dangerous Writing App&lt;/a&gt;, which puts time pressure on you to type every five seconds or it deletes everything you wrote. There are many other ways it’s done.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fiction</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/fiction</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2013 11:54:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/fiction</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“I like fantasy books! I used to read a lot of Eoin Colfer.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What does that mean, &lt;em&gt;used to&lt;/em&gt;? You don’t read anymore? That’s so &lt;em&gt;sa-a-a-ad&lt;/em&gt;…”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our teacher and I had this conversation during our first English class, and I realized I agreed with her. Well, no, of course I still read: news articles, r/AskReddit threads, and the books we get assigned in class. But not fiction, almost. As I later mentioned to my teacher, I followed Sam Hughes’ &lt;a href=&#34;http://qntm.org/ra&#34;&gt;Ra&lt;/a&gt; avidly (something I highly recommend). That was it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does my present self still think of Eoin Colfer? Although I adored the &lt;i&gt;Artemis Fowl&lt;/i&gt; books when I was younger, my interest faded, but not before I had recommended it to my sister. The conversation spurred me to get out the seventh &lt;i&gt;Artemis Fowl&lt;/i&gt; book, which I had stopped reading halfway through a year ago, and finish it. It was still true that I didn’t like it as much, because I couldn’t feel the high stakes strongly in the book and I found that the joking asides compounded the problem. But a few days later, when we took a trip to the Taipei library, I found the eighth book and borrowed it, plowing through nine-tenths of the book before we left. The ending seemed to be happy but still felt counterintuitively poignant for me. In any case, I had closure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what’s the lesson? Authors vary in output too. I was naïve to suppose that because I found this book boring, I had outgrown all books that were even vaguely similar. In the same trip, I also borrowed a bunch of other random fantasy books, plus a realistic fiction book about a teenage pregnancy, just for kicks. It turned out to be surprisingly good. In a week, I read four books, cover to cover, despite a typical load of homework and chemo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any excuses I made before about not having enough time simply don’t hold water. Still, I have yet to figure out if this sort of reading is sustainable, because not every book is so engrossing. Far from it…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
