<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Anesthetic on Bounded-Error Log</title>
    <link>//blog.vero.site/tag/anesthetic</link>
    <description>Recent content in Anesthetic on Bounded-Error Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2015 22:37:45 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//blog.vero.site/tag/anesthetic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Last Step</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/last-step</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2015 22:37:45 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/last-step</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is more than slightly intimidating to go into the room through the big sliding door and see everybody dressed up in full-on green surgical garb with masks and hair nets. I don’t remember this part. Feeling a little vulnerable, I change my clothes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ask to listen to my iPod during the operation — I remember being able to do this during the operation four long years ago when the subject of today’s surgery was inserted into my shoulder — but the nurse(?) says it’s best not to do that because they’ll be using something electric to stop the blood. Instead I can listen to music played from a computer in the operating room. Well, okay then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She escorts me through a bunch of twisty little passages to said room. The computer is a dual-screen Windows XP. The nurse shows me that there is a folder with random albums sorted by year. I poke through the folders and create a playlist in Windows Media Player interleaving &lt;cite&gt;1989&lt;/cite&gt; with a collection of classics from 五月天(Mayday). Then I get on the operating table and wait. One of the nurses compliments me on my choice of the latter band. A few tracks later, I deduce that my interleaving had been to no avail because the media player was set to shuffle. I spend a lot of time on the operating table at first not doing anything except stare at the ceiling. There is a white three-legged contraption there, with each hinged limb ending in a large blue-rimmed circle of surgical lights. There are white sans-serif letters inscribed on the rims, saying Chromophare® E 668 and Berch-something. I think the “something” was a synonym for “say” or “tell”. An after-the-fact search says it’s Berchtold. Typical human memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later I am covered with lots of green cloth, which blocks out the ceiling. Instead, I can only see a clipboard and random paper forms on the left side of my peripheral vision, presumably propping up the cloth. The clipboard is a highly translucent pink. The form on top is yellow and has a box saying something about somebody paying; the form on bottom is white with a black-and-pink-striped right border. The clipboard’s clip also has random streaks of black marker across a white sticker.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>