<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nerdship on Bounded-Error Log</title>
    <link>//blog.vero.site/category/nerdship</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nerdship on Bounded-Error Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2015 23:45:41 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//blog.vero.site/category/nerdship/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>MIT Course Number Mnemonics</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/mit-mnemonics</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2015 23:45:41 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/mit-mnemonics</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I first realized it might be helpful to start trying to remember the correspondence between MIT courses and their numbers, I expected a list of mnemonics for this correspondence would be one of those Things That Should Exist On the Internet. I’m pretty surprised it doesn’t. I mean, MIT has, what, &lt;a href=&#34;http://web.mit.edu/facts/alum-association.html&#34;&gt;at least 100,000 alumni&lt;/a&gt;; as far as I know, nearly everybody who goes there speaks the number correspondence fluently, so they have to learn it; and the science of mnemonics has been with us since the ancient Greeks and people who understand its usefulness can’t be uncommon, especially not in such a prestigious institute of higher education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What gives?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure. Maybe it’s just that nobody has posted their mnemonic set on the Internet out of embarrassment? My mnemonics are pretty bad too, but hey, &lt;a href=&#34;https://meta.wikimedia.org/wiki/Cunningham%27s_Law&#34;&gt;Cunningham’s Law&lt;/a&gt; — if you’re reading, feel free to add better ones in the comments, or to criticize my horribly unenlightened and stereotypical characterizations of your courses, to make this thing better. Or maybe it’s out of concern that nobody else will find it useful? I get that feeling but my &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/commitment&#34;&gt;streak&lt;/a&gt; compels me to ignore it now, as it has for the last dozen posts or so. Or maybe they just didn’t optimize for search engine findability, so I can’t find it? I hope this post fixes that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually, I guess the most likely reason is that maybe most people don’t actually have &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; the course numbers memorized with perfect recall, only the handful of most common ones they and their friends are in, and it’s perfectly fine to ask for clarification when an unknown number comes up in conversation, so nobody ever feels like they need to bother with mnemonics for every single course. Feels sensible to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But anyway, I’m not most people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most comprehensive resource of courses and numbers, including their history, appears to have once been at &lt;code&gt;http://alumweb.mit.edu/clubs/sandiego/contents_courses.shtml&lt;/code&gt;. Many, many links point there. Unfortunately, it is dead and I cannot find its new home, if it has one. Fortunately, there is an &lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.is/xViRP&#34;&gt;archived version on archive.is&lt;/a&gt;; on the other hand, I am not sure whether any updates have occurred since it was archived. A more recent version with course populations from 2005 is &lt;a href=&#34;http://web.mit.edu/mollieb/www/blog/MIT%20course%20numbers.html&#34;&gt;this chart&lt;/a&gt; linked from the MIT Admissions blog post &lt;a href=&#34;http://mitadmissions.org/blogs/entry/numbers_are_names_too&#34;&gt;Numbers are names too&lt;/a&gt;.  Speaking of which, I realize that this chart will likely reduce the effectiveness of using course numbers as a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shibboleth&#34;&gt;shibboleth&lt;/a&gt;, which the blog post appreciated. But I say if this mnemonic set can reduce the cognitive load of a few other MIT students, so they have more time and more energy to spend on academics and self-actualization and various important things, then it’s worth it. (I don’t care either way. I have fun memorizing weird things.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phone</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/phone</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 23:58:02 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/phone</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tl;dr: anybody want to add me on Line or tell/remind me about other phone chat apps? betaveros as always.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wow, talk about uninspired post titles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got a new phone today. Or, well, it’s second-hand, actually. I try to make electronics last a long time, but I think this was justified given the state of my last phone’s screen:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/screen.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/screen.jpg?w=269&#34; alt=&#34;old phone screen, with a visibly malfunctioning black patch&#34; width=&#34;269&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-3142&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides, I’m going off to college and all. Anyway, the phone is pretty cool. It’s a slick shade of red, it came with a cover and everything, and it has one of those fancy 3x3-grid locks. How secure are those again?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, we could just &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/6979524/android-lock-password-combinations&#34;&gt;find the answer on StackOverflow&lt;/a&gt;, but that’s boring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MUMS Puzzle Hunt 2013</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/mums</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2013 21:44:24 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/mums</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/informatix.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/informatix.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;Informatix [MUMS Puzzle Hunt 2013]&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I somehow managed to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ms.unimelb.edu.au/~mums/puzzlehunt/teamstats.html?team=not+AoPS&#34;&gt;get 25 points all by myself&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ms.unimelb.edu.au/~mums/puzzlehunt/&#34;&gt;MUMS Puzzle Hunt 2013&lt;/a&gt;. Well, I pestered chaotic_iak a little with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ms.unimelb.edu.au/~mums/puzzlehunt/2013/puzzles/3.3_Diagnosus_ghQ3AcbJ.html&#34;&gt;3.3 Diagnosus (.html with animated .gif)&lt;/a&gt; but we still didn’t recognize all the Pokémon until hint 3, at which point Google sufficed for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is nowhere near the top, but compared to the usual results of whatever AoPS team I form, it’s amazing. By far the best result of AoPS was on CiSRA in 2010 (46th with 58 points), before I discovered puzzle hunts in AoPS; unfortunately due to people getting older and the influx of younger and younger people to the fora, there are less possible teammates each year and they have less time, so here I am by myself. (Also I could have accepted an invitation from a guy in the some-form-of-Elephant team, but I figure if you can win two MUMS hunts in a row you don’t need any more people.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all: Yay!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>