<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>thoughts on Bounded-Error Log</title>
    <link>//blog.vero.site/category/thoughts</link>
    <description>Recent content in thoughts on Bounded-Error Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 00:37:43 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//blog.vero.site/category/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cook Like You&#39;re Not on MasterChef</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/cook</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 00:37:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/cook</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;series&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;part of the “what I learned after four years at MIT” series, I guess?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was very young, I thought cooking was easy. I sliced plastic vegetables with a toy knife and then Velcroed them back together, ad infinitum. For at least some time, I wanted to be a chef when I grew up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was slightly less young, I thought cooking was hard. My reference points were mostly (1) my parents, who seemed to know how to make a million different dishes in inscrutable ways without thinking, and (2) MasterChef contestants (who I assume were better at cooking than my parents because they were, well, on MasterChef) messing things up and getting kicked off the show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I think I probably elided some meaningful distinctions there in my youthful naïveté. Cooking food that will keep you from getting kicked off MasterChef is hard. Cooking edible food is easy.&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Cooking storebought dumplings in particular is so stupidly easy it’s unfair. More generally, though, most recipes tolerate a lot of substitutions,&lt;a href=&#34;#fn2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; number fudging,&lt;a href=&#34;#fn3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and even straight-up skipping pesky instructions, like the ones in baking recipes where you mix two sets of ingredients separately in specific orders. There are reasons for those steps, but ignoring them and dumping everything into the same mixing bowl usually won’t make your results inedible. You can also just decide to omit ingredients you don’t like. Probably the least tolerant ingredient measurements in recipes are the measurements of baking soda or baking powder, which by the way are different things, in baking recipes. But otherwise you’d really be surprised how many corners you can get away with cutting — I’ve even completely winged one baking soda/powder measurement with decent results. I think this is especially important to know for people from technical backgrounds like me, who have an instinct to treat the numbers in recipes as precisely measured, painstakingly optimized choices to produce the best dish. They usually aren’t, and even if they are optimized for the recipe author’s palate, they probably won’t be optimized for yours.&lt;a href=&#34;#fn4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; And they certainly aren’t optimized for any tradeoffs you might want to make between food quality versus the time and effort you’re putting into cooking. Make the tradeoffs you want. You’re not on MasterChef.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Money Matters</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/money</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 23:34:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/money</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;series&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;part of the “what I learned after four years at MIT” series, I guess?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s some oft-cited psychology studies that suggest that once your salary goes above $75,000, additional money doesn’t make you happier. This sounds like a sage bit of life advice if it were true, the ultimate rebuff against excessive greed and materialism and sacrificing other things for a six-digit salary, but it overstates the case a bit. &lt;a href=&#34;https://80000hours.org/articles/money-and-happiness/&#34;&gt;80,000 Hours’ analysis of money and happiness&lt;/a&gt; is probably the analysis I’d trust the most here; I think it would be more accurate just to say that you get diminishing returns of happiness from salaries above $70,000.&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Still, that was enough for me to decide fairly early on that I wasn’t interested in trying to get a high-paying job for its own sake, or in spending too much effort trying to invest my way to a fortune.&lt;a href=&#34;#fn2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; I wanted my job to be personally satisfying and good for the world, while paying enough for me and my family (current and future) to get by, but I planned to treat any additional money after that as little more than a bonus used for breaking ties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still mostly stand by that decision today, but over the intervening years I realized there were a whole host of reasons to want money that weren’t that selfish at all.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go to Class (Most of the Time)</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/go-to-class</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 09:10:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/go-to-class</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;series&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;part of the “what I learned after four years at MIT” series, I guess? A short post this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can’t begin to count the number of times we were exhorted in high school to go to class. College is different, they said. Nobody is going to force you to go to class any more. This is what you came to college to do, what you paid so much time and money for. It’s on you to make sure you’re learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By and large I followed this advice, until I considered that I might have overcorrected given the exhortations. There are a lot of definitely bad reasons to skip class, chief among them being too lazy to get out of bed. There are also some non-obvious reasons to go to class, such as getting the professors to recognize you — this is a reason to go to office hours even if you’re not particularly struggling with the class, or if you know people who might be able to help you that you could ask more comfortably or more conveniently; professors who know you may eventually be able to give you career advice, research opportunities, or letters of recommendation. (Of course, you shouldn’t try to befriend professors purely for these selfish motives; they’re also good to know just as fellow humans.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there are also plenty of legitimate reasons to skip class. (It’s really unclear how many people out there need to hear this, but my past self did, and I want this draft out of the way-too-long queue of posts.) Here are some.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing for the Mundane</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/writing</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 21:23:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/writing</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;series&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;part of the “what I learned after four years at MIT” series, I guess?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hated timed essays in high school. It’s pretty clear if you skim that part of the blog archives:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My [SAT] essay got a 10 out of 12. It’s an essay I’d be ashamed of posting anywhere else; it’s disgustingly traditional and formulaic. […] This was simply because I knew that using my normal essay-writing mindset, I’d get maybe a 3, because I’d spend the first twenty minutes debating myself over which side I was on and rewrite the introduction ten times. Too bad. I wasn’t there to write a good essay; I was there to get a good score on the SAT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The worst issue is that students do not need to give in-depth explanation of anything they learned. Due to its stringent time limit, the essay portion rewards quick reckless writing much more than deep thought. […] encouraging students to practice writing 25-minute essays in order to improve their college-bound skills is like encouraging people to play Grand Theft Auto in order to improve their driving skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took the Grand Theft Auto analogy pretty far. I’m not proud enough of these posts to link them, but you can find them if you try. In short, past me thought timed essays rewarded writing too quickly, with a disregard not only for facts but for the opportunity to lay out your opinions and thoughts so you could clarify and revise them, which was actually the most valuable part of writing.&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; I conceded that the time limits made sense as a practical concession to allow you to test students’ writing skills fairly,&lt;a href=&#34;#fn2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; but I felt like there was still way too much emphasis on the raw speed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/things</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2019 16:40:07 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/things</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;series&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of a series of posts about what I learned after four years at MIT. We’re ramping up to deeper topics eventually, I promise. Soon™.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is about things. You know, physical objects. Earthly possessions. The indispensable yet fickle chains that bind us to this plane of existence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a freshman I loved getting free stuff. I went into my first career fair starry-eyed, taking free pens and t-shirts and sunglasses and drawstring bags from every company that would let me; I’m sure many other MIT students have gone through the same ritual of passing. There seemed to be no downside. Besides, all the swag was probably small change for most of the companies anyway, due to VC funding or massive government contracts or whatever. So I might as well make full use of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Less normally (although I have no idea by how much), I also hoarded a lot of things that naturally pop up in everyday life, the stuff that would otherwise get thrown away: extra napkins, plastic bags, produce containers, boxes, those payment envelopes that come with magazine subscriptions and exhort you to Subscribe Now To 12 Issues For 20% Off!! At some point I kept the fortune from every fortune cookie I had ever eaten in a tiny resealable bag. The rationale was basically the same: they might be useful some day&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and there was no downside.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Choose an MIT Username</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/username</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 17:39:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/username</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wanted to write a post after two years at college about everything I had learned. I didn’t, firstly because I didn’t make it a priority, and secondly because trying to write about everything I’ve learned at MIT over any nontrivial length of time is the kind of poorly scoped endeavor that I could never complete to my own satisfaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two years came and went, and now it’s been two more years and I’ve learned even more things, not to mention, actually graduated. Jeez. I tried to self-impose a deadline for the big post, but it didn’t work out. There were still too many higher priorities, most of which were also natural consequences of graduating. I also couldn’t bring myself to cut anything, because unlike most of the stuff I haphazardly throw onto this blog, I can actually imagine an audience for just about everything I wanted to write about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally I decided that I would break it into lots of small posts on specific topics. This way, at least the perfectionism can’t bleed between posts too much. The first topic I wanted to write about is simple, mundane, and also fairly limited in scope itself: how to choose your MIT username.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On #DeleteFacebook</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/on-delete-facebook</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 20:09:37 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/on-delete-facebook</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It feels a little surreal watching #DeleteFacebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On one hand, despite how hard it is to keep an issue trending in today’s fast news cycle, this issue has managed to continue burning for a while. Somewhat recently (March 21), we got two high-profile Facebook account deletions from &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/brianacton/status/976231995846963201&#34;&gt;Brian Acton (WhatsApp cofounder)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://techcrunch.com/2018/03/23/elon-musk-deletes-own-spacex-and-tesla-facebook-pages-after-deletefacebook/&#34;&gt;Elon Musk&lt;/a&gt;. Other apparent examples include &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.usatoday.com/story/money/2018/03/28/playboy-dumps-facebook-amid-public-furor-over-users-data-leaks/465156002/&#34;&gt;Playboy and Cher&lt;/a&gt;, or see &lt;a href=&#34;http://time.com/money/5220854/delete-facebook-celebrities-companies-cutting-ties-privacy/&#34;&gt;Time&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cnet.com/news/several-companies-and-people-are-pulling-back-from-facebook/&#34;&gt;CNET&lt;/a&gt; for a few more. Facebook’s U.S. and Canada user base &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.recode.net/2018/1/31/16957122/facebook-daily-active-user-decline-us-canda-q4-earnings-2018&#34;&gt;declined for the first time last quarter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, for me and for a lot of people, the scandal just doesn’t seem that qualitatively different from things we’ve known about Facebook for a long time — its stance on privacy, its psychological effects, its willingness to manipulate the user experience. Why is this time different? (Here’s the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/NoStupidQuestions/comments/87u9ro/why_is_everyone_all_of_a_sudden_mad_at_facebook/&#34;&gt;/r/NoStupidQuestions thread.&lt;/a&gt; I don’t actually know which answer I believe the most.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this time really different? I’m not optimistic. The decline could simply be Facebook running out of potential users to add and space to grow. According to a recent Raymond James survey, about half of surveyed users did not plan to change how much they used Facebook, while only 8% would stop using it, and this may still be an overestimate of people who will actually leave or delete their accounts.&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Mark Zuckerberg himself &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/03/21/technology/mark-zuckerberg-q-and-a.html&#34;&gt;told the New York Times&lt;/a&gt;, “I don’t think we’ve seen a meaningful number of people act on [the #DeleteFacebook campaign]”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I myself have to admit upfront that, even though I &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/me-and-facebook&#34;&gt;barely use Facebook any more&lt;/a&gt; and have carefully contemplated deleting my Facebook account for a long time, I still haven’t pulled the trigger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why? What will it take to change this?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Me and Facebook</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/me-and-facebook</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 15:00:20 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/me-and-facebook</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tl;dr: I don’t use Facebook much. If you want to contact me, I would prefer nearly any other mode of communication. I am also going to stop autosharing posts from this blog onto Facebook. RSS readers are great; get yours today.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently I checked Facebook and it said something like “You’ve added N friends this past T units of time! Thanks for making the world more connected!” and I just couldn’t any more. Facebook friends are not friends. &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dunbar&#39;s_number&#34;&gt;Dunbar’s number&lt;/a&gt; is around 150, maybe double that if you want to stretch it; humans cannot handle that many human relationships. Facebook’s siloed ecosystem is the opposite of connected with the rest of the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is one of many reasons I pretty much don’t use Facebook any more. This is not new, but I’ve never formalized it. Also, I figure others might assume otherwise since I still do have an account and still accept friend requests and post sometimes. Thus, I’m writing this post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are all of the reasons:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s Complicated</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/complicated</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 12:26:52 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/complicated</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On November 8th, 2016, Donald Trump was elected the 45th President of the United States. Along with a Republican House and Senate majority, to boot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world around me is still hurting and reeling from the shock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make no mistake, I am scared. I am scared of the policies and executive orders and legal decisions to come that may strip away many civil rights and send the environment down a worse track faster than anyone expected, and I’m barely in any of the groups that have the most to lose. I have no idea what it’s like to go through this as any of you. I am sorry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I am also scared that this fear is driving my friends and my community away from talking to the people we need to talk to if we want to make sure this doesn’t happen again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve heard a lot of people vilify Trump and Trump supporters. &lt;a href=&#34;https://nmnnmnnmmnnnmnrnmnmnnmn.wordpress.com/2016/11/09/1067/&#34;&gt;Anecdotally, so have others&lt;/a&gt;. It’s an understandable reaction, but a fragile one. 60 million people voted for Trump. &lt;a href=&#34;http://waitbutwhy.com/2016/11/its-going-to-be-okay.html&#34;&gt;Quoting &lt;em&gt;Wait But Why&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, “[P]eople with kids and parents and jobs and dogs and calendars on their wall with piano lessons and doctors appointments and birthday parties written in the squares. Full, three-dimensional people who voted for what they hope will be a better future for themselves and their family.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People voted for Trump. Why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://fivethirtyeight.com/features/trumps-base-is-blue-collar-his-voters-looking-for-a-return-to-better-times/&#34;&gt;FiveThirtyEight profiling a few blue-collar voters&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/wonk/wp/2016/11/08/a-new-theory-for-why-trump-voters-are-so-angry-that-actually-makes-sense/&#34;&gt;The Washington Post interviewing an author who spent a lot of time in rural Wisconsin&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2016/11/11/us/politics/the-women-who-helped-donald-trump-to-victory.html?smid=fb-nytimes&amp;amp;smtyp=cur&#34;&gt;The New York Times on women&lt;/a&gt;. If the articles’ reasons for voting Trump could be summarized in one word, it would certainly be “economy”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then FiveThirtyEight tempers it a little bit with this reminder that &lt;a href=&#34;http://fivethirtyeight.com/features/the-mythology-of-trumps-working-class-support/&#34;&gt;Trump’s supporters are on average more well-off than others&lt;/a&gt;. Here’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2016/07/11/george-saunders-goes-to-trump-rallies&#34;&gt;The New Yorker visiting a bunch of Trump rallies&lt;/a&gt;. SupChina discusses &lt;a href=&#34;http://supchina.com/2016/11/03/many-first-generation-chinese-immigrants-supporting-donald-trump/&#34;&gt;first-generation Chinese immigrants supporting Trump&lt;/a&gt; and racism is a bullet point there, but apparently it’s partly rallied around rap lyrics about robbery that advise to “find a Chinese neighborhood” to steal from, so…? I am not going to go any deeper into this rabbit hole. Then here’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.motherjones.com/kevin-drum/2016/03/trump-voters-are-not-angry-about-economy-really&#34;&gt;Mother Jones arguing against the economy being a big factor at all&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2016/10/15/13286498/donald-trump-voters-race-economic-anxiety&#34;&gt;Vox saying it &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; about racial resentment&lt;/a&gt;. Here’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bloomberg.com/view/articles/2016-11-11/revenge-of-the-deplorables&#34;&gt;Bloomberg on the Clinton campaign’s failure to persuade&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://thefederalist.com/2016/11/11/how-jon-stewart-and-the-daily-show-elected-donald-trump/&#34;&gt;The Federalist on “hyper-liberal late-night comedy”&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.washingtontimes.com/news/2016/nov/9/donald-trump-and-the-new-american-revolution/&#34;&gt;The Washington Times on Trump’s optimism&lt;/a&gt;. I could find hundreds more out there just by Googling, and so could you; and chances are if you’re enough of a voracious reader to be reading my humble blog, you’ve already read some of these.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s complicated.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time, Money, and All That Good Stuff: Part 1 of ∞</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/time-money-1</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2016 15:38:29 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/time-money-1</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had this 5,000-word draft, but I half-abandoned it for being sappy, boring, pointless, and impossible to rewrite to be satisfactorily un-cringeworthy. Instead, let me just tell you a couple random stories and anecdotes that went somewhere near the start. Maybe posting them will motivate me to salvage something from the 4,500 words that go after it and post it. Eventually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some time ago, Namecheap had a discount, so I bought a domain name for 88¢. Unfortunately, the discount only lasted for one year; afterwards, it would cost $29/year to renew. Even though I bought it on a whim and didn’t have much use for it, I &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Endowment_effect&#34;&gt;found myself wanting to keep it more and more&lt;/a&gt; and had a huge mental struggle over whether I could afford it, because wow, $29 is a lot!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, during the same school year, more or less:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Musings on Time Pressure</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/musings-pressure</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 15:44:20 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/musings-pressure</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I hate doing things under time pressure, but I have to admit I do a lot more things when time pressure exists. One of the things is writing. Another is posting the things I write. They aren’t very good, but they’re better than writing that doesn’t exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(in case you forgot, I’m still posting this pretty much only because &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/no-excuses&#34;&gt;I made myself post once every weekend&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s interesting that I can impose time pressure on myself by declaring commitment devices by fiat and it works. Other people have developed other methods of doing this — I recently discovered &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.themostdangerouswritingapp.com/&#34;&gt;The Most Dangerous Writing App&lt;/a&gt;, which puts time pressure on you to type every five seconds or it deletes everything you wrote. There are many other ways it’s done.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pangs</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/pangs</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 15:22:19 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/pangs</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have this memory —&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was a tiny kid, lying in bed and trying to fall asleep, and I started thinking about death and nonexistence, and I thought about how one day I wouldn’t exist any more, that there wouldn’t &lt;em&gt;be&lt;/em&gt; a me thinking my thoughts and perceiving my perspective, and suddenly I was terrified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got up and knocked on my parents’ bedroom door and asked them about this. Maybe. Or maybe I didn’t because the fear was less crippling than the social awkwardness of randomly knocking on my parents’ door in the middle of the night to ask them a question like that; I don’t remember. It was a long time ago, okay?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music II</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/music-ii</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 15:50:43 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/music-ii</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I first made myself commit to posting weekly, I was trying to make myself spend a little time every day of the week thinking and writing and whittling away at old drafts. Instead I’m here at 10:40 PM basically starting a brand-new post. Oh well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I last &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/music&#34;&gt;blogged about music in 2013&lt;/a&gt;. I tagged two other posts with “music” since then, but neither is particularly deep: &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/8-songs&#34;&gt;8 Songs for 18 Years&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/drop-in&#34;&gt;Drop-In Filler&lt;/a&gt;. Let’s continue the tradition of self-analysis part IIs from nowhere…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I meditated a little bit in &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/conversations&#34;&gt;Conversations&lt;/a&gt; about “lacking experience or interest in a lot of the commonly discussed culture.” I think this applies to me and music as well, although not as fully. Back in Taiwan, when mentally bracing myself for coming to the U.S. for college, I sometimes worried about not knowing enough about pop music and bands and not listening enough to popular albums, and having trouble integrating into the culture for this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turns out, among the communities I wandered into and friends I made, it was a more frequent obstacle that I didn’t know enough about classical music and composers. Whoops. Some of the names rang faint bells from either music class or conversations with high school friends who did do classical music, but I could not identify or remember any styles or eras, and would remember composers only by unreliable first letters or unusual substrings of their names.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gaming</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/gaming</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 16:55:32 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/gaming</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s another weekend, isn’t it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m out of deep things to say. I don’t usually have deep things to say. Sorry to anybody who subscribed hoping for more things like the last post. This is basically going to be a personal stream of consciousness post. But it’s a stream with a long ancestry, since I apparently wrote 400 words about it in a WordPress draft four years ago. This was way back before I even started writing post drafts in Markdown on my computer instead of directly in WordPress, so I guess it must be an interesting topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Four years ago, Brian&lt;sub&gt;2012&lt;/sub&gt; was suddenly struck by how many of the people he knew were such serious gamers. But let’s go back even earlier, shall we?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A long long time ago, when I was in elementary school or so, my parents had some sort of reward system where I had to do productive things, like study or do chores or write diary entries or practice the piano or something, to earn time on the computer for games. “Gaming time” was a currency. I enjoyed saving up lots of thirty-minute increments and knowing I had the freedom to using them slowly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That much I remember; the details of how it worked are very fuzzy and I’m not sure what I played in those thirty-minute increments either. I think there was Neopets and Runescape and Club Penguin. (My Neopets account still sees sporadic activity, because I get really really bored sometimes…)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;I reached the highest bank account level today (after almost exactly 12 years, apparently) &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/Jb9zyWcjRw&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/Jb9zyWcjRw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Brian Chen (@betaveros) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/betaveros/status/749362619044077568?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;July 2, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Islam, Headlines, and Definitions</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/islam-headlines</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2016 15:29:43 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/islam-headlines</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post’s topic might be the most controversial thing I’ve posted here ever. I hope the points I want to make aren’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the excuses for not blogging I came up with and then deleted while &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/no-excuses&#34;&gt;rambling about not blogging&lt;/a&gt; was that I’m getting more feelings about real-world real-person issues, things that people take heated positions on — it’s not topics like what food I ate or what games I’m playing in fourth grade any more — and my identity is pretty public here, so who knows what’ll happen. Oh well. I’m probably just paranoid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s also delayed, as the articles I’m talking about are old; the latest two news items are the shootings of Alton Sterling and Philando Castile and then the police shooting at the Dallas rally. That was also really sad, but I don’t think I have anything insightful to say about it. Let me point you to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://mitadmissions.org/blogs/entry/black-lives-matter&#34;&gt;MIT Admissions post, “Black Lives Matter”&lt;/a&gt;, and then for something a bit more optimistic out of a huge range of possible choices, &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@Mandela/my-white-boss-talked-about-race-in-america-and-this-is-what-happened-fe10f1a00726#.wtnr99lp1&#34;&gt;this Medium article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although after I started writing this post, the story about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.indiatimes.com/news/world/muslim-man-hugs-isis-militant-armed-wearing-suicide-vest-before-explosion-saves-hundreds-of-lives-258126.html&#34;&gt;a Muslim man preventing an ISIS suicide bomber&lt;/a&gt; came out, so now this is mildly relevant again. Anyway, I guess the delay is no different from how I put up life posts weeks after the life event happens. So today, I bring you two old news articles about Islam that my friends shared and discussed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Green: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/todd-green-phd/is-islam-responsible-for-_b_10449060.html&#34;&gt;Is Islam Responsible For The Orlando Nightclub Shooting?&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
King: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nydailynews.com/news/world/king-isis-terrorists-aren-muslims-evil-men-article-1.2699463&#34;&gt;ISIS terrorists aren’t Muslims — they’re just evil men hell-bent on carnage and destruction&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second one first, whose argument is, to be frank, weak. I think this piece from &lt;cite&gt;The Atlantic&lt;/cite&gt; by Wood, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2015/03/what-isis-really-wants/384980/&#34;&gt;“What ISIS Really Wants”&lt;/a&gt;, is a better-researched overview of ISIS while still being pretty readable. One caveat is that it’s somewhat old. But its central claim is quite the opposite:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conversations</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/conversations</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 13:10:21 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/conversations</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the most unexpectedly different facets of life during my internship has been the meals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not talking about the food; it’s certainly different in a fantastic way (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/DropboxTuckShop/?fref=ts&#34;&gt;Dropbox’s food (link to Facebook page)&lt;/a&gt; is like something out of a high-end restaurant), but I knew that before coming already. Also of note is the way I started eating ∞% more ramen over the weekends than I did over the entire school year at MIT, because here I can’t buy that many groceries without them spoiling and am amazingly lazy in this new environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, this (deadlined, so not that well-thought-out, but whatever) post is about conversations at meals, which happen basically every lunch and some dinners when my team eats together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve never had any regular experience like it. Of course I’ve had many meals at home with family, but they feel different because, well, it’s family and we have so many topics in common. I went to the same school for twelve years and we didn’t generally use a cafeteria; we just ate at our desks in our classrooms, or while doing things like attending club meetings or taking makeup tests. Sometimes if people felt like it they would push desks together to eat, but eating by oneself was totally normal. (At last, I feel like that was what it was. It seems so far away now that I don’t trust my memory, which is pretty sad… I faintly suspect I would have this experience in a more stereotypical American high school. But this is mostly just based off the cafeteria in &lt;cite&gt;Mean Girls&lt;/cite&gt;, a movie I only watched in its entirety on the flight here, which is weird because I know I’ve seen the “The limit does not exist!” part much much earlier. /aside)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And at MIT? “Time is an illusion. Lunchtime doubly so.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am glad for these conversations over lunch because I get to know my team more personally (and don’t have to awkwardly eat alone in the bathroom), but they’ve also given me a lot of time to ponder my (lack of) conversation skills.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[insert name here]</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/insert-name-here</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2016 15:31:22 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/insert-name-here</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(I’m making random short posts to entertain certain people during spring break.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since air-dropping into this crazy cultural salad bowl of a place, I’ve met a lot of people whose names get mispronounced. All sorts of long vowels and short vowels and consonants and word boundaries that jump across languages unpredictably. As a result, people often acquire nicknames or alternative names to get called by, whether actively, passively, or somewhere in between.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In contrast, my name is easy and boring. Now, I rather doubt I’d want an exciting name, in the sense of a name that everybody mangles in excitingly different ways. I’m not exactly dissatisfied with people calling me “Brian”. It just strikes me that I think I’ve gone my entire life without a meaningful nickname or even meaningful derivative of my name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(I’m ignoring the transposition. Why am I ignoring the transposition? I’m not sure I can rationally justify that, but thinking about it makes me cringe, which is the reason I’m delicately avoiding explicitly writing out what nickname I refer to by “transposition”. I will just say it is rather uninspired… and also, perplexingly to me, used by accident a lot…)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zootopia</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/zootopia</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 14:27:21 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/zootopia</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(So. It’s spring break. Two-week-late post, and somehow by the end it’s all aboard the angst train again?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two Sundays ago, I mobbed with a small group of MIT furries to watch &lt;cite&gt;Zootopia&lt;/cite&gt;, the recent highly-reputed Disney movie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Before anything else, first there were the previews. I was impressed that every single one of them — there were six or so — was about an upcoming movie featuring anthropomorphic animals front and center. Let me see if I can remember all of them… in no particular order, &lt;cite&gt;Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles&lt;/cite&gt;, &lt;cite&gt;The Secret Life of Pets&lt;/cite&gt;, &lt;cite&gt;The Jungle Book&lt;/cite&gt;, &lt;cite&gt;Storks&lt;/cite&gt;, &lt;cite&gt;Finding Dory&lt;/cite&gt;, and &lt;cite&gt;Ice Age: Collision Course&lt;/cite&gt;. &lt;ins datetime=&#34;2016-04-09T05:10:42+00:00&#34;&gt;edit: Oh, also &lt;cite&gt;Angry Birds&lt;/cite&gt;.&lt;/ins&gt; Wow, I said, they know their audience.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went into the movie with a vague impression that &lt;cite&gt;Zootopia&lt;/cite&gt; was more adult-oriented than most Disney films — not in the naughty way, but in general making a lot of jokes and invoking a lot of parallels that I think only adults might have the experience to get. My suspicions were confirmed a few lines into the movie, where there was a joke about taxes I cracked up at but can’t imagine that children a few years younger would have found funny. If you the reader haven’t watched it, I hope that was vague enough not to ruin the start for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(To be fair — and, uh, some parts of the internet are kind of big on this fact — the film also at one point enters a nudist colony. Fortunately (?), &lt;a href=&#34;http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/AnimalsLackAttributes&#34;&gt;Animals Lack Attributes&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humor aside, I think the movie also deals with some weighty and nuanced themes, ones that would take more life experience to fully appreciate than the themes of most Disney movies. The social commentary is very clear. Possibly bordering on too blatant for my tastes — even though the whole movie is kind of Funny Talking Animals, there are some animal species for which it’s really easy to guess which human demographic groups they might be symbolizing, to the point where I can already imagine the other side of the debate. You won’t need a PhD in literature to figure out the parallels; you wouldn’t even need an AP English Literature class. But, I think, it still works. It’s like &lt;cite&gt;Animal Farm&lt;/cite&gt; on training wheels.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pause</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/pause</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2015 16:03:56 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/pause</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are 30 minutes until my laundry finishes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is 2:30 in the morning as I write this. Normal people are not awake at this time of day. It’s possible that normal MIT students are, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been meaning to blog for a while, but things happen and other things happen and still more things happen. From a state of total inexperience in the kitchen, I’ve already managed to single-handedly cook six six-person meals for my co-op, not to mention all the weird meals I make for myself (which is just as well, I don’t think they are of typically mentionable caliber.) I’ve already taken two exams in three of my classes and the big midterm for my fourth. Four puzzlehunts — Simmons, aquarium, Palantir, ΣUMS; five if you perhaps include Next Haunt. Six SIPB meetings. A few bottles of Soylent; I lost count and don’t want to check my room because that’ll disturb my roommate. Θ(3000) zephyrs. And after many weekends of eye-opening group practice, tonight I have to catch a flight to Rochester, NY for ACM-ICPC regionals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sharpies</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/sharpies</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2015 14:59:48 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/sharpies</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As readers of this blog probably know, I am not an MITAdmissions blogger. It was kind of disappointing at the moment, but now I rarely think about it except when I come up with good reasons why I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be an MITAdmissions blogger. One reason is that I am not very good at coming up with advice that could generalize to a wide audience, even an audience only as wide as people at or coming to the &amp;lsquo;Tvte. &lt;em&gt;(There can be only one!)&lt;/em&gt; This by itself probably wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be so bad because there&amp;rsquo;s plenty of generalizable advice to go around, but I also don&amp;rsquo;t like repeating well-known stuff. Don&amp;rsquo;t skip class, except when you really know when you&amp;rsquo;re doing, which you probably think you do when you skip class. Get enough sleep, maintain good study habits, set aside time to keep up with old friends, back up your zarking data, alternate alcoholic and nonalcoholic drinks, do not forget the factor of one-half when computing the area of a triangle. You get the picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s only one piece of advice I can say that I believe is generalizable to any degree, and in particular I think my past self would have appreciated and also had not heard, even in passing, from any other source: Get a Sharpie.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carpe Annum</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/carpe-annum</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2015 14:47:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/carpe-annum</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A fun/interesting/unfortunate/fortunate consequence of the mental world model of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inside_Out_(2015_film)&#34;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Inside Out&lt;/cite&gt; (2015 Pixar film)&lt;/a&gt; (which is a great movie, and I’m saying this as a non-movie-type — I laughed, and I cried, and just omgwtfbbq Disney/Pixar) is that imaginary friends that are capable of autonomous flight are probably immune to being forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unfiltering</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/unfiltering</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 14:00:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/unfiltering</guid>
      <description>People are afraid of the dark
because it holds the unknown
and unknowns are scary.
But maybe it is just as frightening
if we let the light shine everywhere
and believe that because we know everything the light shines on
we know everything.
Perhaps for once
when the sun fades over the horizon
and the darkness returns in its dependable cycle
we should silence the fears
and remember
there is darkness in all of us</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Tests (and a Mysterious New Student)</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/old-tests</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2015 23:57:41 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/old-tests</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Short &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/commitment&#34;&gt;streak&lt;/a&gt; post. And for the uninformed, I’m using &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spivak_pronoun&#34;&gt;Spivak pronouns&lt;/a&gt; for this post just because.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally, when people I don’t already know through math competitions ask me or my parents about something like how to teach their intelligent child to make em really good at math, or even English or whatever, I am skeptical by default because there seem to be a lot of Taiwanese parents who have alarmingly rigid and largely baseless expectations or assumptions about what their children ought to be interested in and excel at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can lead a horse to water, and honestly I think you could find a way to force it to drink if you really wanted to, but you can’t make it enjoy the process of being force-fed. Um. &lt;a href=&#34;https://english.stackexchange.com/questions/36489/eat-is-to-feed-as-drink-is-to-what&#34;&gt;Force-watered? Force-hydrated?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can teach your child math and English, and you could make em ace all eir tests, but you probably can’t make em enjoy the test so much that e decides to create more diabolical versions of these tests to give to eir fictional characters in eir stories for fun!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are all &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;actual illustrations&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; from the old stories I mentioned in &lt;a href=&#34;https://betaveros.wordpress.com/2015/07/24/more-fiction-part-2-5/&#34;&gt;part 2.5 of “More Fiction”&lt;/a&gt;. Stories I wrote in 2004. As a first-grader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is kind of horrifying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/test6blurred.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/test6blurred.png?w=652&#34; alt=&#34;test6blurred&#34; width=&#34;652&#34; height=&#34;458&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter size-large wp-image-3231&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Fiction (Part 2.5)</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/more-fiction-2-5</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 20:27:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/more-fiction-2-5</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is not Part 3. It’s just two things I thought of tacking on to &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/more-fiction-2&#34;&gt;part 2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What can I say? Part 2s are easy blog post fodder; Part 2 appendixes are even easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One, there’s one other wall I run into often during those rare attempts when I get motivated enough to try to write a story: naming characters is hard. At least, it provides an excellent motivational roadblock whenever I even consider committing a story to paper, a point before I’ve actually written anything at which I think “maybe I should give up and go on Facebook instead” and proceed to do so. Aggh. And I think there’s more than one reason for this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
I have trouble coming up with names to some degree. Sure, it’s easy to browse BabyNames.com and look for choices, but a lot of the names there are really weird and contemplating them for every unimportant character kind of rips me out of the immersed mindset.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Reading great stories in English class and elsewhere may have gotten me feeling like every name ought to be a deep meaningful allusion, or at least pun fodder. I feel like I will regret it if I write a story and, a few months and/or chapters down the road, realize I missed a better name or the name I chose has some undesirable connotations in context or provides an atmosphere-ruining coincidence.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I think the real kicker is simply that some part of me is terrified of the awkwardness of giving a character the same name as anybody I know, because then they might read the story and wonder if the character is somehow based on them. And too many of the names that I consider common enough to not lure readers off into looking for hidden meanings are used up that way. This is obviously worst if the character is an antagonist. But it seems just as awkward if the character is a protagonist in accord with everything I’ve written, i.e. a paper-thin character blatantly created for escapist purposes. I am already kind of terrified I might ever meet anybody with the same name as one of my mentally established characters even though I haven’t actually written anything about him. And there’s a well-established convention of &lt;a href=&#34;http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/OneSteveLimit&#34;&gt;not reusing a first name in a work&lt;/a&gt;, so this gets even harder with every work; I’m just as worried, what if somebody thinks this character is related to the other character in that story I wrote in second grade? Oh no!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s like not reusing variable names in a programming language where everything is in the same scope. Positively nightmarish.&lt;/p&gt;
And I actually discovered some evidence this is a thing in my past: I found some stories I wrote in 2004. They are possibly the most extreme exemplification of &lt;a href=&#34;http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/WriteWhatYouKnow&#34;&gt;Write What You Know&lt;/a&gt; imaginable: the main character, Michael, goes to school and makes friends. That’s all.
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/illustration.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/illustration.png&#34; alt=&#34;Illustration courtesy Brian2004&#34; width=&#34;540&#34; height=&#34;543&#34; class=&#34;size-full wp-image-3223&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
Illustration courtesy Brian&lt;sub&gt;2004&lt;/sub&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I kind of want to share these stories, but fast-forward a few years and you’ll see that a classmate named Michael entered my grade and we stayed in the same grade until we graduated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi, Michael. You’re probably not reading this, but the character I created in 2004 is not in any way based on or inspired by you, especially not this image. And unlike later in this post where I name a character after myself, I’m not being sarcastic, really.&lt;/p&gt;
See, this is awkward.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Variance</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/variance</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 23:59:25 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/variance</guid>
      <description>It’s olympiad season. Taiwan placed 18th in the IMO rankings1. Next day there are news stories about how it’s our “third worst performance in history”, and commenters drawing casual arrows from changes in Taiwan’s standardized tests and curriculum to this result, and the Ministry of Education saying they’d review their procedures or something.
What.
Did you forget our performance last year? Do you think our olympiad training system is completely overhauled on an annual basis, or has even a tangential relationship with the overall education system?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self vs. Other</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/self-vs-other</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2015 23:59:54 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/self-vs-other</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My mom says I blog too much about myself. I am completely guilty of that and this post is mostly not an exception. Sorry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not that I wouldn’t like to write posts about others and for others. But I know more about myself so obviously there’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/WriteWhoYouKnow&#34;&gt;more I can write about myself&lt;/a&gt;. It’s kind of a habit, and it’s been a very personally helpful habit. I discover lots of things when I write introspectively. But I’m a very weird person and a lot of the insightful things I discover when doing this are things I doubt I can generalize to other people. I tried getting a lot of my friends to join HabitRPG when I discovered it, but it was nowhere as effective on them as it was on me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What else could I blog about? What else do people blog about?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;World-event-inspired topics?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Management</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/management</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2015 23:35:50 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/management</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;All through high school I had really high standards for myself. Not the grades, mind you (I admit, humblebrag, my grades were always uncomfortably high, probably as an expected but still sad byproduct of this process (yes, I’m actually complaining about grades being too high. I don’t want my report card to have lots of Bs or Cs, but I really didn’t need to pour enough resources into schoolwork that I graduated as valedictorian, when there were so many other personally and socially meaningful things I could be dedicating effort into creating — but that’s a subject for another post (humblebrags all the way down. Somebody get some internet pitchforks and poke some sense into me))), but simply how I managed my time for doing homework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my opinion: not very well. I always spent too much time surfing the internet and doing things less urgent than homework, then ended up sleeping at midnight or one o’clock or whenever often to finish what I should have done earlier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet, compared to many of my friends (definitely not all, though), that’s not late at all and the amount of buffer time I had between finishing work and having it due was positively luxurious. But then, I suppose, I didn’t have the same amount of math homework. But to counter my excuse, I had additional responsibilities such as practicing olympiad problems and preparing weekend presentations and translating the school newsletter. So I don’t actually know if my workload was significantly lighter than average or not, ergo I don’t know whether my time management skills were significantly better than average or not. It seriously doesn’t feel like they would be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And allegedly, even when I’m procrastinating, it’s more productive than my friends’ procrastination, maybe even &lt;a href=&#34;http://paulgraham.com/procrastination.html&#34;&gt;Paul Graham’s good type of procrastination&lt;/a&gt;. Often when I gripe about how much my former self procrastinated they will ask me what I’ve been doing and, after hearing the answer, tell me this. What have I done to put off homework? Oh, I did some olympiad math problems, committed to my GitHub projects, read a bunch of programming blogs, organized my old chemistry notes from two years ago, and surfed the Stanford Encyclopedia of Philosophy. Yeah. Total waste of time. Meanwhile certain friends surf 9GAG whenever they get the chance. (Which is not to say that I don’t procrastinate in obviously unproductive ways sometimes — I surf reddit, YouTube, and TVTropes of course. Sometimes I even just read my own blog or dig through old folders in my computer. I’m weird. But anyway.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bilingualism II</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/bilingualism-ii</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2015 23:16:46 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/bilingualism-ii</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;我本來還想把這一篇用英文跟中文各打一次來實際比較看看，但這已經被困在草稿匣夠久了。一直做重複、吹毛求疵、沒有效率的修改本來就是我寫心情文時的弊病，如果再要求修改時要保持兩種語言版本的同步的話，大概寫到天荒地老都寫不完。（如果讀者沒有讀過我最近亂發的文章，故事都是這樣的：我覺得我在草稿匣累積了太多寫一半的文章，所以在畢業後，我&lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/commitment&#34;&gt;在六月十一號決定從那天開始每天發文，直到我出國&lt;/a&gt;，目的是強迫自己把那些草稿寫完，中間還亂發很多其他我本來大概不會寫下來的東西。其實還滿有成就感的。另外，如果你的中文沒有很爛的話，如果你在任何地方認為我寫的中文不流暢或是可以寫得更好，請毫不留情的留言批評。這也是一件我發現我在寫中文方面很缺乏的經驗，我會很感謝。當然，根據以往經驗，懇求讀者留言沒什麼機會成功。）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you came to this blog or this post hoping to read English, sorry not sorry. It’s only fair, really, given how many people on Facebook can’t read the massive English textwall posts I’ve spammed them with for so long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;常常有人訝異我的英文這麼好。有時候這些人還會問我怎麼學的－－碰到這種問題我都不知道要怎麼回答。喔，很簡單啊，只要選擇在一個主要說英文的國家出生，然後跟一群從國外回來的同學一起讀有80%的課是用英文上的學校連續讀十二年就好了。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;偶爾也有人知道我是雙語部的或在不同的情況下認識我，反而會覺得我的中文比他們預期的好，例如我的駕訓班教練。其實我在雙語部還是上了十二年的國文課，進度理論上跟其他學校一樣（「理論上」三個字要強調），我也跟身旁很多親戚朋友用中文溝通了更久。比奧林匹亞競賽的經驗應該也讓我認識的上普通國語教學學校的學生，比其他雙語部同學認識的多。所以這應該也不奇怪吧。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;但是。其實我對這兩個語言的精熟度其實還是差很多。日常對話沒問題，不過我對英文細枝末節的部分瞭解的比中文多太多太多了。家裡有不止一本「常見英語錯誤」類的書，我小時候會當小說讀－－我是一個很奇怪的人。在學校課程中，我編輯自己或他人的英文文章是一天到晚的事情，什麼奇怪的句子跟構造都碰過、想過、修理過。還有些時候，我會很自然的寫出一個英文單字，然後發現我不知道為什麼自己會知道這個單字的意思，但就是有一種感覺告訴我，對，subsist的意思就是「存活於只有最基本的需求被滿足的情況」。跟中文比較：有時候，直覺也會告訴我有某一個成語是可以用的，但我只能清楚想到這個成語的兩、三個字。聽起來很「對」，不過我就是想不到第四個字是什麼，或是怕前三個字換成錯別字，再加上懷疑整個成語意思根本不是我模糊腦袋裡現在浮現的，因為我認得這些字字面上的意思，但無法說服自己為什麼它們合在一起可以解釋成這種意思，最後只好放棄，用國小白話文的措詞就好了。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
「總覺得，我在用任何偏離國小程度的白話文的詞彙的時候都是假裝的。」
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我在舊一點的草稿寫出了這個句子，不過那一串「的」字讓我覺得怪怪的，現在想想，沒有人跟我討論過寫出這種或其他奇怪的句子時應該怎麼辦。哪一些「的」可以省略？有辦法把句子重寫（recast）避開嗎？還是不管它，我覺得它聽起來很奇怪純粹是錯覺，多讀一點中文就會發現根本沒什麼大不了的？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;使用兩種語言的方法也差很多。看看這個部落格就知道了。我相信我在學校雙語部外的大部分台灣朋友不會試著去理解我關於自己長篇大論的英文作文，但長篇大論的文章還是我最認真表達自己的地方。反觀我的中文短文，都通常是那種搞笑、釣讚、裝弱的文。（不，我真的很弱。）我不時會發現自己在網上逛到一個陌生人的心情文，看得津津有味。我們之間的關係頂多是朋友的朋友的朋友，我只知道我跟他應該都喜歡數學這個共同點罷了，但因為語言，我在那些瞬間覺得自己瞭解他勝於瞭解幾乎所有在我身邊講中文的朋友。我自己怎麼看這件事都覺得不合理，有點慚愧。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我回去讀了&lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/bilingualism&#34;&gt;我第一次寫的關於雙語的文章&lt;/a&gt;，可能有一點過火：後來證實，在我的朋友中似乎真的有會純粹為了抒發感情而寫七言律詩的人。而且，我講中文的朋友圈裡，文學類佔的比例本來就應該比他們在整個社會裡佔的比例少很多。在學校跟在生活裡，吸收英文多於中文（而且數學多於英文）是我做的選擇，只是我自己不知道選擇的中介點好不好罷了。是否，我花在跟講中文的親戚朋友互動的力氣不夠？&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drop-In Filler</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/drop-in</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2015 21:50:05 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/drop-in</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/commitment&#34;&gt;streak&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll probably be making filler posts for a while until I make decent progress on linear algebra and programming work, including another presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s listen to some more music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/fgtwncI3RuM&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Fiction (Part 2)</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/more-fiction-2</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2015 23:47:49 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/more-fiction-2</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/more-fiction-1&#34;&gt;Part 1 was here&lt;/a&gt;. This is still part of the &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/commitment&#34;&gt;daily posting streak I have openly committed to&lt;/a&gt; and standard disclaimers still apply. Just as in &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/fiction&#34;&gt;my original post&lt;/a&gt;, back to the flip side — let’s see what I have to do to &lt;em&gt;write&lt;/em&gt; fiction to my own satisfaction. And this time I have a guide: the list I made in the first part of this post. Could I create fiction I would enjoy reading?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1: I enjoy calling things before they happen…&lt;/p&gt;
2: …I also enjoy the Reveal for questions when the author has done something clever I didn’t catch…
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, obviously, I can’t predict things in my own plot. But I can develop riddles in the plot, set up expectations and drop subtle clues and use Chekhov’s Tropes. Can I?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cognitive Asymptotics</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/cognitive-asymptotics</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2015 23:08:25 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/cognitive-asymptotics</guid>
      <description>Short blog content for daily posting streak. Standard disclaimers apply. Not much to see here.
At some point in the past, because I was a bored teenager, I memorized this.
  So now, in theory, I can tell you the capital of each state of the U.S. This is already a lame trick, but as I realized yesterday, it’s made even lamer by the fact that the data structure I chose only supports O(n) lookup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Fiction (Part 1)</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/more-fiction-1</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2015 13:41:12 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/more-fiction-1</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m going to do it again! I’m going to break a post into parts to milk it for the &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/commitment&#34;&gt;daily posting streak&lt;/a&gt;. Desperate times call for desperate measures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is mostly a self-analysis post though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WARNING: &lt;a href=&#34;http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/JustForFun/TVTropesWillRuinYourVocabulary&#34;&gt;This post contains many, many TVTropes links.&lt;/a&gt; If you are like me and need to be productive but are &lt;a href=&#34;http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/TVTropesWillRuinYourLife&#34;&gt;liable to being sucked into TVTropes&lt;/a&gt;, maybe you should find a way to commit to not clicking on any of these links, or just stop reading. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://xkcd.com/609/&#34;&gt;obligatory xkcd&lt;/a&gt; is kind of long and also featured on one of the TVTropes links I’ve already made, so I’m not going to embed it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/fiction&#34;&gt;blogged about this before in 2013&lt;/a&gt; — how I felt that the analysis trained into me by English class was dulling my ability to appreciate and write the types of fiction I really enjoyed. After thinking about it I realized the mismatch goes deeper than that. Because the things I seek the most in fiction are escapism and entertainment. I like simple fiction with obvious (though maybe not &lt;a href=&#34;http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/Anvilicious&#34;&gt;that obvious&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;a href=&#34;http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/AnAesop&#34;&gt;Aesops&lt;/a&gt; and extreme economy of characters via making all the reveals being of the form “X and Y are the same person” (which does not quite seem to be a trope but may be an occurrence of &lt;a href=&#34;http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/ConnectedAllAlong&#34;&gt;Connected All Along&lt;/a&gt;, with the most famous subtrope being &lt;a href=&#34;http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/LukeIAmYourFather&#34;&gt;Luke, I Am Your Father&lt;/a&gt; (which is &lt;a href=&#34;http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/BeamMeUpScotty&#34;&gt;a misquote&lt;/a&gt;!), and is also one common &lt;a href=&#34;http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/StockEpilepticTrees&#34;&gt;Stock Epileptic Tree&lt;/a&gt;, so maybe this isn’t the best example), because not only are such reveals fun, they make the plot simpler. What can I say, it works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The qualities of being thought-provoking or heartwarming are only bonuses for me; needless &lt;a href=&#34;http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/JigsawPuzzlePlot&#34;&gt;complexity in the number of characters or plots&lt;/a&gt; is a strict negative. Sorry, I don’t want to spend effort trying to remember which person is which and how a hundred different storylines relate to each other if they don’t build to a convincing, cohesive, and &lt;em&gt;awesome&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/TheReveal&#34;&gt;Reveal&lt;/a&gt;, and often not even then. And I like closure, so I feel pretty miserable when writers &lt;a href=&#34;http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/KudzuPlot&#34;&gt;resolve a long-awaited plot point just to add a bunch more&lt;/a&gt;. Because of this I am ambivalent about long book series; most of my favorite works of fiction have come in long series but starting a new one always gives me &lt;a href=&#34;http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/CommitmentAnxiety&#34;&gt;Commitment Anxiety&lt;/a&gt;. Even when there’s closure, when I finish an immersive movie or book I’m always left kind of disoriented, like I’ve just been lifted out of a deep pool and have to readjust to breathing and seeing the world from the perspective of a normal person on land. I like when I’m reading good fiction, but I don’t like going through withdrawal symptoms. If I want to read complicated open-ended events, I’ll go read a history textbook, because at least the trivia might come up useful some day; if I want tough problems I’ll just look at real life and think about the possibility of college debt and having to find a job and everything. (If it wasn’t obvious yet, this is why I hyperbolically hate on &lt;cite&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;/cite&gt; often.) Even worse than all of this is multiple paragraphs full of scenery and nothing else, unless of course parts or maybe all of the scenery are &lt;a href=&#34;http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/ChekhovsGun&#34;&gt;Chekhov’s Guns&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some part of me is embarrassed to admit this because I’ve been educated for so long about deep literature that makes social commentary or reveals an inner evil of humanity or whatever. But then again, I don’t really need an education to appreciate the simple, fun fiction I apparently do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So: there are a lot of famous classics or mainstream works I can’t really enjoy too much, or in some cases, at all. And yet, sometimes a random story or webcomic will appear and I just won’t be able to stop reading. Why? I decided to try making a list of things I like in fiction:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quixotic Reimagining of Standardized Tests (Part 2)</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/quixotic-2</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 23:59:53 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/quixotic-2</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you remember, &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/quixotic-1&#34;&gt;Part 1 was here&lt;/a&gt; and my goal is to construct a theoretical system of standardized tests that I would be satisfied by. Here’s what I’ve got. As usual, because of the &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/commitment&#34;&gt;daily posting streak I have openly committed to&lt;/a&gt;, standard disclaimers apply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’d have a first-tier test like the SAT, except this will be &lt;em&gt;explicitly designed&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; to distinguish among the high performers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of the test is to assess &lt;em&gt;basic&lt;/em&gt; proficiency in reading, writing, and mathematics. Nothing else. Most good students, those who have a shot at “good colleges” and know it, will be able to ace this test with minimal effort and can spend their time studying for other things or engaging in other pursuits. Students who don’t will still have to study and it will probably be boring, but the hope is that, especially if you’re motivated to get into a good college, there won’t be much of that studying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For colleges, the intention of this test is to allow them to require this test score from everybody without having to &lt;a href=&#34;http://mitadmissions.org/blogs/entry/the-difficulty-with-data&#34;&gt;put up disclaimers&lt;/a&gt; that go like,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;there is really not a difference in our process between someone who scores, say, a 740 on the SAT math, and someone who scores an 800 on the SAT math. So why, as the commentor asks, is there such a difference in the admit rate? &lt;em&gt;Aha! Clearly we DO prefer higher SAT scores!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Well no, we don’t. What we prefer are things which &lt;em&gt;may coincide&lt;/em&gt; with higher SAT scores…
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quixotic Reimagining of Standardized Tests (Part 1)</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/quixotic-1</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2015 23:19:42 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/quixotic-1</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Life update: I got my driver’s license from the place where I learned to drive. Then I drove home from there with my mom, and it was zarking &lt;em&gt;terrifying&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, WordPress says it has protected my blog from 3&lt;sup&gt;8&lt;/sup&gt; spam comments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Early in the morning tomorrow, I have a small surgical operation, so I can’t sleep too late. (Well, it ended up being pretty late anyway. Darn.) Therefore I think I’m going to do something unprecedented on this blog for the &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/commitment&#34;&gt;daily posting streak&lt;/a&gt;: I’m going to post an incomplete non-expository post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, the only purpose of the title is to get initials that are four consecutive letters of the alphabet..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the more argumentative post sequences on my blog involved ranting against standardized tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My very first stab was probably the &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/test&#34;&gt;silly satire&lt;/a&gt; directed at the test everybody has to take that takes up two hours per day of an entire week. Once college became a thing in my life, I wrote a &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/2400&#34;&gt;humblebrag rant&lt;/a&gt; after I took the SAT and then a &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/sat&#34;&gt;summary post&lt;/a&gt; after I snagged this subject for an English class research paper and finished said paper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should be plenty clear that I am not ranting against this part of the system because it’s disadvantageous to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it should also be said that I’ve read some convincing arguments for using standardized tests &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; in college admissions (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newrepublic.com/article/119321/harvard-ivy-league-should-judge-students-standardized-tests&#34;&gt;Pinker&lt;/a&gt;, then &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.scottaaronson.com/blog/?p=2003&#34;&gt;Aaronson&lt;/a&gt;). Despite the imperfections of tests, they argue, the alternatives are likely to be less fair and more easily gamed. The fear that selecting only high test-scorers will yield a class of one-dimensional boring thinkers is unfounded. And the idea that standardized tests “reduce a human being to a number” may be uncomfortable for some, but it makes no sense to prioritize avoiding a vague feeling of discomfort over trusting reliable social science studies. Neither article, you will note, advocates selecting &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; of one’s college admits based on highest score. Just a certain unspecified proportion, one that’s probably a lot larger than it is today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And although I wish the first article linked its studies, I mostly agree with their arguments. So this puts me in a tricky position. These positions I’ve expressed seem hard to reconcile! So, after arguing about all this with a friend who told me things like&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
I think you fail to understand how anti-intellectual american society is
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(comments on this statement are also welcome) I think some clarifications and updates on how I feel are in order.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Points on Photography</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/photography</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2015 23:55:52 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/photography</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Uncohesive blog content, posted as part of a &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/commitment&#34;&gt;daily posting streak I have openly committed to&lt;/a&gt;; standard disclaimers apply. Whew, made it by a few minutes…)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This essay was partly inspired by but mostly orthogonal in purpose to dzaefn’s essay on a similar subject, &lt;a href=&#34;https://zyxyvy.wordpress.com/2012/04/09/humans-photographs-and-names/&#34;&gt;Humans, Photographs, and Names&lt;/a&gt;. I agree with many of its points, although I deviate in that I think it’s more important for my Facebook picture to identify me than to inform about me (there’s the rest of Facebook, plus my maybe half a dozen other sites, for doing so). Part of the problem for me there, and part of the reason I hang on to my nine-letter random handle from fourth grade, is that my names, first and last, are so commonplace. Among the people who share them (according to DuckDuckGo) are a New York Times tech writer, more than one computer science professor, a photographer, a couple doctors, and some guy who did some sort of graphics work for a short clip and two movies. This means that, to somebody not already in my social circles trying to match me to my account, my Facebook photo is my primary tool for disambiguating myself from all these other people, and I don’t think there is anything that could do that job quite as precisely as a picture of my actual face and body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, I agree enough to be bothered by having a profile picture suffering from “the whole extent of photographic informational void”. I always planned to add some GIMP layers to the photo to indicate context and content more precisely. Except I procrastinated and it got more and more awkward to do this as time went by, since as far as I know, normal people update their profile pictures only to reflect more recent events, especially when they’re important. Like, you know, &lt;em&gt;graduating from high school&lt;/em&gt;? So yes, I’ve been waiting to do this for an entire year now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eh, to hell with awkwardness. That’s the spirit of this daily-posting exercise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Fun fact: The code in what I’m about to set as my profile picture, if I don’t procrastinate even more, is real IOI 2014 code I submitted successfully (for &lt;a href=&#34;https://betaveros.wordpress.com/2014/07/26/one-line/&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;rail&lt;/code&gt;, as previously featured&lt;/a&gt;; the visually selected fragment was the key fix for the final bug I fixed). Except I actually had to manually retype my code printout to get the picture because I lacked the foresight (sound familiar?) to save an electronic copy of my IOI submissions.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, I’m glad this isn’t a smiling photo because I feel like it’s easier to appreciate happy posts from a person whom one associates with a serious face, than serious posts from a person whom one associates with a happy face, and I want both types of posts to impact people when I post them. I could be overgeneralizing from my own feelings though. If you are reading this and want to chat me feedback (as way more than one of you has been doing), I’d welcome more data points on this issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s not what I &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; wanted to rant about in this post, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do people take photographs?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spontaneous Thoughts on Teaching</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/thoughts-teaching</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 23:04:09 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/thoughts-teaching</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Disorganized and probably incomplete blog content, posted as part of a &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/commitment&#34;&gt;daily posting streak I have openly committed to&lt;/a&gt;; standard disclaimers apply)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, I’m actually going to try starting this blog post and posting it in the same day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Story: As a sort of extracurricular activity slash side job, I taught a math class after school once a week to six fifth-graders. It was nominally geared towards some Australian Math Competitions, which my math teacher administers in Taiwan, although in the end I don’t think I achieved this end very well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After writing this brain dump I realized this was a pretty terrible hackjob; I had absolutely no idea how to teach fifth-graders or how to organize an after-school class, and I still mostly don’t. Parents did most of the organizing, really. And provided refreshments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I get paid for this????&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bulleted list of other thoughts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wow, I didn’t realize / remember how serious the gender gap between elementary-school students is. I don’t mean the difference between their performance (that might have been the case, but I don’t think I felt a significant enough difference to conclude anything); I mean how fifth-grade boys and fifth-grade girls don’t like to mingle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When given the opportunity, they would pick team names like, “[members of my gender] Rule, [members of other gender] Drool!” They wouldn’t discuss with each other either. If prompted, they would sometimes point out mistakes in each others’ work, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think this is a phase that people grow out of, and I probably did it myself when I was young. I don’t remember when it ends, but in any case, ugh, it’s so unproductive that boys and girls separate themselves for any length of time at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sigh.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rekt</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/rekt</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 00:36:06 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/rekt</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Darn, I only lasted four days. That’s pretty bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I broke like 90% of my HabitRPG streaks too. I was busy running Monte-Carlo calculations to estimate the number of domino logic puzzles, and forgot about midnight. Okay, before that I spent twice as much time on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www1.flightrising.com/&#34;&gt;Flight Rising&lt;/a&gt; for whatever reason. Bad life decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess that means today I have to post one now, before going to sleep, and one later. Eh, time to harvest really weird mini-posts from nowhere.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mortality</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/mortality</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 21:00:51 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/mortality</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Faux-philosophical blog content, posted as part of a &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/commitment&#34;&gt;daily posting streak I have openly committed to&lt;/a&gt;; standard disclaimers apply)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a hard essay to write because (1) it’s very irrational and I should (and I do) know better — death by car accident is much more likely than death by an airplane crash, but the latter is scarier because it’s more vivid and we have less control over it, and (2) people don’t like talking about it. When I tried writing it, though, I realized I already burned through most of the down-to-earth worries in the posts I made between April and August of 2010. They still coherently and accurately sum up my current thoughts surprisingly well. And most of the irrational, overly philosophical fears appeared in &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/midnight&#34;&gt;Thoughts at Midnight&lt;/a&gt;. So there used to be a lot of fluff here like this, which was inducing procrastination because I don’t know what to include and what to cut, but now that I have a daily deadline, I cut most of it. Here’s what’s left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One, xkcd:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/leaving.png&#34; alt=&#34;xkcd&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two, bonus quote: As really-long-term readers know, I have had a reason to think that I might actually die in the past few years, a real reason that has stayed with me and gotten me thinking now and then about what &lt;em&gt;my&lt;/em&gt; meaning of life is, instead of a short-lived fuzzy philosophical feeling obtained from reading &lt;cite&gt;Tuesdays with Morrie&lt;/cite&gt; (which is not to say that &lt;cite&gt;Tuesdays with Morrie&lt;/cite&gt; isn’t a good book; I just suspect no book can convey everything a personal experience can.) Anyway, it’s over in all likelihood, but the point is that in the middle, I wrote an essay for class in ninth grade, which I find equally coherent and equally representative of my views. The conclusion runs thus:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts at Midnight</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/midnight</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2015 00:49:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/midnight</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;These are the thoughts that sometimes keep me awake at night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are things I don’t want to think about. These are things I’ve spent hours thinking about, never productively. They are worrying, but unlike typical worries in my life, it is fundamentally impractical to take steps to resolve or mitigate them, after which I may rest assured that I’ve done my best. The reason is that they also happen to be either untestable/unfalsifiable or only testable if one incurs absurd and irreversible costs, mainly dying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I explain them away to myself successfully and move on. Sometimes I read what I’ve written and think about these thoughts and do the cognitive equivalent of looking at them funny, as I’m expecting most readers to feel if they get that far — why would anybody be bothered, or afraid, or soul-crushingly panicked about these things? Life is so busy, there are literally more than sixty-four items on my HabitRPG to-do list, and besides, there are so many serious global issues humanity is actually facing right now, and people who are actually deprived of basic rights and resources and have to struggle to stay alive. How can I possibly be bothered by these absurd remote thoughts?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I know that other times I do feel those emotions exactly. And if I stare &lt;em&gt;just right&lt;/em&gt;, I can feel those emotions bubbling beneath the surface in me. Sometimes I can’t explain the issues away to myself, and a deep soul-sucking pang grows in my stomach. I’m irrational — I’m afraid of some of these thoughts — and I have submitted to the fact that there are some edges of my irrationality that would not be worth the effort to fix if just not thinking about them is better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes these thoughts make me wish I were not so rational. Sometimes they even make me wish I were religious; it would be easier if (I believed) consciousness were, somehow, special. I suspect if I tried really hard, I could make myself believe something like that sincerely. But I think that’s a betrayal of myself I’m not willing to take. I think there are better ways to remain happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to maximize happiness. Thinking about more general moral principles will help with that, but the remoteness of these particular thoughts is such that I doubt I’ll ever have to make a choice that would benefit from me having thought about them. At least, I think the chance is small enough to not be worth the negative utility spent thinking about them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So: “There is nothing to fear but fear itself.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I feel frustrated: not thinking about something just doesn’t seem like a solution. I don’t know how to come to terms with just how irrational happiness fundamentally is. And I still can’t resist thinking about them sometimes…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Re-Re-Revisiting the SAT</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/sat</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2014 00:54:03 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/sat</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First, I got worked up about the test. Then I got a score and ranted about it on this blog. (I’m still uncertainly hoping that didn’t come off as arrogant. Let me add, I did not get a perfect PSAT.) Then a friend pitched to me the idea that I write an article about it for my school newspaper, which I did. It was far too long. As if that weren’t enough, I then decided to examine whether the SAT was an accurate prediction of “academic ability and success” for my English research paper. Now I’ve come full circle to this blog, where I’m going to try to synthesize and conclude everything, free of the shackles of the research paper format, to allow me to move on with my life. This post contains bits lifted from all three essays and lots of new stuff; I’ve been editing it for so long that I feel like I have it memorized. Its word count is around that of the newspaper article &lt;em&gt;plus&lt;/em&gt; the research paper, i.e. far far far too long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But whatever, nobody reads this blog anyway and I have to get this out of my system. When I said I wanted to “move on with my life”, I really meant my winter homework. Oops!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer:&lt;/strong&gt; I am not an admissions officer. I have not yet even been accepted to a prestigious university (despite rumors to the contrary…), for whatever definition of “prestigious”, unlike some of the bloggers I’m referencing. So some of this is pure speculation. On the other hand, some of it is researched and referenced, and I think the pure speculation still makes sense. That’s why I’m posting it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, here we go…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with the question of accurate prediction. The SAT is a useful predictor, but not as useful as one might assume. Intuitively, it ought to be more accurate than other metrics because it’s a &lt;em&gt;standardized&lt;/em&gt; test, whereas GPAs other awards vary by habits of teacher and region and are hard to compare objectively. But as a &lt;a href=&#34;http://research.collegeboard.org/sites/default/files/publications/2012/7/researchreport-2008-5-validity-sat-predicting-first-year-college-grade-point-average.pdf&#34;&gt;study from the College Board &lt;em&gt;itself&lt;/em&gt; (PDF)&lt;/a&gt; found:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
the correlation of HSGPA [high-school GPA] and FYGPA [first-year GPA in college] is 0.36 (Adj. r = 0.54), which is slightly higher than the multiple correlation of the SAT (critical reading, math, and writing combined) with FYGPA (r = 0.35, Adj. r = 0.53).
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, that doesn’t mean the SAT is worthless, because combining the SAT score and high school GPA results in a more accurate metric than either one alone. But by “more accurate” I refer to a marginal improvement of 0.08 correlation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Okay, I got a 2400. Happy now?</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/2400</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 22:59:07 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/2400</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;warning&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt; from the future, 2017-11-25: I am fairly unhappy with this rant as it stands — it makes many points I still agree with, but it just sounds sooo pretentious — but it is one of very few posts to actually receive a link from an external post I’m aware of, so I am letting it stand for historical interest. I wrote this years ago; please don’t take it out of context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have to admit, I got unhealthily worked up about getting this score.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the purposes of college, I only ever wanted a score that wouldn’t be a deal-breaker — anything above 2300 would be enough. Any other time I had left would be better spent in other endeavors. Such endeavors might help on the college app, but more importantly, I’d also get to enjoy them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why am I here? Partly it’s because my classmates got worked up about it. Somebody specifically requested me to post my score somewhere. And partly it’s because there couldn’t be a better way at the moment to establish my authority to (yet again) rant against standardized tests here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pronunciation Stereotypes and the Uncrackable IPA Code</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/pronunciation</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2013 18:37:12 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/pronunciation</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;warning&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: I wrote this in 2013. It seems too irreverent in places when I look back, and not quite in the way that I’d like, but maybe it’s kind of amusing anyway?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer:&lt;/strong&gt; just because a significant number of people in group A (esp. of a certain race/ethnicity) also have quality B does not mean that (i) all or most people of group A have quality B or (ii) people of group A who do not have quality B are in any way strange or inferior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, stereotypes are stupid; don’t apply them to real people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The stereotypical “Asian” (a person from “Asia”, a mythical faraway continent consisting of two countries, China and Japan) is too hard-working, gets disowned for any grade below an A, has infinitesimally thin eyeslits, and pronounces L’s and R’s identically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/BtNBg.gif&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/BtNBg.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Animation: A door labeled Supplies opens to reveal four Asians in martial arts robes with stereotypical insignias mouthing the words &#39;Surprise!&#34; title=&#34;Supplies!&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;em&gt;jumps at opportunity to find and use .gif seen on Reddit without understanding any context&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The internet says the L/R thing is mostly due to Japanese having only a single sound somewhere in between those two. Wikipedia has a page on Japanese phonology which seems to support this. Still, Wikipedia articles on phonology all consist of giving every sound a long incomprehensible name, such as the “apical postalveolar flap undefined for laterality” for the Japanese sound discussed above, and I’m not Japanese, so don’t take my word for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mandarin Chinese (blatantly ignoring the myriad dialect variations) has a perfect L sound (ㄌ) and an R sound (ㄖ) that is only a little different. Of course, there are people who still pronounce them identically, but it’s not common — generally, the language teaches L’s and R’s well. Right?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Similarity</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/similarity</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2013 22:57:48 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/similarity</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, a sentiment randomly appears in my brain. I wonder about it. There’s a draft I’ve worked on because I’m trying to get something out of my bubble. My emotions are confusing and they need to be released.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And after a few sentences, they’ve been released, but the post’s not out there because I want to polish it. First it’s just a look-over for typoes or grammar, then maybe I want to get the flow of the sentences right or cut down the embarrassing bits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, on the third read-over, I don’t know why I’m writing it anymore.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unread Count</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/unread-count</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2012 11:32:50 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/unread-count</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;warning&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt; from 2019: My 2012 self wrote this. I don’t remember writing it. This is the first time I have felt personally attacked by a post I wrote seven years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do so many people have these three- or four- or even five-digit inbox unread counts? I become uncomfortable when I have more than about five unread emails, or if there are twenty emails of whatever status in my inbox — the rest get archived, of course. Out of sight, out of mind. Whew. It’s hard for me to fathom how anybody can sleep knowing they have such a scary number of unread emails waiting for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why does the status of being unread matter, one might ask? There are already so many ways to classify things in the typical inbox: stars or labels or folders or flags or whatever your mail service may call them. Well, the thing that makes the unread qualifier stand out is that it already has meaning; you don’t need to assign it any. It means you haven’t read it! Thank you, Captain Obvious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you know how to use email, there are no good reasons to ignore the status. Is the email actually not important to the point where you won’t even bother to read it? In that case, why is it even in your inbox? If it’s spam, mark it as such; spam filters are pretty effective nowadays, but only if you train them, and even if not it only takes one click to get rid of it. If it’s some notification you don’t care about, unsuscribe or fine-tune your subscription. As invasive as web services are getting nowadays, I haven’t yet seen a legitimate one that doesn’t provide a link to let you do one of these things, even if it’s concealed in small gray text at the bottom of the email. Should you encounter a notification that doesn’t have these links or doesn’t stop spawning evil clones after you tell it to, don’t think twice; it is spam and should be mercilessly filtered as such. And if you still have two hundred emails left after all that, you should either rethink your values or start reading them now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>English Names</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/english-names</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2012 23:08:46 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/english-names</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;warning&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: I wrote this in 2012. Maybe it’s kind of amusing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some reason, everybody around here seems to think that adding English characters, no matter how broken or meaningless, confers an added sense of quality or superiority. I don’t really understand the mindset here but it’s the only explanation I can come up with. It’s certainly not to make the lives of our English-speaking population any easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were sharing songs in Chinese class with literary techniques, and there were a bunch of songs, including mine, by this pretty famous singer with the stage name &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fish_Leong&#34;&gt;Fish Leong&lt;/a&gt;. Okay, it’s kind of cute and it’s a translated homophonic Cantonese pun, so it makes some sense, although I wonder what people would think the name meant if mentioned without any context. There was this more obscure guy a couple seasons back in the reality TV singing competition (see, no original shows around here) whose name was Quack. &lt;em&gt;smacks head&lt;/em&gt; It’s also kind of cute if you only know that the word is the sound a duck makes, which probably holds for most of the audience. But still, it takes just five seconds to &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quack&#34;&gt;put it into Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;. Oops?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nerdy Writing</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/nerdy-writing</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2011 21:18:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/nerdy-writing</guid>
      <description>Note: My 2011 self wrote this. It is selectively preserved for historical interest and amusement. It’s just meta enough to be funny, I think.
 I can look at the posts I made in fourth grade, and understand how I might get exaggeratedly happy about these tiny things, and write this ramble that goes up and down and all over the place.
Anyway apparently I wrote “to indulge in a colloquialism” less than a year ago in a school essay and now it sounds plain freaky to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Random Blathering</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/more-random-blathering</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2009 21:47:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/more-random-blathering</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;warning&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: My 2009 self wrote this. It is preserved for historical interest and amusement only, and does not reflect my current beliefs or attitudes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somehow my cousin deleted the Eragon game from his PSP. Ah well, it was fun while it lasted. Current project: get that secretary-problem paper done. It looks much nicer now, due to the references and big bold titles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lost</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/lost</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2008 20:09:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/lost</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;warning&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: My 2008 self wrote this. It is selectively preserved for historical interest and amusement from a lot of similar, chronologically nearby posts. That’s all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a life and I still don’t know what to do with it. I like making powerpoints, programming, typing tests, made-up hyperbolic IQ tests, Gmail, and odd things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All that animation has gone to my nerves. And Bookworm Adventures pining. Best word so far: VORACIOUS, which earned me a blue gem tile, which froze somebody. I want to design games for PopCap too, because then I get to play the ones they already have for free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lolcode:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A (****) of a Lot of (****)</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/a-lot-of</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2008 21:41:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/a-lot-of</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;warning&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: My 2008 self wrote this. It is preserved for historical interest and amusement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arvorie has just spammed my email account with three emails, two of them talking about palindromes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What? The fat in your head?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My latest hard cryptogram, used with a substitution cipher:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/change-2008</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2008 20:38:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/change-2008</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;warning&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: My 2008 self wrote this. It is selectively preserved for historical interest and amusement from a lot of similar, chronologically nearby posts. It is not representative of my current beliefs or attitudes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like this life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember somewhere in some book (Walk Two Moons, I think) someone said sometime something about everybody being afraid of change. Change’s only problem is that it is completely unpredictable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Return of the Omnipotent Biker</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/the-return-of-the-omnipotent-biker</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2008 20:46:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/the-return-of-the-omnipotent-biker</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;warning&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: My 2008 self wrote this. It is selectively preserved for historical interest and amusement from a lot of similar, chronologically nearby posts. That’s all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Biking is fun. Unfortunately it doesn’t require as much exertion as other workout methods do. The thing you learn most from it is how to obey traffic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;“I asked him if he knew what the word ‘obey’ meant. He replied,”Sure. It’s a place online where you can buy stuff.&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Physical</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/physical</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2008 20:44:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/physical</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;warning&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: My 2008 self wrote this. It is selectively preserved for historical interest and amusement from a lot of similar, chronologically nearby posts. It is not representative of my current beliefs or attitudes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent excercise: I’ve bicycled all over the place, almost going into Jhubei. Obviously, with parental notice. In fact they rode with me. Or, more strictly speaking I rode with them. Whatever. Also I’ve done a few pushups wrongly. And I’m typing, I guess. Ah, whatever.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtues, Complaints, and Trash</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/virtues-complaints-and-trash</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2008 18:48:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/virtues-complaints-and-trash</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;warning&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: My 2008 self wrote this. It is selectively preserved for historical interest and amusement from a lot of similar, chronologically nearby posts. It is not representative of my current beliefs or attitudes. I hope you enjoy the glimpse into a sixth grader’s psyche while he attempts to wax philosophical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been pondering an interesting problem for a long time. Which virtue is the best, the most important, the most worthy of epitomizing the word “virtue”? Due to homework constraints I have been unable to put this up for a long time, which is frustrating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My candidates: First, honesty. Then we have kindness. Then responsibility, and optimism, and courage, and intelligence. It doesn’t look like a fair match, really.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human Dependencies and More Trash</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/human-dependencies-and-more-trash</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2008 16:41:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/human-dependencies-and-more-trash</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;warning&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: My 2008 self wrote this. It is selectively preserved for historical interest and amusement from a lot of similar, chronologically nearby posts. It is not representative of my current beliefs or attitudes. I hope you enjoy the glimpse into a sixth grader’s psyche while he attempts to wax philosophical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humans depend on electricity. It’s the main problem with blackouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prehistoric people didn’t have this dependency. If our world is further electronized, blackouts will be very dangerous and will have to be made more robust.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peanut Butter Viscosity</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/peanut-butter-viscosity</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2008 08:44:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/peanut-butter-viscosity</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;warning&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: My 2008 self wrote this. It is selectively preserved for historical interest and amusement from a lot of similar, chronologically nearby posts. That’s all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note to self: PB gets stickier when toasted. Slightly strange because under heat it should flow easier, but it’s probably the same principle as the way cement works.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>