<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Puzzlehunt on Bounded-Error Log</title>
    <link>//blog.vero.site/tag/puzzlehunt</link>
    <description>Recent content in Puzzlehunt on Bounded-Error Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 19:39:22 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//blog.vero.site/tag/puzzlehunt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2018 MIT Mystery Hunt</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/2018-hunt</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 19:39:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/2018-hunt</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My third MIT Mystery Hunt with ✈✈✈ Galactic Trendsetters ✈✈✈ (also see: &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/january&#34;&gt;2017&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/whoosh&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt;, writing with Random in &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/hunt&#34;&gt;2015&lt;/a&gt;). It was a good hunt with a fun theme, solid puzzles, and extraordinary production quality, marred only by a fickle unlock structure and a handful of unnecessarily involved extractions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we had been told the hunt would be smaller than past years’ (now a controversial statement since the coin was &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; found particularly early) and we didn’t particularly want to win (yet), part of our team temporarily split off this year to hunt as Teammate. Based on our Discord channel, ✈✈✈ Galactic Trendsetters ✈✈✈ had 75 people this year, including remote solvers and people who dropped in and out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A short description of the hunt structure: This year’s hunt theme was &lt;em&gt;Inside Out&lt;/em&gt;, the Disney movie about anthropomorphized emotions. This was revealed through a kickoff that demonstrated the hunt’s extraordinary production quality, in which we watched the unveiling of the Health &amp;amp; Safety hunt, first directly, then in the Control Room with the emotions of a distraught hunter (Miss Terry Hunter) and a lot of beautiful memory orbs and scenery. After Terry’s emotions became overwhelmed in response to the theme, we had to help her emotions to allow her to complete the Health &amp;amp; Safety hunt. The intro round took place in the Control Room; we had to solve 34 regular puzzles and five metapuzzles (somewhat overlapping, with some regular puzzles belonging to more than one metapuzzle) to help each of the five emotions get back to the Control Room. The rest of the hunt consisted of recovering memory orbs from each of four Islands of Personality, each of which had its own theme and meta structure, and which we could choose the unlock order of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I guess January is puzzles month</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/january</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2017 14:27:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/january</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;And it’s not even January any more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Thing negative two: Thing zero, which is at the bottom of this post, contains two puzzles by me. Skip there if that sounds interesting and text walls don’t.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thing negative one: I abandoned this blog (again). The last month has been a mess and much of it is political stuff of the sort that I’m the worst/slowest at writing about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thing one: I was on-site for a second MIT Mystery Hunt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>whoosh</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/whoosh</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 08:19:46 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/whoosh</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I finally did it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was on-site for the 2016 MIT Mystery Hunt. I even &lt;em&gt;solved a metapuzzle&lt;/em&gt;. This year I hunted with ✈✈✈ Galactic Trendsetters ✈✈✈, the team primarily but not overwhelmingly formed from floorpi, my dorm floor. (Perhaps somewhat regrettably, I didn’t contribute to any events or runarounds or things given to HQ, unless you count attending a “recitation” for Student Simulator (round King Arthur, second from left).)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Also, I made this post. Has it been two weeks already? Okay, that’s not an unusual timeframe.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But wow, I got to touch so many puzzles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Non-spoilery comments on particularly memorable puzzles I did, which are disproportionately programming-related, if anybody wants to look at them (I am describing how to get to the puzzle from the round instead of linking because I’m lazy and links might rot but the instructions will hopefully survive archival (although turns out there’s actually a &lt;a href=&#34;http://huntception.com/toc.html&#34;&gt;table of contents&lt;/a&gt; so I don’t know what I’m doing)):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three for the Price of One (Meta)</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/three-for-one</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2015 13:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/three-for-one</guid>
      <description>And that’s another year!
As usual, you can check your answers here. Text above this horizontal rule is not part of the puzzle.
Solvers:
Yoshiap @ 11-20 13:31:56  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When Is My Birthday Again?</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/birthday-again</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 13:00:25 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/birthday-again</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As usual, &lt;a href=&#34;http://bpchen.scripts.mit.edu/2015/&#34;&gt;you can check your answers here.&lt;/a&gt; Text above this horizontal rule is not part of the puzzle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solvers (in my local UTC−5 because I’m lazy):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol type=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lewis Chen (phenomist) @ 11-19 05:03:07&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jack Lance @ 11-19 10:39:11&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yoshiap @ 11-20 03:29:54&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anticron</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/anticron</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2015 13:00:59 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/anticron</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I did not get this successfully testsolved, although, for whatever comfort it may provide, I did engage in several interactive rounds of nerfing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As usual, &lt;a href=&#34;http://bpchen.scripts.mit.edu/2015/&#34;&gt;you can check your answers here.&lt;/a&gt; Text above this horizontal rule is not part of the puzzle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solvers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Signature Puzzle</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/signature-puzzle</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2015 13:00:06 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/signature-puzzle</guid>
      <description>As usual, there had to be something here. In fact, this year, there are several somethings. Hype!
This is based on an idea by chaotic_iak. You can check your answers here. Text above this horizontal rule is not part of the puzzle.
ETA 11/17 16:15 UTC−5: Adjusted spacing between the bottom numbers after feedback. The puzzle is otherwise the same, and solving should not be significantly impacted.  Solvers (in my local UTC−5 because I’m lazy):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2015 MIT Mystery Hunt</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/hunt</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 11:45:50 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/hunt</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, it’s been over a week, which is a long time for blog posts to be delayed after the event they’re documenting in probably all of the world except my blog. So.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess this post should start with a bit of background. I’ve been puzzlehunting for… wow, three and a half years now. I was introduced to puzzlehunts from AoPS, when some fellow members got together a team for &lt;a href=&#34;http://puzzle.cisra.com.au/2011/teamstats_AoPS.html&#34;&gt;CiSRA 2011&lt;/a&gt;, and I think I’ve participated to some degree in every known internet Australian puzzlehunt since.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commemorating Obvious Milestones Involving Chronological Sustenance</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/comics</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/comics</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, there had to be something here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately I don’t have time for anything more complex, so here’s a low-effort illogical puzzle for the occasion. (It &lt;em&gt;has&lt;/em&gt; been testsolved, at least. Thanks, Yoshiap.) It also features a brand new category, so as not to distract the people on LMI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don’t already know what occasion it is, it’s easy to find out by looking through my archives or possibly anywhere else I’ve left a trail online. Or you could solve the puzzle! (Or you could &lt;ins datetime=&#34;2014-11-20T12:29:52+00:00&#34;&gt;scroll down to read the solution!&lt;/ins&gt;) If this puzzle had an answer, it would be a nine-letter word, although like most of mathematics, it’s less about the answer than about the path you take to get there…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ins datetime=&#34;2017-11-24T18:36:41-0500&#34;&gt;
2017 edit: A warning that this has somewhat linkrotted and is harder to solve, but theoretically still possible.
&lt;/ins&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 44 / ???</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-44</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 00:00:26 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-44</guid>
      <description>&lt;ins datetime=&#34;2013-11-18T23:20:18+00:00&#34;&gt;
Edit 11/19 7:23 AM UTC+8: Fixed some transcription errors on right: &lt;strong&gt;R4C17 is D instead of N, and R15C17 is G instead of E.&lt;/strong&gt; Neither change should greatly impact solvability. Thanks to ksun for pointing out an error.
&lt;/ins&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Logic puzzles are easy to construct if one doesn’t have some specific pattern or theme in mind. It’s just that, given the increasing number of constructors and puzzles with amazing themes, I don’t think it’s very meaningful for me to just construct more puzzles of the same genres by putting down clues randomly. That’s why, for my seventeenth birthday, I took the puzzlehunt route and made something without instructions that is not completely solved by logical deduction. Still, I’ve provided all the information needed to do this puzzle initially, so I hope my not getting the inductive bits test-solved can be excused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MUMS Puzzle Hunt 2013</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/mums</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2013 21:44:24 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/mums</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/informatix.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/informatix.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;Informatix [MUMS Puzzle Hunt 2013]&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I somehow managed to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ms.unimelb.edu.au/~mums/puzzlehunt/teamstats.html?team=not+AoPS&#34;&gt;get 25 points all by myself&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ms.unimelb.edu.au/~mums/puzzlehunt/&#34;&gt;MUMS Puzzle Hunt 2013&lt;/a&gt;. Well, I pestered chaotic_iak a little with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ms.unimelb.edu.au/~mums/puzzlehunt/2013/puzzles/3.3_Diagnosus_ghQ3AcbJ.html&#34;&gt;3.3 Diagnosus (.html with animated .gif)&lt;/a&gt; but we still didn’t recognize all the Pokémon until hint 3, at which point Google sufficed for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is nowhere near the top, but compared to the usual results of whatever AoPS team I form, it’s amazing. By far the best result of AoPS was on CiSRA in 2010 (46th with 58 points), before I discovered puzzle hunts in AoPS; unfortunately due to people getting older and the influx of younger and younger people to the fora, there are less possible teammates each year and they have less time, so here I am by myself. (Also I could have accepted an invitation from a guy in the some-form-of-Elephant team, but I figure if you can win two MUMS hunts in a row you don’t need any more people.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all: Yay!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hunter on Vacation</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/hunter</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 16:18:58 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/hunter</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/rainbow.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/rainbow.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;Very faint rainbow&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
Faint rainbow
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So winter vacation started and parents had planned a trip to southern Taiwan, to get closer to nature and walk around and stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, the MIT Mystery Hunt, the absolute granddaddy of all the other puzzlehunts in terms of age, structure, and size, happened this weekend. Originally, I didn’t have a team and just planned to look at the puzzles after they got archived and &lt;s&gt;try solving some puzzles&lt;/s&gt; read the solutions while constantly thinking, “How could anybody ever solve that?” Because of that, I wasn’t planning to even bring my laptop at first; then I could force myself to study some long-overdue ring theory during the nights. I was taken aback by a private message on Saturday morning from somebody with many different names inviting me to remote-solve for Random Thymes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>