<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>geometry on Bounded-Error Log</title>
    <link>//blog.vero.site/tag/geometry</link>
    <description>Recent content in geometry on Bounded-Error Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 12:04:30 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//blog.vero.site/tag/geometry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>[CIMC 2015 Part 2] Journey of the Blue-White Slippers</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/cimc-2015-part-2</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 12:04:30 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/cimc-2015-part-2</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Nontopical life update: Current 18.06 homework status: 34% (mildly screwed, probably won’t finish before I leave my cozy home for the U.S. and I usually struggle to get into the mood for homework while traveling, but I guess I’ll have to)) &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/18-06-1.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/18-06-1.png?w=296&#34; alt=&#34;[18.06 status panel: 34%]&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (I’ve been spending most of my uptime doing said homework and running errands, and my downtime catching up on &lt;cite&gt;Last Week Tonight with John Oliver&lt;/cite&gt; while farming the Flight Rising Coliseum. And, okay, making the above status panel. &lt;a href=&#34;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/5295912/status.html&#34;&gt;Live version here&lt;/a&gt; courtesy of Dropbox’s Public folder. No regrets.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;day-3-excursions&#34;&gt;
Day 3 (Excursions)
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morning routine snipped. We come to the middle school again to eat breakfast and gather; the contestants will be taking their tests here (accompanied by one bottle of “Buff” energy drink each) while the rest of us will be going on an excursion. Before this happens, though, two Taiwanese contestants ask me and Hsin-Po some math problems. There’s a geometry problem, which I fail to solve:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
(paraphrased) In triangle △ABC, ∠A is 40° and ∠B is 60°. The angle bisector of ∠A meets BC at D; E is on AB such that ∠ADE is 30°. Find ∠DEC.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hsin-Po figures out that, once you guess (ROT13) gur bgure boivbhf privna vf nyfb na natyr ovfrpgbe naq gurl vagrefrpg ng gur vapragre, lbh pna cebir vg ol pbafgehpgvat gur vapragre naq fubjvat sebz gur tvira natyr gung gurl vaqrrq pbvapvqr.&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Then, there’s a combinatorics problem in a book with a solution that they’re not sure about:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rise from the Ashes</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/rise</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2014 19:27:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/rise</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After the first stage of selection camp, I was very nervous because I was fifth place in a selection sequence that would finally result in a team of four.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I screwed myself over on the first mock test by committing to a bad implementation method on a problem that was hard to get points on. My method seemed simple, but the memory usage leaked out in a way that was confusing and hard to patch; unfortunately, I tried to patch it in increasingly desperate and convoluted ways rather than scrapping the method, and thus missed out on many of the points elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the second test I failed to read the last problem carefully and spent too much of my time on the second problem, once again missing out on a lot of relatively easy points. I had optimized and optimized and pushed my quadratic runtime down to linearithmic, which would allow me to get the points for the last subtask — or so I thought. But with 10 minutes left I had all but one testcase right, and after desperately rereading my code, I realized that I had a string comparison stuck in an inner loop that could make my runtime degenerate to quadratic if the input string had lots of the same digit. In order to have a solidly linearithmic algorithm, I would have to implement a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Suffix_array&#34;&gt;suffix array&lt;/a&gt;. Ten minutes? I gave up. (The problem setters told me afterwards that hashing would have worked too; I didn’t think of that at all. Oops.) I spent the 10 minutes reading the last problem and still failed to read it carefully. So that did not go very well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, as the title probably gave away, during the third and fourth mock tests everything went much better than expected. :)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
