<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>procrastination on Bounded-Error Log</title>
    <link>//blog.vero.site/tag/procrastination</link>
    <description>Recent content in procrastination on Bounded-Error Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2014 19:04:12 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//blog.vero.site/tag/procrastination/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>HabitRPG</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/habitrpg</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2014 19:04:12 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/habitrpg</guid>
      <description>HabitRPG: harnessing the addiction of web games with cheap leveling mechanisms to destroy bad habits, avoid procrastination, and improve your life.
(Ironically, I discovered it on /r/InternetIsBeautiful.)
These claims sound a bit hyperbolic, but they are actually working on me. Most notably: for the three days after I discovered it, most of which has been spent at IOI selection camp away from school and worldly concerns, I’ve only gone on reddit once — and only for about two minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>74 Days</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/74-days</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2013 18:14:21 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/74-days</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I did it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/ascension.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/ascension.png&#34; alt=&#34;ascension&#34; width=&#34;652&#34; height=&#34;479&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-2307&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/test</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2013 21:58:01 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/test</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Parts of this (a majority of questions, I hope) are intended as satire. Other parts of this are silliness created to blow off steam from being coerced into spending nine unproductive hours. Still other parts exist simply because I wanted to have equally many questions per test. Also, 256th post w00t. &lt;ins datetime=&#34;2019-08-22T22:21:48-0400&#34;&gt;(2019 edit: after the migration, this post count is wildly incorrect, but whatever.)&lt;/ins&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;
“Verbal Reasoning”
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Directions:&lt;/em&gt; The questions in this test are multiple-choice. Each question has four possible choices. Read each question and decide which answer is the best answer. Find the row in your answer sheet that matches the number of the question. In that row, fill in the oval corresponding to the answer you selected.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>