<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>procrastination on Bounded-Error Log</title>
    <link>//blog.vero.site/tag/procrastination</link>
    <description>Recent content in procrastination on Bounded-Error Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2014 19:04:12 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//blog.vero.site/tag/procrastination/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>HabitRPG</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/habitrpg</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2014 19:04:12 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/habitrpg</guid>
      <description>HabitRPG: harnessing the addiction of web games with cheap leveling mechanisms to destroy bad habits, avoid procrastination, and improve your life.
(Ironically, I discovered it on /r/InternetIsBeautiful.)
These claims sound a bit hyperbolic, but they are actually working on me. Most notably: for the three days after I discovered it, most of which has been spent at IOI selection camp away from school and worldly concerns, I’ve only gone on reddit once — and only for about two minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>74 Days</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/74-days</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2013 18:14:21 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/74-days</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I did it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/ascension.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/ascension.png&#34; alt=&#34;ascension&#34; width=&#34;652&#34; height=&#34;479&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-2307&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/test</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2013 21:58:01 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/test</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Parts of this (a majority of questions, I hope) are intended as satire. Other parts of this are silliness created to blow off steam from being coerced into spending nine unproductive hours. Still other parts exist simply because I wanted to have equally many questions per test. Also, 256th post w00t. &lt;ins datetime=&#34;2019-08-22T22:21:48-0400&#34;&gt;(2019 edit: after the migration, this post count is wildly incorrect, but whatever.)&lt;/ins&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;
“Verbal Reasoning”
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Directions:&lt;/em&gt; The questions in this test are multiple-choice. Each question has four possible choices. Read each question and decide which answer is the best answer. Find the row in your answer sheet that matches the number of the question. In that row, fill in the oval corresponding to the answer you selected.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter Bandwagon</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/twitter-bandwagon</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 11:58:32 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/twitter-bandwagon</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;warning&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: My 2012 self wrote this. It is preserved for historical interest and amusement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hahahahahahahahahahahahaha look at all the services&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;ahem&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, if you’ve been hiding under a rock for the last decade, Twitter is a platform for microblogging, i.e. blogging with very short posts, called tweets, which have to be under 140 characters after they shorten all the links for you for no reason, often after you’ve already shortened it once somehow-or-other. And yes, I hopped onto the bandwagon during procrastination. Everybody who matters on the technological edges of the internet seems to have one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not arrogant enough to imagine I could compare Twitter to anything else authoritatively… I only barely count myself as using it. But a brief set of first impressions should be okay. Twitter is very public: you can see everybody’s tweets, who everybody is following, and who everybody is being followed by; the single privacy setting is a simple binary choice to lock up your account, so that everybody who wants to see what you posted needs your explicit authorization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Facebook feed consists of entries such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;photographs of people I barely recognize, which I scroll past quickly… unless my mom comes up and says “Who is that?” and spends ten minutes looking at more such photos while asking me questions like “How do you go to the next picture?” or “Why is this photo so blurry?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;context-less fragments of some larger conversation, e.g. “LOL!” or “linglinglinggg” (copied verbatim from a status)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;alerts of J. Random Person having taken a Personality Test or scored too many lines in Tetris&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meta-Facebook infographics, like a cloud of your closest friends or number of status posts. I tend to… have an extraordinarily negative impression of the type of narcissistic achievement-reliant… &lt;em&gt;people&lt;/em&gt;… who need rewards at every step, except that they seem to be &lt;em&gt;everybody&lt;/em&gt;… *sigh&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autological Procrastination</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/autological-procrastination</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2012 17:33:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/autological-procrastination</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#ifdef BORING_SELF_DEPRECATION&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So obviously this isn’t a good parody and the song is ancient (under some “pop” definition, which is probably not a very discriminative label), at over four years. Just randomness that finds its way onto my iPod. And the words are not very creative, and there are even two lines that survive unscathed because they fit reasonably and I can’t think of anything better (and I don’t even know if this is supposed to be bad, I just want to ensure nobody expects otherwise).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#endif&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever, this has been sitting in my draft box for at least one month.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>