<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>puzzles on Bounded-Error Log</title>
    <link>//blog.vero.site/category/puzzles</link>
    <description>Recent content in puzzles on Bounded-Error Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 23:24:47 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//blog.vero.site/category/puzzles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2020 MIT Mystery Hunt</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/2020-hunt</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 23:24:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/2020-hunt</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fifth year with ✈✈✈ Galactic Trendsetters ✈✈✈ (previously: &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/2019-hunt&#34;&gt;2019&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/2018-hunt&#34;&gt;2018&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/january&#34;&gt;2017&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/whoosh&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt;; writing with Random in &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/hunt&#34;&gt;2015&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We won!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But apparently I’m still really busy, so I’ll probably just focus on a few highlights of things I personally experienced and get this post out the door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The theme in a few sentences: As suggested by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/mysteryhunt/comments/eo475t/you_are_cordially_invited/&#34;&gt;the invitation&lt;/a&gt; sent out to teams, there was a wedding. It turned out to actually be a real wedding between two prolific puzzle writers on Left Out, the organizing team. To the surprise of everybody who expected either one, three, or maybe five subversions of this announcement, the wedding actually succeeded (a COIN that would prevent all love in the universe was briefly reported missing, but then immediately found by the bride). Instead, we joined the newlyweds on a trip to an amusement park called Penny Park, which we learned was struggling and closing this weekend. It was up to help its regain its popularity and stay open by solving puzzles. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/mysteryhunt/&#34;&gt;Mystery Hunt subreddit&lt;/a&gt; has lots of other cool links and discussions, including this &lt;a href=&#34;https://public.flourish.studio/visualisation/1267425/&#34;&gt;animated bar chart&lt;/a&gt;, so I won’t spend more time here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m pretty sure the best story I personally experienced was how we solved the metameta, the biggest puzzle that stood between us and winning hunt, and the moment at which we went, holy smokes we might have won Mystery Hunt! We got all the pennies required for the final metameta at Sunday 5:48:09am, and it took us until 12:47:30pm, just under &lt;em&gt;seven hours later&lt;/em&gt;, to solve it…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Puzzlehunts</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzlehunts</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 10:34:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzlehunts</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;series&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;not part of the ongoing series, but you can almost pretend it is. This sentence and the one before it are not a puzzle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine a word search.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now imagine you aren’t told what words to look for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now imagine you aren’t told it’s a word search.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now imagine it isn’t a word search.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;footer&gt;
— &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gmpuzzles.com/blog/2013/04/ask-dr-sudoku-13-puzzle-hunting/&#34;&gt;Mike Develin, via Thomas Snyder&lt;/a&gt; (aka Dr. Sudoku)
&lt;/footer&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post aims to be a fairly comprehensive introduction to puzzlehunts and their puzzles, a single post where I can just point people. I erred towards comprehensiveness in this post because I am not aware of any similar resources, especially for puzzlers interested in trying harder puzzlehunts who might not know any more experienced puzzlers to solve with. It’s possible to start solving some puzzles after reading much shorter guides, e.g. Puzzled Pint’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.puzzledpint.com/files/3513/8254/7894/2013_10_22_Puzzling_Basics_Infographic.pdf&#34;&gt;“Puzzling Basics” (PDF)&lt;/a&gt;, so feel free to skip around, stop reading midway through, or bookmark this to read only after you’ve spent more time solving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-a-puzzlehunt&#34;&gt;What is a Puzzlehunt?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;puzzlehunt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an event where people, usually in teams, solve a series of &lt;strong&gt;puzzles&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not a very useful definition. The more interesting question is, what is the kind of “puzzle”&lt;a href=&#34;#fn2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that appears in a puzzlehunt? The concept of a puzzlehunt puzzle is fuzzy and difficult to define precisely. Just about any hard rule one might try to state will be broken by some puzzle, sometimes deliberately. Still, here are some common features of puzzlehunt puzzles:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019 MIT Mystery Hunt</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/2019-hunt</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 19:39:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/2019-hunt</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(this post is sketchily backdated from February 2020)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fourth year with ✈✈✈ Galactic Trendsetters ✈✈✈. Past: &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/2018-hunt&#34;&gt;2018&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/january&#34;&gt;2017&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/whoosh&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt;, writing with Random in &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/hunt&#34;&gt;2015&lt;/a&gt;). Evidently I was unable to find the time or motivation to blog about this, and I can’t remember any particularly good stories, so let me just slip this backdated list post in the archives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The theme in a few sentences: The hunt organizers declare a new Molasses Awareness Day, but because they didn’t follow the proper procedure, throwing the world of Holidays into chaos, where “chaos” means molasses. This resulted in lots of puzzle-to-meta matching, since puzzles were in Holiday towns but metas were at lampposts between two towns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Highlights of puzzles I solved:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Good Walk Spoiled&lt;/strong&gt; (Holi): Happens to be about a topic I know well and find interesting. Fun steps. Justified use of substitution ciphers; the pasting into quipqiup was worth it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;State Machine&lt;/strong&gt; (President’s): A one-aha! one-step puzzle. Maybe more unfortunate because apparently this was not the only puzzle to use a specific aspect of a specific source material, but I didn’t know about that other puzzle so it’s fine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clued Connections&lt;/strong&gt; (Pi): I went to sleep near the end of this puzzle, so I didn’t see it through, but Floorpi was collectively called out by it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I Can’t Deal with These Endless Numbers&lt;/strong&gt; (Patriot’s): Incredible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loaded&lt;/strong&gt; (Arbor): Simple and self-contained enough.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018 MIT Mystery Hunt</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/2018-hunt</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 19:39:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/2018-hunt</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My third MIT Mystery Hunt with ✈✈✈ Galactic Trendsetters ✈✈✈ (also see: &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/january&#34;&gt;2017&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/whoosh&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt;, writing with Random in &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/hunt&#34;&gt;2015&lt;/a&gt;). It was a good hunt with a fun theme, solid puzzles, and extraordinary production quality, marred only by a fickle unlock structure and a handful of unnecessarily involved extractions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we had been told the hunt would be smaller than past years’ (now a controversial statement since the coin was &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; found particularly early) and we didn’t particularly want to win (yet), part of our team temporarily split off this year to hunt as Teammate. Based on our Discord channel, ✈✈✈ Galactic Trendsetters ✈✈✈ had 75 people this year, including remote solvers and people who dropped in and out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A short description of the hunt structure: This year’s hunt theme was &lt;em&gt;Inside Out&lt;/em&gt;, the Disney movie about anthropomorphized emotions. This was revealed through a kickoff that demonstrated the hunt’s extraordinary production quality, in which we watched the unveiling of the Health &amp;amp; Safety hunt, first directly, then in the Control Room with the emotions of a distraught hunter (Miss Terry Hunter) and a lot of beautiful memory orbs and scenery. After Terry’s emotions became overwhelmed in response to the theme, we had to help her emotions to allow her to complete the Health &amp;amp; Safety hunt. The intro round took place in the Control Room; we had to solve 34 regular puzzles and five metapuzzles (somewhat overlapping, with some regular puzzles belonging to more than one metapuzzle) to help each of the five emotions get back to the Control Room. The rest of the hunt consisted of recovering memory orbs from each of four Islands of Personality, each of which had its own theme and meta structure, and which we could choose the unlock order of.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I guess January is puzzles month</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/january</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2017 14:27:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/january</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;And it’s not even January any more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Thing negative two: Thing zero, which is at the bottom of this post, contains two puzzles by me. Skip there if that sounds interesting and text walls don’t.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thing negative one: I abandoned this blog (again). The last month has been a mess and much of it is political stuff of the sort that I’m the worst/slowest at writing about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thing one: I was on-site for a second MIT Mystery Hunt.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>020315040524</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/bcodex</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 13:54:22 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/bcodex</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;--... ---.. ....- ..... ..--- ----- ....- ....- ...-- -.... ...-- -.... ...-- . ....- ....- ..--- ----- ....- ..... ...-- ----. ...-- -.... ....- ...-- ...-- -.... ..... -.... ....- ....- ..--- ----- ...-- ..-. ....- ----- ..--- ----- ...-- ..--- ...-- ..-. ....- ..... ...-- .- ...-- ..... ....- ----- ....- ..... ...-- -.... ..--- ----- ...-- --... ....- ----- ....- ...-- ..--- ----- ...-- ..--- ...-- ..-. ...-- ---.. ....- ....- ....- ..... ..--- ----- ...-- -.. ...-- .- ...-- -.-. ...-- -.... ..--- ----- ...-- --... ...-- .- ...-- ..-. ...-- ..... ...-- .- ...-- ..-. ...-- ---.. ..--- ----- ....- ....- ....- ----- ...-- . ...-- -.... ....- ..... ...-- ----. ...-- .- ...-- ..-. ...-- ---.. ..--- ----- ...-- ....- ....- ----- ....- ----- ...-- -.. ..--- ----- ...-- ..--- ...-- ..-. ...-- ..... ..--- ----- ...-- ..... ....- ----- ....- ---.. ...-- ..-. ..... -.-. ....- ..... ....- ----- ..... -.-. ...-- -.... ...-- ..--- ....- ...-- ....- ..... ...-- ----. ..... -... ..--- ----- ...-- ..--- ...-- ..-. ...-- ..... ..--- ----- ...-- ..... ....- ----- ...-- .- ...-- ..-. ...-- ---.. ..--- ----- ...-- .- ....- ..... ..... -..&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;..--- ..... ....- ----- ...-- ..... ...-- ..--- ....- .- ..--- ----- --... ---.. ..--- ----- ...-- ..... ...-- .- ...-- ..... ..--- ----- ...-- ..--- ..--- ----- ....- ..... ...-- ----. ...-- .- ...-- ..-. ...-- ---.. ..--- ----- --... ---.. ..--- ----- ....- ---.. ...-- ..--- ...-- ..-. ....- ..... ...-- -.... ...-- ..... ..--- ----- ....- ..... ....- ----- ..--- ----- ...-- ..... ....- ----- ..--- ----- ...-- --... ....- ----- ....- ...-- ..--- ----- ...-- ..--- ..--- ----- ...-- -.. ....- ----- ...-- ..-. ...-- ---.. ..--- ----- ....- ..... ...-- .- ...-- . ...-- -.... -.... ----. ..--- ----- --... ---.. ..--- ----- ...-- ....- ....- ----- ...-- . ....- .---- ...-- .- ...-- -.. ...-- -.... ...-- ..... ..--- -----&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/betaveros/bcodex&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;...-- ...-- ...-- ....- ....- ----- ...-- ..... ...-- -.... ....- ----.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;..--- ----- ...-- --... ....- ...-- ....- ----- ...-- . ..--- ----- --... --... ...-- ..--- ....- ....- ...-- -.-. ...-- -.... ...-- -.. ...-- -.. ..--- ----- ....- ..... ....- ----- ..--- ----- --... ----. ...-- ..--- ....- --... ...-- ..--- ..--- ....- ...-- ....- ....- ...-- ...-- .- ....- .---- ....- ..... ..--- ----- ....- ....- ....- ----- ..--- ----- ...-- .- ....- ..... ..--- ----- ...-- ....- ....- ----- ....- -.... ...-- -.. ...-- ..... ..--- ----- ....- ...-- ....- -.... ...-- ..-. ..--- ----- ...-- .- ...-- ..-. ..--- ----- ...-- ..--- ...-- ..-. ....- .- ..--- ----- ...-- . ....- ----- ...-- ..... ...-- -.... ....- ...-- ...-- ..-. ..--- ----- ...-- ...-- ....- ...-- ....- ----- ....- ---.. ....- ....- ...-- -.... ....- ...-- ..... -.. ..--- -----&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://betaveros.github.io/bcodex/&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;..--- .- ....- ----- ....- -.... ..--- ----- ...-- ....- ...-- ..--- ...-- ..-. ..--- ----- ....- ..... ....- ...-- ....- .- ..--- ----- ...-- .- ....- ..... ..--- ----- ...-- ----. ...-- -.... ....- ...-- ...-- -.... ..... -----&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>whoosh</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/whoosh</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 08:19:46 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/whoosh</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I finally did it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was on-site for the 2016 MIT Mystery Hunt. I even &lt;em&gt;solved a metapuzzle&lt;/em&gt;. This year I hunted with ✈✈✈ Galactic Trendsetters ✈✈✈, the team primarily but not overwhelmingly formed from floorpi, my dorm floor. (Perhaps somewhat regrettably, I didn’t contribute to any events or runarounds or things given to HQ, unless you count attending a “recitation” for Student Simulator (round King Arthur, second from left).)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Also, I made this post. Has it been two weeks already? Okay, that’s not an unusual timeframe.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But wow, I got to touch so many puzzles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Non-spoilery comments on particularly memorable puzzles I did, which are disproportionately programming-related, if anybody wants to look at them (I am describing how to get to the puzzle from the round instead of linking because I’m lazy and links might rot but the instructions will hopefully survive archival (although turns out there’s actually a &lt;a href=&#34;http://huntception.com/toc.html&#34;&gt;table of contents&lt;/a&gt; so I don’t know what I’m doing)):&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 49 / Triple Back</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-49</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2015 00:25:46 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-49</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m not really satisfied with the execution, but eh, what the hell. My brain can only function at so much of its full capacity when it’s a few kilometers up in the sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://mellowmelon.wordpress.com/2009/12/20/puzzle-135/&#34;&gt;Triple Back&lt;/a&gt;, variant on &lt;a href=&#34;https://mellowmelon.wordpress.com/double-back/&#34;&gt;MellowMelon’s Double Back&lt;/a&gt;. Briefly, draw a closed loop through all square centers visiting each bold-outlined area exactly three (= ⌊π⌋) times. Shaded cells do not influence solving, only aesthetics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>November 2015 Puzzles Hints</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/november-2015-hints</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2015 13:16:59 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/november-2015-hints</guid>
      <description>A Signature Puzzle: Trying to solve the puzzle with Extreme Speed can’t hurt.   Anticron: This puzzle runs on two distinct 24-hour clocks, which is why you can be zoned out for half the time and still solve it.   When Is My Birthday Again?: Apparently, if you don’t want to tell your friends your birthday, you can tell one of them the month and the other the day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three for the Price of One (Meta)</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/three-for-one</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2015 13:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/three-for-one</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;And that’s another year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As usual, &lt;a href=&#34;http://bpchen.scripts.mit.edu/2015/&#34;&gt;you can check your answers here.&lt;/a&gt; Text above this horizontal rule is not part of the puzzle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solvers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol type=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yoshiap @ 11-20 13:31:56&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When Is My Birthday Again?</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/birthday-again</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 13:00:25 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/birthday-again</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As usual, &lt;a href=&#34;http://bpchen.scripts.mit.edu/2015/&#34;&gt;you can check your answers here.&lt;/a&gt; Text above this horizontal rule is not part of the puzzle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solvers (in my local UTC−5 because I’m lazy):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol type=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lewis Chen (phenomist) @ 11-19 05:03:07&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jack Lance @ 11-19 10:39:11&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yoshiap @ 11-20 03:29:54&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anticron</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/anticron</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2015 13:00:59 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/anticron</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I did not get this successfully testsolved, although, for whatever comfort it may provide, I did engage in several interactive rounds of nerfing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As usual, &lt;a href=&#34;http://bpchen.scripts.mit.edu/2015/&#34;&gt;you can check your answers here.&lt;/a&gt; Text above this horizontal rule is not part of the puzzle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solvers:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Signature Puzzle</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/signature-puzzle</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2015 13:00:06 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/signature-puzzle</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As usual, there had to be something here. In fact, this year, there are several somethings. Hype!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is based on an idea by chaotic_iak. &lt;a href=&#34;http://bpchen.scripts.mit.edu/2015/&#34;&gt;You can check your answers here.&lt;/a&gt; Text above this horizontal rule is not part of the puzzle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ins datetime=&#34;2015-11-17T21:15:09+00:00&#34;&gt;
ETA 11/17 16:15 UTC−5: Adjusted spacing between the bottom numbers after feedback. The puzzle is otherwise the same, and solving should not be significantly impacted.
&lt;/ins&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solvers (in my local UTC−5 because I’m lazy):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol type=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yoshiap @ 11-17 18:28:34&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 48 / Double Back</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-48</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2015 23:15:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-48</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At least one person wants me to post. I’m not even going to try do a life summary. It’s too hard. Let’s just say:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
right now, my blog drafts contain a backlog of ~7500 words and counting;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
I was not accepted as an MIT Admissions blogger, which is bad because my blogging will continue to not reach a large audience, but good because my blogging will continue to not reach a large audience. Maybe it had something to do with the fact that, because the application form wouldn’t let me submit without any media, I panickedly cranked out the following puzzle in an hour or so to attach.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Throwback Thursday Puzzles!</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/tbt-puzzles</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 23:39:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/tbt-puzzles</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wow, there are so many cool things in my old folder. I could probably create and schedule enough filler posts to make my &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/commitment&#34;&gt;streak&lt;/a&gt; last through my week-long trip and back. I guess I won’t, though, because I don’t want to dilute my textwall-draft brand more than necessary and there are a few text posts that I fully intend to post before leaving. Or at least one. Although on second thought, it’s possible they might actually not be as interesting as posts like this one about the adorable me from the past. As Pablo Picasso once said, “Youth has no age.” (Yes, I totally just went on BrainyQuote and searched for “youth”. Forgive me, please.) Oh well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today’s throwback theme is old puzzles! Particularly picture ones! In reverse chronological order by last modified time, because I said so! All the image puzzles are puzzlehunty in the sense that you’re supposed to end up with a single word or short phrase as your final answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;p06pre2&#34;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;art/hidd3n/p06pre2.png&lt;/code&gt; (2010/10/31)
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/p06pre2.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/p06pre2.png&#34; alt=&#34;p06pre2&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3210&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; A straightforward one to start. I have no idea what’s with the filename, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;purity2logic&#34;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;haxxor/purity2/logic.html&lt;/code&gt; (2010/10/10?)
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My file hierarchy is really weird. I don’t think this time stamp is when I wrote the puzzle because it was part of a silly static site setup I created (but never actually put anywhere), and I probably edited and regenerated stuff like the breadcrumbs many times, but it’ll have to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is also funny because the title of the HTML file is “Logic Puzzles” and the description starts, “These puzzles were made when I was really bored…”, but there’s only one puzzle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, it’s better than an under construction page, I guess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll quote the entirety of the old instructions as I wrote them, even though they’re really verbose, since it’s easy to scroll past them:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 47 / Fillomino [LITS &#43; Walls]</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-47</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2015 20:01:26 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-47</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CLICKBAIT PERSONALITY TEST THAT YOU CAN DO WITHOUT SOLVING THE PUZZLE: What do you see in the puzzle image below? I have my own thoughts but I won’t bias you by posting them yet. Sound out your thoughts in the comments below! (I don’t expect this to work but I’d love to be proven wrong)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay so apparently how puzzles work is I go nearly a year without posting one and then when I post a terrible one, I feel guilty and obligated to post a legitimate one soon after. Testsolved by chaotic_iak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a Fillomino (write a number in every empty cell so that every group of cells with the same number that is connected through its edges has that number of cells) where each tetromino has had their 4s replaced by one of L, I, T, or S describing their shape, and they obey the rules of LITS — they can touch if they are not congruent, they must all be connected, and their squares cannot form a 2×2 block. In addition, cells separated by a thick border may not contain the same number or letter.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 46 / Fillomino [LITS &#43; Extra Region &#43; Walls &#43; Anti-Walls &#43; Inequality &#43; Tapa &#43; Masyu]</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-46</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2015 13:01:08 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-46</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
5:27 PM &lt;strong&gt;phenomist&lt;/strong&gt;: do you use gridderface to make pretty puzzles?&lt;br /&gt;
…&lt;br /&gt;
5:52 PM &lt;strong&gt;phenomist&lt;/strong&gt;: actually nvm excel is probably easier lol
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay I’m sorry this is a horrible puzzle where the rules don’t make sense and I didn’t even get it testsolved. I just wanted an image to concisely demonstrate the capabilities of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/betaveros/gridderface&#34;&gt;gridderface&lt;/a&gt;, my puzzle marking and creation program, for the project homepage, after somebody expressed interest in using the program to write a puzzle. Then I got tremendously carried away.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2015 MIT Mystery Hunt</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/hunt</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 11:45:50 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/hunt</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, it’s been over a week, which is a long time for blog posts to be delayed after the event they’re documenting in probably all of the world except my blog. So.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess this post should start with a bit of background. I’ve been puzzlehunting for… wow, three and a half years now. I was introduced to puzzlehunts from AoPS, when some fellow members got together a team for &lt;a href=&#34;http://puzzle.cisra.com.au/2011/teamstats_AoPS.html&#34;&gt;CiSRA 2011&lt;/a&gt;, and I think I’ve participated to some degree in every known internet Australian puzzlehunt since.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But as for my experience with the MIT Mystery Hunt in particular, I sort of hunted with a decidedly uncompetitive AoPS team in 2012 (I think we solved one puzzle exactly), but my serious hunting career began when dzaefn recruited me into the Random team (then Random Thymes) &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/hunter&#34;&gt;for the 2013 hunt&lt;/a&gt; (and I did blog obliquely about it). We didn’t win (and I actually didn’t participate that much because I was traveling with family) but the next year (as One Fish Two Fish Random Fish Blue Fish (1f-2f-17f-255f (I am evidently in a parentheses mood today because as you’ve probably noticed, the amount and depth of parentheses in this sentence are positively alarming (lol)))) we won.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I do have a half-written post about that which will never get posted (and I &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; didn’t participate that much, because my family was moving that weekend) but okay, let’s just drop any semblance of chronological coherence on this blog and dump a short version of the list of puzzles and parts towards which I contributed solving, as I wrote them down one year ago:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commemorating Obvious Milestones Involving Chronological Sustenance</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/comics</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/comics</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, there had to be something here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately I don’t have time for anything more complex, so here’s a low-effort illogical puzzle for the occasion. (It &lt;em&gt;has&lt;/em&gt; been testsolved, at least. Thanks, Yoshiap.) It also features a brand new category, so as not to distract the people on LMI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don’t already know what occasion it is, it’s easy to find out by looking through my archives or possibly anywhere else I’ve left a trail online. Or you could solve the puzzle! (Or you could &lt;ins datetime=&#34;2014-11-20T12:29:52+00:00&#34;&gt;scroll down to read the solution!&lt;/ins&gt;) If this puzzle had an answer, it would be a nine-letter word, although like most of mathematics, it’s less about the answer than about the path you take to get there…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ins datetime=&#34;2017-11-24T18:36:41-0500&#34;&gt;
2017 edit: A warning that this has somewhat linkrotted and is harder to solve, but theoretically still possible.
&lt;/ins&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 45 / Fillomino [No-Path]</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-45</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2014 08:15:37 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-45</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As requested, a puzzle post! Straight from the WTF-variant department. Quite hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nikoli.co.jp/en/puzzles/fillomino.html&#34;&gt;Fillomino&lt;/a&gt;, with the additional constraint that for each polyomino, there must &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; exist a path (i.e. a sequence of cells, each orthogonally adjacent to the next) that includes each of the polyomino’s cells exactly once (and does not include cells outside the polyomino).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a degenerate case, 1-ominoes are banned as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 44 / ???</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-44</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 00:00:26 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-44</guid>
      <description>&lt;ins datetime=&#34;2013-11-18T23:20:18+00:00&#34;&gt;
Edit 11/19 7:23 AM UTC+8: Fixed some transcription errors on right: &lt;strong&gt;R4C17 is D instead of N, and R15C17 is G instead of E.&lt;/strong&gt; Neither change should greatly impact solvability. Thanks to ksun for pointing out an error.
&lt;/ins&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Logic puzzles are easy to construct if one doesn’t have some specific pattern or theme in mind. It’s just that, given the increasing number of constructors and puzzles with amazing themes, I don’t think it’s very meaningful for me to just construct more puzzles of the same genres by putting down clues randomly. That’s why, for my seventeenth birthday, I took the puzzlehunt route and made something without instructions that is not completely solved by logical deduction. Still, I’ve provided all the information needed to do this puzzle initially, so I hope my not getting the inductive bits test-solved can be excused.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 43 / Fillomino [Nonrectangular &#43; Walls]</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-43</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2013 20:52:46 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-43</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m extremely satisfied — a little incredulous, in fact — with how this puzzle came out. &lt;a href=&#34;https://chaosatthesky.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt;chaotic_iak&lt;/a&gt; labels it the “most ridiculous fillomino ever in history”. Apparently, it’s rather tricky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ins datetime=&#34;2013-09-30T13:05:57+00:00&#34;&gt;
ETA: Journalistic responsibility compels me to mention that chaotic_iak also added, “might be beaten later”. Oops?
&lt;/ins&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nikoli.co.jp/en/puzzles/fillomino.html&#34;&gt;Fillomino&lt;/a&gt; combining the &lt;a href=&#34;http://mathgrant.blogspot.tw/2011/09/monday-mutant-95-polyominous-no.html&#34;&gt;Nonrectangular&lt;/a&gt; (polyominoes can’t be rectangles) and &lt;a href=&#34;http://mathgrant.blogspot.tw/2012/10/fillomino-fillia-2-preview-series-walls.html&#34;&gt;Walls&lt;/a&gt; (polyominoes can’t span thick lines) variant rules. I think the first variant first came from mathgrant; I’m not as sure about the second, but they both appeared in &lt;a href=&#34;http://logicmastersindia.com/forum/forums/thread-view.asp?tid=525&amp;amp;posts=64&amp;amp;start=1&#34;&gt;Fillomino-Fillia 2&lt;/a&gt;, at least.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write a number in every empty cell so that every group of cells with the same number that is connected through its edges is a shape that’s not a rectangle with that number of cells. In addition, cells separated by a thick border may not contain the same number.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 42 / Fillomino [Greater-Than]</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-42</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2013 08:57:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-42</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Oops, I forgot the “puzzles” category was semi-reserved for puzzles I constructed/wrote, because among other things an LMI bot is following it. Anyway, if this makes up for anything, I have a puzzle that I’ve procrastinated posting for very, very long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nikoli.co.jp/en/puzzles/fillomino.html&#34;&gt;Fillomino&lt;/a&gt; puzzle. Inequality signs in the grid must be satisfied by the two numbers they touch.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MUMS Puzzle Hunt 2013</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/mums</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2013 21:44:24 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/mums</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/informatix.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/informatix.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;Informatix [MUMS Puzzle Hunt 2013]&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I somehow managed to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ms.unimelb.edu.au/~mums/puzzlehunt/teamstats.html?team=not+AoPS&#34;&gt;get 25 points all by myself&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ms.unimelb.edu.au/~mums/puzzlehunt/&#34;&gt;MUMS Puzzle Hunt 2013&lt;/a&gt;. Well, I pestered chaotic_iak a little with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ms.unimelb.edu.au/~mums/puzzlehunt/2013/puzzles/3.3_Diagnosus_ghQ3AcbJ.html&#34;&gt;3.3 Diagnosus (.html with animated .gif)&lt;/a&gt; but we still didn’t recognize all the Pokémon until hint 3, at which point Google sufficed for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is nowhere near the top, but compared to the usual results of whatever AoPS team I form, it’s amazing. By far the best result of AoPS was on CiSRA in 2010 (46th with 58 points), before I discovered puzzle hunts in AoPS; unfortunately due to people getting older and the influx of younger and younger people to the fora, there are less possible teammates each year and they have less time, so here I am by myself. (Also I could have accepted an invitation from a guy in the some-form-of-Elephant team, but I figure if you can win two MUMS hunts in a row you don’t need any more people.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all: Yay!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 41 / Slitherlink [Clones]</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-41</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2013 17:27:26 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-41</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I survived midterms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nikoli.co.jp/en/puzzles/slitherlink.html&#34;&gt;Slitherlink&lt;/a&gt; mutant. Draw a loop through adjacent vertices that cannot intersect itself. Each number indicates how many of the four edges around it are drawn. In addition, each pair of colored squares in corresponding positions (e.g. R1C1 and R6C6, R2C8 and R7C3) must have an equal number of edges drawn around them (i.e. if there were numbers placed there, they would be equal).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 40 / Fillomino [Samurai]</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-40</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 00:03:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-40</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yeah, and there’s this. chaotic_iak rejected this variant for his &lt;a href=&#34;https://chaosatthesky.wordpress.com/puzzles/#fff&#34;&gt;February sequence&lt;/a&gt; in order to get consistent 7x7 dimensions, so I made one. It’s been about a month. I have no idea why I procrastinated posting it until now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a Samurai &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nikoli.co.jp/en/puzzles/fillomino.html&#34;&gt;Fillomino&lt;/a&gt;, which means each grid satisfies the constraints on its own. Write a number in every empty cell so that, in each square grid, every group of cells with the same number that is connected through its edges has that number of cells. Note that the two grids must contain the same numbers where they overlap, but the grouping should be considered independently. I’d explain this really carefully if it weren’t the main gimmick of this puzzle.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 39 / Contact &#43; Slitherlink [Antisymmetric]</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-39</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2013 21:38:54 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-39</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yay crazy hybrids! I guess this one is kind of hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Draw a loop through adjacent vertices that cannot intersect itself. For each pair of symmetrically placed numbers, one is a Slitherlink clue which indicates how many of the four edges around it are drawn, and one is a Contact clue which indicates the total length of all straight segments adjacent to it where segment length is always measured up to the nearest turns in the loop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;del datetime=&#34;2017-11-25T16:26:24-0500&#34;&gt;
Please click on the image if it looks weird, which it very likely will.
&lt;/del&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;ins datetime=&#34;2017-11-25T16:26:37-0500&#34;&gt;(This was a WordPress bug that should no longer be relevant.)&lt;/ins&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 38 / Contact</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-38</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2013 00:00:47 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-38</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;http://inabapuzzle.com/honkaku/contact.html&#34;&gt;Naoki Inaba (JP)&lt;/a&gt; type, as seen on &lt;a href=&#34;http://puzzleparasite.blogspot.tw/2012/01/rules-contact.html&#34;&gt;Para’s Puzzle Site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Draw a loop through adjacent vertices that cannot intersect itself; each number indicates the total length of all straight segments adjacent to it, where segment length is always measured up to the nearest turns in the loop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s see how well WordPress’s scheduling works again. Happy Chinese New Year!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 37 / Slitherlink &#43; Masyu</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-37</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2013 15:16:51 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-37</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nikoli &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nikoli.co.jp/en/puzzles/slitherlink.html&#34;&gt;Slitherlink&lt;/a&gt; + &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nikoli.co.jp/en/puzzles/masyu.html&#34;&gt;Masyu&lt;/a&gt; hybrid; I don’t know who first put them together but combinations like this aren’t rare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Draw a loop through vertices that cannot intersect itself; each number indicates how many of the four edges around it are drawn; the loop must pass through all large dots, and it must go straight through white dots while turning either before or after (or both), while it must turn on black dots without turning either before or after.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 36 / Fillomino [LITS]</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-36</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 18:29:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-36</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mathgrant.blogspot.tw/2012/11/monday-mutant-119-polyominous-tetra.html&#34;&gt;mathgrant’s hybrid type&lt;/a&gt;: a Fillomino (write a number in every empty cell so that every group of cells with the same number that is connected through its edges has that number of cells) where each tetromino has had their 4s replaced by one of L, I, T, or S describing their shape, and they obey the rules of LITS — they can touch if they are not congruent, they must all be connected, and their squares cannot form a 2x2 block.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hunter on Vacation</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/hunter</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 16:18:58 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/hunter</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/rainbow.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/rainbow.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;Very faint rainbow&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
Faint rainbow
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So winter vacation started and parents had planned a trip to southern Taiwan, to get closer to nature and walk around and stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, the MIT Mystery Hunt, the absolute granddaddy of all the other puzzlehunts in terms of age, structure, and size, happened this weekend. Originally, I didn’t have a team and just planned to look at the puzzles after they got archived and &lt;s&gt;try solving some puzzles&lt;/s&gt; read the solutions while constantly thinking, “How could anybody ever solve that?” Because of that, I wasn’t planning to even bring my laptop at first; then I could force myself to study some long-overdue ring theory during the nights. I was taken aback by a private message on Saturday morning from somebody with many different names inviting me to remote-solve for Random Thymes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Me: !!!!!!!!!!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 35 / Double Back</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-35</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2013 22:42:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-35</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is another &lt;a href=&#34;https://mellowmelon.wordpress.com/double-back/&#34;&gt;MellowMelon’s Double Back&lt;/a&gt;. Briefly, draw a closed loop through all square centers visiting each bold-outlined area twice. Shaded cells do not influence solving, only aesthetics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s mostly easy, I think. It’s okay if you don’t know what the theme means. (Yes, chao, I want more contrib points.) Also, WordPress seems to have stopped automatically linking images to their files. Hmm.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 34 / Snail&#39;s Nest</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-34</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2012 22:08:43 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-34</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been a while, hasn’t it? This is something I constructed semi-experimentally to stop failing at an entire genre of puzzles, and then procrastinated posting just about forever. I only test-solved this on paper; I hope I didn’t do anything silly while digitizing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rules paraphrased from USPC because I can’t find any good links: Write each of the given words into its own snail; letters must be entered from the outside of the snail spirally inward. Not all squares will be used; squares with “-” must stay blank. Each letter can appear at most once in each row and column.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gridderface 0.5</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/gridderface-0-5</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2012 17:53:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/gridderface-0-5</guid>
      <description>Okay, I give up. Here it is: Gridderface is a (quoting the project description, which I wrote anyway so whatever) “keyboard inferface for marking grid-based puzzles in Java” that I’ve been working on for too long. It is open-source under the GPL v3.
Basically, it’s a thing you can paste logic puzzle images into to solve them in, like people do in Paint, when you can’t or don’t want to print them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 33 / Ice Barns</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-33</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2012 20:59:38 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-33</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Noticed this at &lt;a href=&#34;http://meanderlawn.blogspot.tw/&#34;&gt;meander lawn&lt;/a&gt; who has a really broad puzzle blogroll… I don’t really know what I’m doing and may have misinterpreted something, but here goes. (Ahahaha puzzle 33 on 11/22… I wish it was intentional :P)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Draw a path through square centers which enters and exits through the given places. Outside the “ice barns” (the gray things), the path may turn freely but may not self-intersect; inside “ice barns” the path may self-intersect but may not turn. Each ice barn (not necessarily every cell but every region, I think) must be passed over. The path must pass through each given arrow in the given direction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 32 / Slitherlink [Crosslink &#43; Liar]</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-32</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2012 00:00:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-32</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yes, a “big” crazy mutant puzzle for a “milestone” &lt;a href=&#34;https://xkcd.com/1000/&#34;&gt;(as seen on xkcd)&lt;/a&gt;, both for this blog and for my life. Things are rough now, but I prepared this ridiculously ahead of time. It’s still not &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; big, but I’m not so experienced and I don’t have the inspiration for something like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.artofproblemsolving.com/Forum/viewtopic.php?f=535&amp;amp;t=506208&#34;&gt;an entire mini-puzzlehunt&lt;/a&gt;. Also, I think I should attempt more word-bank-based puzzles some day so I won’t fail as completely at them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But anyway: This is a Slitherlink combining MellowMelon’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://mellowmelon.wordpress.com/slitherlink/crosslink/&#34;&gt;Crosslink&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://mellowmelon.wordpress.com/category/puzzle-types/slitherlink/liar-slitherlink/&#34;&gt;Liar&lt;/a&gt; variations. Draw a loop through vertices that can intersect itself but must go straight both times if it does; each number normally indicates how many of the four edges around it are draw, but exactly one clue in each row and column is false. Have fun.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 31 / Fillomino [Sashigane]</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-31</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2012 17:03:16 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-31</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nikoli.co.jp/en/puzzles/fillomino.html&#34;&gt;Fillomino&lt;/a&gt; puzzle where every polyomino is required to be an L-shape, as in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nikoli.co.jp/en/puzzles/sashigane.html&#34;&gt;Sashigane&lt;/a&gt;. Write a number in every empty cell so that every group of cells with the same number that is connected through its edges is an L-shape (with arms of positive length and 1-cell thickness) with that number of cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My second, and now symmetric, attempt at this crazy self-invented mutant; &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-22&#34;&gt;puzzle 22&lt;/a&gt; was the first. A word of warning: I can’t solve this without bifurcating near the end, so logic purists may be disappointed, but I like the clue arrangement too much. In fact I suspect this puzzle could have many more clues removed without affecting uniqueness, so tight are the rule constraints in this type.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 30 / Fillomino [Skyscrapers]</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-30</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2012 16:58:09 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-30</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Haha, way-overdue &lt;a href=&#34;http://logicmastersindia.com/FF2/&#34;&gt;Fillomino-Fillia&lt;/a&gt; practice puzzle. This is a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nikoli.co.jp/en/puzzles/fillomino.html&#34;&gt;Fillomino&lt;/a&gt; puzzle; in addition to normal rules, treat numbers inside the grid as building heights. Numbers outside the grid indicate how many buildings can be seen from that direction, where a building blocks all buildings of lower or equal height behind it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit: I should warn that the arithmetic here is pretty annoying.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 29 / Corral [Antisymmetric Multiplicative]</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-29</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2012 17:35:43 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-29</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://mellowmelon.wordpress.com/corral/&#34;&gt;Corral&lt;/a&gt; puzzle in which half the clues are &lt;a href=&#34;http://mathgrant.blogspot.tw/2012/08/monday-mutant-117-inner-limits.html&#34;&gt;multiplicative&lt;/a&gt;. For each symmetric pair of clues, one is normal and one is multiplicative.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 28 / Fillomino [Nonrectangular]</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-28</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2012 20:39:47 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-28</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nikoli.co.jp/en/puzzles/fillomino.html&#34;&gt;Fillomino&lt;/a&gt; puzzle where every polyomino is required to be nonrectangular (which also bans squares). Write a number in every empty cell so that every group of cells with the same number that is connected through its edges is a shape that’s not a rectangle with that number of cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://logicmastersindia.com/FF2/&#34;&gt;Fillomino-Fillia 2&lt;/a&gt; is coming! Anyway I don’t know how to judge difficulty but this is probably terrible practice. I should try a Skyscrapers if I can keep pretending USH homework doesn’t exist which I probably shouldn’t.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 27 / LITS</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-27</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2012 19:37:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-27</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nice and tricky. (I think.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact I tried to be too tricky and spent a very long time fixing an ambiguity. It was worth it though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nikoli.co.jp/en/puzzles/lits.html&#34;&gt;LITS - Nikoli.&lt;/a&gt; Exactly one tetromino per region, no 2x2s, they’re connected, adjacent tetrominoes are noncongruent.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 26 / Double Back</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-26</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2012 08:48:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-26</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;That’s not a picture. Why is it recreated as one? Oh well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can interpret this as me about reaching level 8.1 (the user ranking) on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rankk.org/&#34;&gt;rankk&lt;/a&gt; or complaining about how infuriating level 8.1 (the puzzle) is. I’m torn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one of a bunch of &lt;a href=&#34;https://mellowmelon.wordpress.com/double-back/&#34;&gt;MellowMelon’s Double Backs&lt;/a&gt;. Briefly, draw a closed loop through all square centers visiting each bold-outlined area twice. Shaded cells do not influence solving, only aesthetics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 25 / Double Back</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-25</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2012 08:40:02 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-25</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most uncreative picture ever! But it’s suitable after &lt;a href=&#34;http://puzzle.cisra.com.au/&#34;&gt;CiSRA’s Puzzle Week&lt;/a&gt;. This might be the first time our AoPS team managed all four puzzles in a group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;…sigh, now I must handle the guilt for squeezing out so much time from my normal schedule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one of a bunch of &lt;a href=&#34;https://mellowmelon.wordpress.com/double-back/&#34;&gt;MellowMelon’s Double Backs&lt;/a&gt;. Briefly, draw a closed loop through all square centers visiting each bold-outlined area twice. Shaded cells do not influence solving, only aesthetics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 24 / Double Back</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-24</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2012 08:26:11 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-24</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Right, back to puzzles because I have nothing substantial to say. Circumstantial evidence suggests I created this one in June.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one of a bunch of &lt;a href=&#34;https://mellowmelon.wordpress.com/double-back/&#34;&gt;MellowMelon’s Double Backs&lt;/a&gt;. Draw a closed loop through all square centers visiting each bold-outlined area twice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 23 / Corral [Multiplicative]</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-23</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2012 21:49:01 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-23</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mathgrant.blogspot.tw/2012/08/monday-mutant-117-inner-limits.html&#34;&gt;Too lazy to explain rules today&lt;/a&gt; although this is probably an easy one.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 22 / Fillomino [Sashigane]</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-22</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2012 21:07:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-22</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nikoli.co.jp/en/puzzles/fillomino.html&#34;&gt;Fillomino&lt;/a&gt; puzzle where every polyomino is required to be an L-shape, as in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nikoli.co.jp/en/puzzles/sashigane.html&#34;&gt;Sashigane&lt;/a&gt;. Write a number in every empty cell so that every group of cells with the same number that is connected through its edges is an L-shape (with arms of positive length and 1-cell thickness) with that number of cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May be slightly reminiscent of &lt;a href=&#34;http://mathgrant.blogspot.com/2011/09/monday-mutant-95-polyominous-no.html&#34;&gt;no-rectangle Fillominoes&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Slightly…&lt;/em&gt; (Has anybody done this before? It seems so interesting that I feel like I couldn’t be first.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 21 / LITS</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-21</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2012 10:27:40 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-21</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I made this a long time ago but put it off until I had programmed enough to digitize it without my fingers leaving the home row. I think the finish is interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nikoli.co.jp/en/puzzles/lits.html&#34;&gt;LITS - Nikoli.&lt;/a&gt; Exactly one tetromino per region, no 2x2s, they’re connected, adjacent tetrominoes are noncongruent.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 20 / Sashigane</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-20</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2012 07:12:36 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-20</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/20-sashigane.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/20-sashigane.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Sashigane&#34; width=&#34;345&#34; height=&#34;345&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-1302&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, I lied last time I made one of these; the original Nikoli name wasn’t that hard to remember, and “sashigane puzzles” has shown up as a search query, so here you go. Perfect opposite-type-clue rotational symmetry, chaotic_iak! I hope you’re satisfied now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 19 / Yajilin</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-19</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2012 14:16:36 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-19</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have just realized that I have only ever tried one level of difficulty in puzzle construction, viz., “as hard as I can make it”. This is mainly because I don’t want to construct anything overly trivial with the same few tricks, but, well, maybe it’s not the best idea for actually trying to build an audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Am I actually trying to build an audience? Am I? *shudders*&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Yajilin summary: fill in some cells, draw a loop through the rest, filled cells aren’t adjacent, arrows denote # of filled cells along some ray; &lt;a href=&#34;https://mellowmelon.wordpress.com/yajilin/&#34;&gt;MellowMelon’s rules&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 18 / Smullyanic Dynasty</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-18</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 19:03:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-18</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Again, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://zotmeister.dreamwidth.org/2005/03/22/&#34;&gt;Zotmeister type&lt;/a&gt;. (Short rules: each cell states how many liars are in the 3x3 square centered at it, liars incorrectly so. Liars satisfy the “dynasty” rule i.e. liars are not orthogonally adjacent and non-liars are connected through sides.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 17 / Corral</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-17</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2012 19:07:41 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-17</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Corral puzzle, aka Cave aka Bag etc. (Yes, from nikoli.) Short rules: draw a loop along the grid lines; each numbered cell is in the loop and the number denotes how many cells can be seen vertically or horizontally from that cell, plus the cell itself. Stealing link to &lt;a href=&#34;https://mellowmelon.wordpress.com/corral/&#34;&gt;MellowMelon’s long rules&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 16 / Slitherlink [Domino]</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-16</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2012 19:57:09 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-16</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Slitherlink with 20 clues taken out as dominoes and their original positions shaded. For more lucid rules please visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://mellowmelon.wordpress.com/2010/10/21/puzzle-263/&#34;&gt;MellowMelon’s puzzle 263&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Domino set is all possible dominoes exactly once each: &lt;strong&gt;{00,01,02,03,11,12,13,22,23,33}&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 15 / Sudoku / Happy Birthday!</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-15</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2012 00:00:08 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-15</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A bonus gift for the birthday of a very important person! Ignore the colors while solving.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 14 / Slitherlink</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-14</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2012 20:46:51 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-14</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just a normal one this time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 13 / Akari</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-13</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2012 06:44:28 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-13</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Somewhat depressing almost-symmetry.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 12 / Sashigane</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-12</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2012 13:30:47 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-12</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are reading this, then our APMO testing time is over! There’s a small chance of me being really happy or really frustrated about how I did, but I’m betting on a solid “meh.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mathgrant.blogspot.com/2012/01/rules-ellbound.html&#34;&gt;Rules page&lt;/a&gt; by mathgrant. There’s no way I’m going to memorize the Japanese name yet. [edit: It’s Sashigane. It’s not that hard.]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 11 / Smullyanic Dynasty</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-11</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2012 18:25:47 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-11</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://zotmeister.dreamwidth.org/2005/03/22/&#34;&gt;Ruleset&lt;/a&gt; designed by Zotmeister.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 10 / Nurikabe 3</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-10</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2012 18:00:11 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-10</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A ratio-preserving enlargement of the janko.at sample invocation puzzle, perhaps. I wanted to try using smaller clues. Finally a grid too large for full-size displaying! Is that even supposed to be an achievement?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 9 / Yajilin</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-9</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2012 12:00:09 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-9</guid>
      <description>Man, hacking new puzzle types into the image generator is an amazing way to procrastinate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 8 / Fillomino</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-8</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2012 12:00:58 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-8</guid>
      <description>Hey, a “theme” (look at the corners)!

Honestly though I’m just spreading out my puzzle posts so there’s some illusion of regularity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 7 / Slitherlink [All Twos]</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-7</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2012 18:47:04 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-7</guid>
      <description>It’s 2/22 and I have low standards.

This is a normal Slitherlink, except all the 2s have been given to you. Thus, empty squares cannot have exactly two edges around them. Of course it’s been done before (guess who?)
I appear to be drastically overshooting a monthly schedule :P</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 6 / Fillomino</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-6</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2012 17:55:52 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-6</guid>
      <description>Not actually my first try, but I guess I don’t need to resort to 6x6s to fill up my quota just yet, do I?

Okay for the absolutely uninformed, this is a Fillomino (or see MellowMelon’s rule page).
I’ve switched to 32x32 pixel cells because they seem a reasonable size and it’s possible to express all pixel sizes as an exact floating-point fraction of the cell side so my image generator can be used in a general way to get perfect stroke thicknesses without worrying about any rounding errors no matter how obviously numerically insignificant they would be in this case.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 5 (Liar Slitherlink)</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-5</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2012 12:19:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-5</guid>
      <description>One puzzle a month! What a prolific schedule!

A Liar Slitherlink as created by MellowMelon (probably). Normal Slitherlink rules except exactly one clue in each row and column is false; you figure out which. But I bet you knew that already.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 4 / Nurikabe (&#43;Lists of Obscure Stuff)</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-4</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2012 21:11:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-4</guid>
      <description>I was like “Let’s make a 15x15!” and got confused by the graph lines and stopped early. Anyway, I think the steps aren’t so trivial now. I’m still too lazy to fix my generator, however.
   yes, normal Nurikabe   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 3 / Nurikabe</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-3</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2012 17:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-3</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I only just managed to make a 10x10 that’s not broken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.janko.at/Applets/Nurikabe/q.php?w=450&amp;amp;h=340&amp;amp;r=10&amp;amp;c=10&amp;amp;p=,,4,,,,3,,,/,8,,,,,,,,/,,,5,,,,,,/,,,,,,,3,,/,,,,,,,,,/,,,,,,,,,/,,,,,,,7,,/,3,,,,,,,3,/,,2,,,,,,,/,,,,,4,,,,&#34;&gt;janko.at applet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 2 / Slitherlink</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-2</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:01:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-2</guid>
      <description>Written for the new year of 2012.

(janko.at applet)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 1 (Wild Slitherlink Appeared!)</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-1</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2011 19:24:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-1</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>