<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Puzzles on Bounded-Error Log</title>
    <link>//blog.vero.site/category/puzzles</link>
    <description>Recent content in Puzzles on Bounded-Error Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2017 14:27:18 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//blog.vero.site/category/puzzles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>I guess January is puzzles month</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/january</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2017 14:27:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/january</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;And it’s not even January any more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Thing negative two: Thing zero, which is at the bottom of this post, contains two puzzles by me. Skip there if that sounds interesting and text walls don’t.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thing negative one: I abandoned this blog (again). The last month has been a mess and much of it is political stuff of the sort that I’m the worst/slowest at writing about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thing one: I was on-site for a second MIT Mystery Hunt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>020315040524</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/bcodex</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 13:54:22 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/bcodex</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;--... ---.. ....- ..... ..--- ----- ....- ....- ...-- -.... ...-- -.... ...-- . ....- ....- ..--- ----- ....- ..... ...-- ----. ...-- -.... ....- ...-- ...-- -.... ..... -.... ....- ....- ..--- ----- ...-- ..-. ....- ----- ..--- ----- ...-- ..--- ...-- ..-. ....- ..... ...-- .- ...-- ..... ....- ----- ....- ..... ...-- -.... ..--- ----- ...-- --... ....- ----- ....- ...-- ..--- ----- ...-- ..--- ...-- ..-. ...-- ---.. ....- ....- ....- ..... ..--- ----- ...-- -.. ...-- .- ...-- -.-. ...-- -.... ..--- ----- ...-- --... ...-- .- ...-- ..-. ...-- ..... ...-- .- ...-- ..-. ...-- ---.. ..--- ----- ....- ....- ....- ----- ...-- . ...-- -.... ....- ..... ...-- ----. ...-- .- ...-- ..-. ...-- ---.. ..--- ----- ...-- ....- ....- ----- ....- ----- ...-- -.. ..--- ----- ...-- ..--- ...-- ..-. ...-- ..... ..--- ----- ...-- ..... ....- ----- ....- ---.. ...-- ..-. ..... -.-. ....- ..... ....- ----- ..... -.-. ...-- -.... ...-- ..--- ....- ...-- ....- ..... ...-- ----. ..... -... ..--- ----- ...-- ..--- ...-- ..-. ...-- ..... ..--- ----- ...-- ..... ....- ----- ...-- .- ...-- ..-. ...-- ---.. ..--- ----- ...-- .- ....- ..... ..... -..&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>whoosh</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/whoosh</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 08:19:46 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/whoosh</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I finally did it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was on-site for the 2016 MIT Mystery Hunt. I even &lt;em&gt;solved a metapuzzle&lt;/em&gt;. This year I hunted with ✈✈✈ Galactic Trendsetters ✈✈✈, the team primarily but not overwhelmingly formed from floorpi, my dorm floor. (Perhaps somewhat regrettably, I didn’t contribute to any events or runarounds or things given to HQ, unless you count attending a “recitation” for Student Simulator (round King Arthur, second from left).)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Also, I made this post. Has it been two weeks already? Okay, that’s not an unusual timeframe.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But wow, I got to touch so many puzzles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Non-spoilery comments on particularly memorable puzzles I did, which are disproportionately programming-related, if anybody wants to look at them (I am describing how to get to the puzzle from the round instead of linking because I’m lazy and links might rot but the instructions will hopefully survive archival (although turns out there’s actually a &lt;a href=&#34;http://huntception.com/toc.html&#34;&gt;table of contents&lt;/a&gt; so I don’t know what I’m doing)):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three for the Price of One (Meta)</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/three-for-one</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2015 13:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/three-for-one</guid>
      <description>And that’s another year!
As usual, you can check your answers here. Text above this horizontal rule is not part of the puzzle.
Solvers:
Yoshiap @ 11-20 13:31:56  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When Is My Birthday Again?</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/birthday-again</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 13:00:25 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/birthday-again</guid>
      <description>As usual, you can check your answers here. Text above this horizontal rule is not part of the puzzle.
Solvers (in my local UTC−5 because I’m lazy):
Lewis Chen (phenomist) @ 11-19 05:03:07 Jack Lance @ 11-19 10:39:11 Yoshiap @ 11-20 03:29:54  No, it’s not July 16 any more. “July” doesn’t even have 16 letters.
January 4, January 6, January 9, February 6, February 10, July 16, July 25, September 4, September 10, September 16 April 3, April 5, June 17, June 24, August 2, August 5, August 18, November 2, November 3, November 17 April 5, April 9, May 1, May 5, May 8, July 6, July 24, December 1, December 6, December 9 March 7, March 24, April 1, April 2, April 7, November 1, November 5, November 13, December 2, December 5 February 8, February 11, February 13, March 11, March 23, April 4, April 8, April 15, October 4, October 13 January 5, January 20, March 1, March 4, March 10, October 2, October 4, October 5, December 1, December 2 March 6, March 8, March 18, April 10, April 25, September 6, September 15, November 8, November 10, November 15 March 11, March 23, June 3, June 4, June 17, July 1, July 4, August 1, August 3, August 11 January 1, January 2, April 1, April 4, April 8, September 2, September 4, September 13, October 8, October 21 February 1, February 11, February 12, July 1, July 3, July 16, August 3, August 12, September 11, September 22 January 5, January 6, January 17, August 1, August 6, August 18, September 5, September 18, November 1, November 24  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anticron</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/anticron</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2015 13:00:59 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/anticron</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I did not get this successfully testsolved, although, for whatever comfort it may provide, I did engage in several interactive rounds of nerfing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As usual, &lt;a href=&#34;http://bpchen.scripts.mit.edu/2015/&#34;&gt;you can check your answers here.&lt;/a&gt; Text above this horizontal rule is not part of the puzzle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solvers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Signature Puzzle</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/signature-puzzle</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2015 13:00:06 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/signature-puzzle</guid>
      <description>As usual, there had to be something here. In fact, this year, there are several somethings. Hype!
This is based on an idea by chaotic_iak. You can check your answers here. Text above this horizontal rule is not part of the puzzle.
ETA 11/17 16:15 UTC−5: Adjusted spacing between the bottom numbers after feedback. The puzzle is otherwise the same, and solving should not be significantly impacted.  Solvers (in my local UTC−5 because I’m lazy):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 47 / Fillomino [LITS &#43; Walls]</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-47</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2015 20:01:26 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-47</guid>
      <description>CLICKBAIT PERSONALITY TEST THAT YOU CAN DO WITHOUT SOLVING THE PUZZLE: What do you see in the puzzle image below? I have my own thoughts but I won’t bias you by posting them yet. Sound out your thoughts in the comments below! (I don’t expect this to work but I’d love to be proven wrong)
Okay so apparently how puzzles work is I go nearly a year without posting one and then when I post a terrible one, I feel guilty and obligated to post a legitimate one soon after.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 46 / Fillomino [LITS &#43; Extra Region &#43; Walls &#43; Anti-Walls &#43; Inequality &#43; Tapa &#43; Masyu]</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-46</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2015 13:01:08 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-46</guid>
      <description>5:27 PM phenomist: do you use gridderface to make pretty puzzles?
…
5:52 PM phenomist: actually nvm excel is probably easier lol  Okay I’m sorry this is a horrible puzzle where the rules don’t make sense and I didn’t even get it testsolved. I just wanted an image to concisely demonstrate the capabilities of gridderface, my puzzle marking and creation program, for the project homepage, after somebody expressed interest in using the program to write a puzzle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2015 MIT Mystery Hunt (spoiler-free version)</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/hunt</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 11:45:50 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/hunt</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, it’s been over a week, which is a long time for blog posts to be delayed after the event they’re documenting in probably all of the world except my blog. So.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess this post should start with a bit of background. I’ve been puzzlehunting for… wow, three and a half years now. I was introduced to puzzlehunts from AoPS, when some fellow members got together a team for &lt;a href=&#34;http://puzzle.cisra.com.au/2011/teamstats_AoPS.html&#34;&gt;CiSRA 2011&lt;/a&gt;, and I think I’ve participated to some degree in every known internet Australian puzzlehunt since.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commemorating Obvious Milestones Involving Chronological Sustenance</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/comics</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/comics</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, there had to be something here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately I don’t have time for anything more complex, so here’s a low-effort illogical puzzle for the occasion. (It &lt;em&gt;has&lt;/em&gt; been testsolved, at least. Thanks, Yoshiap.) It also features a brand new category, so as not to distract the people on LMI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don’t already know what occasion it is, it’s easy to find out by looking through my archives or possibly anywhere else I’ve left a trail online. Or you could solve the puzzle! (Or you could &lt;ins datetime=&#34;2014-11-20T12:29:52+00:00&#34;&gt;scroll down to read the solution!&lt;/ins&gt;) If this puzzle had an answer, it would be a nine-letter word, although like most of mathematics, it’s less about the answer than about the path you take to get there…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ins datetime=&#34;2017-11-24T18:36:41-0500&#34;&gt;
2017 edit: A warning that this has somewhat linkrotted and is harder to solve, but theoretically still possible.
&lt;/ins&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 45 / Fillomino [No-Path]</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-45</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2014 08:15:37 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-45</guid>
      <description>As requested, a puzzle post! Straight from the WTF-variant department. Quite hard.
This is a Fillomino, with the additional constraint that for each polyomino, there must not exist a path (i.e. a sequence of cells, each orthogonally adjacent to the next) that includes each of the polyomino’s cells exactly once (and does not include cells outside the polyomino).
As a degenerate case, 1-ominoes are banned as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 43 / Fillomino [Nonrectangular &#43; Walls]</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-43</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2013 20:52:46 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-43</guid>
      <description>I’m extremely satisfied — a little incredulous, in fact — with how this puzzle came out. chaotic_iak labels it the “most ridiculous fillomino ever in history”. Apparently, it’s rather tricky.
ETA: Journalistic responsibility compels me to mention that chaotic_iak also added, “might be beaten later”. Oops?  This is a Fillomino combining the Nonrectangular (polyominoes can’t be rectangles) and Walls (polyominoes can’t span thick lines) variant rules. I think the first variant first came from mathgrant; I’m not as sure about the second, but they both appeared in Fillomino-Fillia 2, at least.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 36 / Fillomino [LITS]</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-36</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 18:29:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-36</guid>
      <description>mathgrant’s hybrid type: a Fillomino (write a number in every empty cell so that every group of cells with the same number that is connected through its edges has that number of cells) where each tetromino has had their 4s replaced by one of L, I, T, or S describing their shape, and they obey the rules of LITS — they can touch if they are not congruent, they must all be connected, and their squares cannot form a 2x2 block.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gridderface 0.5</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/gridderface-0-5</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2012 17:53:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/gridderface-0-5</guid>
      <description>Okay, I give up. Here it is: Gridderface is a (quoting the project description, which I wrote anyway so whatever) “keyboard inferface for marking grid-based puzzles in Java” that I’ve been working on for too long. It is open-source under the GPL v3.
Basically, it’s a thing you can paste logic puzzle images into to solve them in, like people do in Paint, when you can’t or don’t want to print them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 31 / Fillomino [Sashigane]</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-31</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2012 17:03:16 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-31</guid>
      <description>This is a Fillomino puzzle where every polyomino is required to be an L-shape, as in Sashigane. Write a number in every empty cell so that every group of cells with the same number that is connected through its edges is an L-shape (with arms of positive length and 1-cell thickness) with that number of cells.
My second, and now symmetric, attempt at this crazy self-invented mutant; puzzle 22 was the first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 22 / Fillomino [Sashigane]</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-22</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2012 21:07:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-22</guid>
      <description>This is a Fillomino puzzle where every polyomino is required to be an L-shape, as in Sashigane. Write a number in every empty cell so that every group of cells with the same number that is connected through its edges is an L-shape (with arms of positive length and 1-cell thickness) with that number of cells.
May be slightly reminiscent of no-rectangle Fillominoes. Slightly… (Has anybody done this before? It seems so interesting that I feel like I couldn’t be first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 10 / Nurikabe 3</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-10</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2012 18:00:11 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-10</guid>
      <description>A ratio-preserving enlargement of the janko.at sample invocation puzzle, perhaps. I wanted to try using smaller clues. Finally a grid too large for full-size displaying! Is that even supposed to be an achievement?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 2 / Slitherlink</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-2</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:01:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-2</guid>
      <description>Written for the new year of 2012.

(janko.at applet)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>