<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Card Games on Bounded-Error Log</title>
    <link>//blog.vero.site/tag/card-games</link>
    <description>Recent content in Card Games on Bounded-Error Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2015 08:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//blog.vero.site/tag/card-games/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ninety-nine (card game)</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/99</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2015 08:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/99</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Frivolous blog content, posted as part of a &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/commitment&#34;&gt;daily posting streak I have openly committed to&lt;/a&gt;; standard disclaimers apply)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is quite interesting that Wikipedia’s article on &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ninety-nine_%28addition_card_game%29&#34;&gt;Ninety-nine (addition card game)&lt;/a&gt;, plus many of the following search results (ignoring the identically-named trick-taking game that is guaranteed to show up), have the same basic idea but wildly differing assignment of special cards from the one I’m familiar with, which everybody I can recall having played with agrees on. (Admittedly I’ve only ever played this among Taiwanese friends.) The only special-card assignment method that came close was a certain person’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://nmnnmnnmmnnnmnrnmnmnnmn.wordpress.com/2012/09/27/concatenation/&#34;&gt;“stuff from my old blog” dumping post&lt;/a&gt; I bumped into very accidentally. (His 5 is our 4; our 5 skips to an arbitrary player. The post also clarifies that negative totals bounce back to zero, and includes a clause whereby players must state the running total after playing and lose if they’re wrong. Interesting.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, yes, I am documenting the rules to a card game on this blog. I think this deserves to exist online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These rules are not completely rigorous because I don’t know them completely rigorously. You can use common sense to reach a consensus in corner cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use a normal deck of playing cards, or two or more identical decks if you want. Deal five cards to each player and set the rest aside to form a draw pile. Cards are played into a discard pile in the center. Players sit in an approximate circle and take turns along the circle, playing one card and then, usually, drawing one replacement card from the draw pile, so in normal 99, hands stay at five cards. When the draw pile runs out, shuffle the discard pile to become the new draw pile.  There is a “running total” in the game, an integer that starts at 0. Normal cards add their value to the running total when played. The total cannot become greater than 99, hence the name. If you have no cards that could keep it less than or equal to 99, you lose. In that case, the turn passes to the next player and the game continues until only one player remains, or until players get bored and decide to play something else.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>