<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nuclear on Bounded-Error Log</title>
    <link>//blog.vero.site/tag/nuclear</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nuclear on Bounded-Error Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2015 11:40:47 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//blog.vero.site/tag/nuclear/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Nuclear II</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/nuclear-ii</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2015 11:40:47 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/nuclear-ii</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/commitment&#34;&gt;streak&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not any better than the &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/nuclear&#34;&gt;first installment&lt;/a&gt;, but I need to post. And then, you know, do homework and presentations and stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Carver had just managed to drill past Dr. Perkins’s cranium when she heard the door behind her creak open.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Ha! You walked right into my trap!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She turned around. Dr. Perkins was standing in the doorway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She looked down. Yes, they were both Dr. Perkins, she’d know that pair of glasses and spiky hair anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She looked up. Well, the guy in the doorway was wearing a set of black robes outside his white lab coat, but other than that, they really looked completely identical.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My DNSE Story</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/nuclear</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2015 17:12:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/nuclear</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Something something something &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/commitment&#34;&gt;daily posting streak&lt;/a&gt; something something standard disclaimers. My schedule is tighter than usual because IPSC is tonight and runs right up until midnight. Anyway, here’s my logic with posting this: given how long I’ve committed to posting, I’m probably going to have to dig deeply enough into my reserves to include it, and to be authentic I can’t edit the story more anyway, so I might as well do it now. (Also maybe this will pressure me into finishing and posting one of the real short stories in my blog draft folder, the same way I feel pressured to make a good puzzle after posting a bad one.) I’m not even going to reread my story because I don’t like cringing at my own writing without being able to edit it, but hopefully that makes it bad enough to be entertaining. If you didn’t know, this was for an MIT preorientation program application. Tell me if it’s bad to repost application stuff. I hope not.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Oops this introduction is about as long as the actual story now.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol type=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tell us a short story in the available space below. Your inspiration is only one word: nuclear. Go!
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>