<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mountains on Bounded-Error Log</title>
    <link>//blog.vero.site/tag/mountains</link>
    <description>Recent content in mountains on Bounded-Error Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2015 23:32:37 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//blog.vero.site/tag/mountains/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>[CIMC 2015 Part 3] Monsters and Pandas and Tigers, Oh My!</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/cimc-2015-part-3</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2015 23:32:37 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/cimc-2015-part-3</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My inner perfectionist is crying that I have to post this, in particular over my pathetic &lt;a href=&#34;http://snowclones.org/2007/05/22/x-y-and-z-oh-my/&#34;&gt;snowclone&lt;/a&gt; title, but my inner pragmatist knows that, judging by my old blogging patterns, it’s now or never.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;18.06: 56%, haven’t touched it in a while, but I think I can do lots more on the plane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a non-contestant, I confess I feel totally uninvested in the results and find the Closing Ceremony boring. All contestants go up, country by country, and have their awards read off. No effort is made to make any sort of buildup to a climax. But maybe this is for the best; we don’t want anybody feeling shafted or discouraged from continuing to do math due to a mere elementary-/middle-school competition. Meanwhile, though, I’m browsing reddit on my phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After this ceremony, the entire Taiwan delegation spends some time walking around outside while the guides make confused phone calls trying to decide where we eat lunch. My parents offer me some potato chips they bought somewhere, which are (as the label is really eager to point out) baked, not fried. Some time passes this way; eventually, the guides figure it out and we go through amazingly long queues to eat at the cafeteria, as usual. Then we are sent to a massive shopping mall for the afternoon, a place so large that its exits have number labels that go up into the double digits so that people don’t get lost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I take trippy failed panorama photos from the bus windows. &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/trippy-panorama.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/trippy-panorama.jpg?w=652&#34; alt=&#34;[trippy panorama of a shopping mall]&#34; width=&#34;652&#34; height=&#34;427&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter size-large wp-image-3321&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>