<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Randomness on Bounded-Error Log</title>
    <link>//blog.vero.site/category/randomness</link>
    <description>Recent content in Randomness on Bounded-Error Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2015 11:46:04 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//blog.vero.site/category/randomness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>[warp]clicker.html</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/clicker</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2015 11:46:04 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/clicker</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Okay, just one more post for the &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/commitment&#34;&gt;streak&lt;/a&gt; milking the stuff uncovered in my old hard drive, and then it’s over, I promise. Here is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://betaveros.github.io/clicker.html&#34;&gt;silly three-button idle game&lt;/a&gt; I discovered, which I apparently made in 2010 when I was a bored eighth-grader and the most recent jQuery version was 1.4.x. Instead of enjoying a text wall, please enjoy trying to get 16,384 clicks in the non-warp version. (There’s no victory message or anything; it’s just a nice round number that I reached while writing this post. And yes, I know you can call JavaScript from your developer console, or edit the source or DOM. That’s cheating.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I realize this is short even for filler posts, so if you don’t want to play an idle game, here is a remix of &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/numbers-bmp&#34;&gt;numbers.bmp&lt;/a&gt; to stare at and feel inspired by. Or disgusted with, or indignant at. Your choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>numbers.bmp</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/numbers-bmp</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 14:06:09 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/numbers-bmp</guid>
      <description>Mom dug up an old hard drive for me to find photos of my elementary-school self participating in the same math competition I’m presenting at in a week. I discovered a lot of other interesting old stuff there. So today’s filler post image for the streak is courtesy of Brian2003/03/23. I don’t think it means anything, but sorry, I really really need to work on that presentation.

To be clear, I didn’t actually upload the original .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>US$2,857</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/2857</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2015 23:20:09 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/2857</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;= within 15 cents of $20,000/7&lt;br /&gt; = NT$88,661, by Google’s current exchange rate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;= 739 hours of Taiwan’s hourly minimum wage or 4.43 months of Taiwan’s monthly minimum wage&lt;br /&gt; = 317 hours of Massachusetts’s minimum wage (7.94 weeks or 1.85 months assuming a 40-hour work week)&lt;br /&gt; = 1.2~1.7 weeks of &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/tzhongg/status/536565474041937921/photo/1&#34;&gt;a list of high tech internship salaries&lt;/a&gt; as &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slate.com/blogs/moneybox/2014/11/24/tech_internship_salaries_they_will_destroy_your_sense_of_self_worth.html&#34;&gt;featured on Slate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;= 2,955 plates of Sushi Express&lt;br /&gt; = 1,478 cheap boxed lunches (at NT$60 each), which would last one person 1.35 years at 3 per day&lt;br /&gt; = 1,122 &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.economist.com/content/big-mac-index/&#34;&gt;Big Macs&lt;/a&gt;, price in Taiwan, or 596 Big Macs, average price in U.S. (January 2015)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sheep</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/sheep</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2015 22:42:57 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/sheep</guid>
      <description>Ok I give up I don’t have any material and don’t feel like preparing any because the influx of IMO problems, including the shortlist, is too fascinating. Instead, here is a joke quoted verbatim from TVTropes (CC-NC-SA).
 An American anthropologist has been studying a tribe in Africa by living with them for a year. One day, the chief called him into the chief’s hut. The chief sighed. “Well, my friend, it seems that we must ask you to leave.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nuclear II</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/nuclear-ii</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2015 11:40:47 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/nuclear-ii</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/commitment&#34;&gt;streak&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not any better than the &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/nuclear&#34;&gt;first installment&lt;/a&gt;, but I need to post. And then, you know, do homework and presentations and stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Carver had just managed to drill past Dr. Perkins’s cranium when she heard the door behind her creak open.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Ha! You walked right into my trap!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She turned around. Dr. Perkins was standing in the doorway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She looked down. Yes, they were both Dr. Perkins, she’d know that pair of glasses and spiky hair anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She looked up. Well, the guy in the doorway was wearing a set of black robes outside his white lab coat, but other than that, they really looked completely identical.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A List</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/a-list</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 20:56:53 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/a-list</guid>
      <description>(streak)
≥1 of you should know what is being referred to.
  Oh yeah, I love being first. Of course the approximate price is that I have to expose the world to the innocent naïveté of my fourth-grade self. So far nobody mean has ventured there yet, but who knows.   Darn, two years. Darn, Cards Against Humanity. I need more of that in my life. I don’t know what else is happening but music is good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drop-In Filler</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/drop-in</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2015 21:50:05 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/drop-in</guid>
      <description>(streak)
I’ll probably be making filler posts for a while until I make decent progress on linear algebra and programming work, including another presentation.
Let’s listen to some more music.
  This is a Deemo song and even though there are a lot of things I could snark about in the grammar, scansion, and execution of the video (less flashy lyric video here), I kind of want to forgive all that for the (really really dark) poetic image.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>(8,9,7)</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/897</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2015 10:09:29 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/897</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/commitment&#34;&gt;streak&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always tell myself, okay, I will actually just draw something facetiously and get it over with, nobody comes to this blog to admire my GIMP mouse doodles, but then perfectionist tendencies kick in and I get &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/1024&#34;&gt;car&lt;/a&gt;ried away and it ends up taking more than an hour or so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/linear.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/linear.png?w=652&#34; alt=&#34;linear&#34; width=&#34;652&#34; height=&#34;489&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter size-large wp-image-3074&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DOUBLE POST</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/double-post</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 01:05:52 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/double-post</guid>
      <description>20 posts so far in my daily streak, ignoring the time I posted after midnight but including exactly one of this post and the commitment-starting post. You pick which one. The arithmetic works out either way. My last four posts have been made with less than two minutes to spare before midnight, and my last post in particular made it by just seven seconds. This is working as intended in that I’ve knocked out nine drafts that I’m pretty sure would have rotted in my draft folder for at least a few more months otherwise, and I’ve also jotted down more spontaneous thoughts and posted them instead of postponing them until they was too late to be applicable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zzz</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/zzz</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2015 23:58:37 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/zzz</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/commitment&#34;&gt;daily posting streak&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facetious paintbrush dragon filler is best filler!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>index.txt</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/index-txt</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2015 20:52:45 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/index-txt</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My DNSE Story</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/nuclear</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2015 17:12:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/nuclear</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Something something something &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/commitment&#34;&gt;daily posting streak&lt;/a&gt; something something standard disclaimers. My schedule is tighter than usual because IPSC is tonight and runs right up until midnight. Anyway, here’s my logic with posting this: given how long I’ve committed to posting, I’m probably going to have to dig deeply enough into my reserves to include it, and to be authentic I can’t edit the story more anyway, so I might as well do it now. (Also maybe this will pressure me into finishing and posting one of the real short stories in my blog draft folder, the same way I feel pressured to make a good puzzle after posting a bad one.) I’m not even going to reread my story because I don’t like cringing at my own writing without being able to edit it, but hopefully that makes it bad enough to be entertaining. If you didn’t know, this was for an MIT preorientation program application. Tell me if it’s bad to repost application stuff. I hope not.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Oops this introduction is about as long as the actual story now.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol type=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tell us a short story in the available space below. Your inspiration is only one word: nuclear. Go!
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8 Songs for 18 Years</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/8-songs</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2015 13:40:30 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/8-songs</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At some point I thought, hmm, maybe this blog would benefit from some more sentimental, memory-capturing music/videos, like I chose for my &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/time&#34;&gt;end of 2013 post&lt;/a&gt; or my &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/rewind&#34;&gt;end of 2014 post&lt;/a&gt;. (Yeah, I link to my own posts alarmingly often. I think that’s kind of weird. I don’t know.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, because you’re reading this already, I decided to follow through with that idea. There’s no particular significance for posting this now — it’s not my birthday or anything, as the title might suggest; it just has a nice ring to it — except of course that I’m starting to get mildly desperate for content for my &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/commitment&#34;&gt;daily posting streak exercise&lt;/a&gt;. Standard disclaimers apply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is mostly for my future self. I should note that, although I like these songs, this is not a list of my absolute most favorite songs ever. You can tell because there isn’t any Coldplay or fun. (the band.) Instead, each of these songs was chosen to be meaningful to myself and my life in at least two different ways that generally don’t overlap with the other songs. This was difficult but I think I managed it — you know, how constraint breeds creativity and everything? Also, they’re arranged by approximate chronological order of impact. But it also means that this list isn’t going to be that meaningful to anybody other than myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, I have a long list of class-of-2015 sentimental songs, which I’m not including here because I think there are so many that they deserve a separate post. Will I avoid procrastinating and feeling awkward for long enough to make such a post? Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;shrugs&lt;/em&gt; Whatever, enjoy the music or stop reading now if you want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1: Simon &amp;amp; Garfunkel - Scarborough Fair/Canticle&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/-Jj4s9I-53g&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34; title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
  Not only is Scarborough Fair one of my mom’s favorite songs, I’ve bumped into it three entirely separate times while solving puzzles. I always love counterpoint and I find the effect here especially haunting.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rekt</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/rekt</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 00:36:06 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/rekt</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Darn, I only lasted four days. That’s pretty bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I broke like 90% of my HabitRPG streaks too. I was busy running Monte-Carlo calculations to estimate the number of domino logic puzzles, and forgot about midnight. Okay, before that I spent twice as much time on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www1.flightrising.com/&#34;&gt;Flight Rising&lt;/a&gt; for whatever reason. Bad life decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess that means today I have to post one now, before going to sleep, and one later. Eh, time to harvest really weird mini-posts from nowhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ninety-nine (card game)</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/99</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2015 08:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/99</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Frivolous blog content, posted as part of a &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/commitment&#34;&gt;daily posting streak I have openly committed to&lt;/a&gt;; standard disclaimers apply)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is quite interesting that Wikipedia’s article on &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ninety-nine_%28addition_card_game%29&#34;&gt;Ninety-nine (addition card game)&lt;/a&gt;, plus many of the following search results (ignoring the identically-named trick-taking game that is guaranteed to show up), have the same basic idea but wildly differing assignment of special cards from the one I’m familiar with, which everybody I can recall having played with agrees on. (Admittedly I’ve only ever played this among Taiwanese friends.) The only special-card assignment method that came close was a certain person’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://nmnnmnnmmnnnmnrnmnmnnmn.wordpress.com/2012/09/27/concatenation/&#34;&gt;“stuff from my old blog” dumping post&lt;/a&gt; I bumped into very accidentally. (His 5 is our 4; our 5 skips to an arbitrary player. The post also clarifies that negative totals bounce back to zero, and includes a clause whereby players must state the running total after playing and lose if they’re wrong. Interesting.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, yes, I am documenting the rules to a card game on this blog. I think this deserves to exist online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These rules are not completely rigorous because I don’t know them completely rigorously. You can use common sense to reach a consensus in corner cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use a normal deck of playing cards, or two or more identical decks if you want. Deal five cards to each player and set the rest aside to form a draw pile. Cards are played into a discard pile in the center. Players sit in an approximate circle and take turns along the circle, playing one card and then, usually, drawing one replacement card from the draw pile, so in normal 99, hands stay at five cards. When the draw pile runs out, shuffle the discard pile to become the new draw pile.  There is a “running total” in the game, an integer that starts at 0. Normal cards add their value to the running total when played. The total cannot become greater than 99, hence the name. If you have no cards that could keep it less than or equal to 99, you lose. In that case, the turn passes to the next player and the game continues until only one player remains, or until players get bored and decide to play something else.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>