<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Computers on Bounded-Error Log</title>
    <link>//blog.vero.site/tag/computers</link>
    <description>Recent content in Computers on Bounded-Error Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 13:48:45 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//blog.vero.site/tag/computers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>[CIMC 2015 Part 1] Rainy Days in July (and Other Months)</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/cimc-2015-part-1</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 13:48:45 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/cimc-2015-part-1</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We get up at 3:40 AM. By 4 AM we have left our house, speeding like a bullet into the dark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Ohai. Somehow it slipped my mind that I was ending my streak by leaving the country for a competition that would likely be highly bloggable, like my last two international olympiads, both of which led to notable post sequences on this blog. (Admittedly, the first one was never really completed…) My only excuse was that I was worried I might not be able to access my blog from inside the Great Firewall, but I did (via vpn.mit.edu) and even if I hadn’t, I could still have drafted posts locally in Markdown as I usually do, so I don’t know what I was thinking.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Also: because, as I’ve said way too many times recently, I need to do linear algebra homework, these posts aren’t going to be as complete or as perfect as I’d like them to be. Although I’m probably just saying this to persuade myself; I tend to include many of the boring parts as well as the interesting parts of the trip, which maybe benefits my future self at the expense of other readers. I probably need to get out of this habit more if I want to blog for a wider audience, though. Oh well.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;backstory&#34;&gt;
Backstory
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imc-official.org/&#34;&gt;International Mathematics Competition&lt;/a&gt; (IMC) is, &lt;a href=&#34;http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/ExactlyWhatItSaysOnTheTin&#34;&gt;as it says&lt;/a&gt;, an international mathematics competition. But I should add that it is for elementary and middle-school students (in other words, I am not competing, okay??). (edit: Also, one or two letters are often prefixed to indicate the host country, for whatever reason. This year it would be CIMC, C for China.) I am tagging along because I am a student of Dr. Sun, one of the chief organizers, and have been slotted to give a talk and possibly help with grading the papers and translating. My father is coming to help arrange a side event, a &lt;a href=&#34;http://dominosolver.com/&#34;&gt;domino puzzle game&lt;/a&gt; competition, which he programmed the system for; and my mom and sister are also coming to help with translation and other duties. Other people in our group: Dr. Sun himself, his longtime assistant slash fellow teacher Mr. Li (wow I’m sorry I forgot you while first writing this), my friend and fellow math student Hsin-Po, who is an expert at making polyhedra from origami or binder clips (and at Deemo); Chin-Ling, my father’s student/employee who also programmed lots of the domino puzzle server and possesses a professional camera; and, of course, all the elementary- and middle-school contestants, as well as most of their parents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t think I’ve ever given this amount of background exposition about any event I’ve attended to my not-so-imaginary audience before. It feels weird. Some part of me is worried about breaking these people’s privacy by posting this, which makes a little bit of sense but not enough for me to think that it’s actually a valid reason to avoid or procrastinate blogging. I think it’s a rationalization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;day-1&#34;&gt;
Day 1
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only interesting thing that happens at the airport is a short loud argument in the queues for luggage check-in, perhaps partly fueled by our high number of people and of heavy boxes (gifts for other countries and raw materials for Hsin-Po’s polyhedra). I don’t know whose fault it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case I fail to scale the firewall, I attempt to download Facebook on my phone for one last look before boarding, but it fails during installation twice and I give up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our plane is not fancy enough to offer personal screens and entertainment centers for everybody, but thankfully the ride lasts only three hours, so this is tolerable. Instead, the plane plays the second &lt;cite&gt;Divergence&lt;/cite&gt; movie on overhead screens, which I watch half-heartedly. The plot setup seems interesting but the ending seems to me to involve two Ass Pulls™, although since I haven’t been paying much attention I am not confident if I just missed some foreshadowing or character development. On the flight, I also read the proof of the irrationality of powers of &lt;i&gt;e&lt;/i&gt; in &lt;cite&gt;Proofs from THE BOOK&lt;/cite&gt; and leaf through the magazines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t hear any good music on-board, except maybe “Space Oddity”, which is a little freaky to be listening to while cruising at so may kilometers in the sky. Perhaps because of this, I find myself singing and humming “Space Oddity” unexpectedly often over the next few days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;arrival&#34;&gt;
Arrival
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The very first sign we see after alighting the plane consists entirely of characters that are the same in Simplified and Traditional Chinese — if I remember correctly, 「前有坡道，小心慢走」&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The Changchun airport looks like any other airport, coolly blue-themed with moving platforms. The restrooms have fancy bright purple soap. Even though I consciously think about how I have suddenly arrived in a country that places notable restrictions on freedom of speech and Internet access, I don’t feel it. Eep, what an anticlimax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/gravel.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/gravel.jpg?w=652&#34; alt=&#34;[People dragging luggage boxes over gravelly ground outdoors.]&#34; width=&#34;652&#34; height=&#34;369&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter size-large wp-image-3267&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technological Fails Continue</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/technological-fails-continue</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2012 22:11:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/technological-fails-continue</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;warning&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: My 2012 self wrote this. It is preserved for historical interest and amusement, and does not reflect my current beliefs or attitudes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hardware:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The laptop I’m typing this on is over two years old. This is not a lot by some measures, but weird spontaneous glitches are starting to accumulate to the point where they’re getting on my nerves. The internet card still needs an extra reset to start working half the time, and occasionally warrants a full reboot, which costs five minutes. The USB ports are loopy, some windows just show up black when they feel like it, and there’s a steadily climbing whir in the background. I’m kind of anticipating the moment the whole thing just drops dead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I’m not about to run out of computers to use (there’s a noisy XP desktop that also barely works despite handling all our print jobs, but also one spanking new eight-core CPU laptop, which Dad considered a valuable enough investment (?)) but such a loss is still not something to be dismissed lightly. And the externalized cost is far more important and chilling. Who knows how many kids in the Congo had to mine coltan, or how much conflict has occurred over the crude oil, or what awful conditions those sweatshop-assembly workers are going through? Annie Leonard’s words still resonate with me from when we were first shown the video a year ago. Which is more recent than this laptop, so that doesn’t mean that much. I think a couple months ago I would have absolutely no second thoughts about getting a new one, though. Yup, I’m in a quandary (ha ha vocabulary) on the balance between desensitization and compulsive hoarding of stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>