<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mit on Bounded-Error Log</title>
    <link>//blog.vero.site/tag/mit</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mit on Bounded-Error Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2017 14:27:18 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//blog.vero.site/tag/mit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>I guess January is puzzles month</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/january</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2017 14:27:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/january</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;And it’s not even January any more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Thing negative two: Thing zero, which is at the bottom of this post, contains two puzzles by me. Skip there if that sounds interesting and text walls don’t.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thing negative one: I abandoned this blog (again). The last month has been a mess and much of it is political stuff of the sort that I’m the worst/slowest at writing about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thing one: I was on-site for a second MIT Mystery Hunt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music II</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/music-ii</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 15:50:43 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/music-ii</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I first made myself commit to posting weekly, I was trying to make myself spend a little time every day of the week thinking and writing and whittling away at old drafts. Instead I’m here at 10:40 PM basically starting a brand-new post. Oh well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I last &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/music&#34;&gt;blogged about music in 2013&lt;/a&gt;. I tagged two other posts with “music” since then, but neither is particularly deep: &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/8-songs&#34;&gt;8 Songs for 18 Years&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/drop-in&#34;&gt;Drop-In Filler&lt;/a&gt;. Let’s continue the tradition of self-analysis part IIs from nowhere…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I meditated a little bit in &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/conversations&#34;&gt;Conversations&lt;/a&gt; about “lacking experience or interest in a lot of the commonly discussed culture.” I think this applies to me and music as well, although not as fully. Back in Taiwan, when mentally bracing myself for coming to the U.S. for college, I sometimes worried about not knowing enough about pop music and bands and not listening enough to popular albums, and having trouble integrating into the culture for this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turns out, among the communities I wandered into and friends I made, it was a more frequent obstacle that I didn’t know enough about classical music and composers. Whoops. Some of the names rang faint bells from either music class or conversations with high school friends who did do classical music, but I could not identify or remember any styles or eras, and would remember composers only by unreliable first letters or unusual substrings of their names.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brand New</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/brand-new</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 14:26:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/brand-new</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(all the times that you beat me unconscious I forgive)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;angst [&lt;span style=&#34;color:#c00;&#34;&gt;████████&lt;/span&gt;  ] &lt;span style=&#34;color:#c00;&#34;&gt;(8/10)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re overdue for one of these posts, I guess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(all the crimes incomplete – listen, honestly I’ll live)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last-ditch feeble attempts at cleaning and reorganizing my desk and shelf before I figuratively drowned in academics led to me finding&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
the Google physical linked puzzle, which I placed in the Kitchen Lounge to nerd-snipe people, successfully
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
a Burger King crown from the previous career fair
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
ID stickers from the Putnam, one of which is now on my keyboard cover cover (← not a typo), just because
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
assorted edibles, like candies and jellies, which I ate; as well as the half-finished Ziploc bag of candy from my FPOP, six months ago, which I just tossed in the trash
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
a box. It’s just, like, a box. I don’t know what goes or went into it
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel more in control of my living quarters. Marginally. Guess I’ll be fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(mr. cool, mr. right, mr. know-it-all is through)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pros and cons of having a departmental advisor in your area of interest:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Pro: the advisor knows something about the classes you want to take and can help you choose classes
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Con: the advisor knows something about the classes you want to take and can help you choose classes
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>whoosh</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/whoosh</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 08:19:46 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/whoosh</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I finally did it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was on-site for the 2016 MIT Mystery Hunt. I even &lt;em&gt;solved a metapuzzle&lt;/em&gt;. This year I hunted with ✈✈✈ Galactic Trendsetters ✈✈✈, the team primarily but not overwhelmingly formed from floorpi, my dorm floor. (Perhaps somewhat regrettably, I didn’t contribute to any events or runarounds or things given to HQ, unless you count attending a “recitation” for Student Simulator (round King Arthur, second from left).)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Also, I made this post. Has it been two weeks already? Okay, that’s not an unusual timeframe.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But wow, I got to touch so many puzzles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Non-spoilery comments on particularly memorable puzzles I did, which are disproportionately programming-related, if anybody wants to look at them (I am describing how to get to the puzzle from the round instead of linking because I’m lazy and links might rot but the instructions will hopefully survive archival (although turns out there’s actually a &lt;a href=&#34;http://huntception.com/toc.html&#34;&gt;table of contents&lt;/a&gt; so I don’t know what I’m doing)):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2015 MIT Mystery Hunt (spoiler-free version)</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/hunt</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 11:45:50 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/hunt</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, it’s been over a week, which is a long time for blog posts to be delayed after the event they’re documenting in probably all of the world except my blog. So.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess this post should start with a bit of background. I’ve been puzzlehunting for… wow, three and a half years now. I was introduced to puzzlehunts from AoPS, when some fellow members got together a team for &lt;a href=&#34;http://puzzle.cisra.com.au/2011/teamstats_AoPS.html&#34;&gt;CiSRA 2011&lt;/a&gt;, and I think I’ve participated to some degree in every known internet Australian puzzlehunt since.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>