<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MIT on Bounded-Error Log</title>
    <link>//blog.vero.site/tag/mit</link>
    <description>Recent content in MIT on Bounded-Error Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 19:52:19 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//blog.vero.site/tag/mit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2022 MIT Mystery Hunt</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/2022-hunt</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 19:52:19 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/2022-hunt</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sixth year hunting with ✈✈✈ Galactic Trendsetters ✈✈✈! As &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/2021-hunt&#34;&gt;last year’s writing team&lt;/a&gt; &lt;small&gt;(previously: &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/2020-hunt&#34;&gt;2020&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/2019-hunt&#34;&gt;2019&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/2018-hunt&#34;&gt;2018&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/january&#34;&gt;2017&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/whoosh&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt;, writing with Random in &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/hunt&#34;&gt;2015&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/small&gt; we had one final responsibility: running the traditional &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1UNagEB8angIEJa7OqageeXj95UEuspAL0tDwekZJhzQ/edit#slide=id.p&#34;&gt;How to Hunt workshop&lt;/a&gt; shortly before this year’s hunt. I didn’t play a huge role in that, but I lurked and reminded myself some things about how new puzzlehunters think about puzzles, and I wrote &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1-KmLvmcydguI_RBJJqHihbewZmssmdNtlWFJIJZVXLk/edit#gid=0&#34;&gt;Yet Another Puzzlehunt Spreadsheet Tutorial&lt;/a&gt; after casting around and being not entirely satisfied with the puzzlehunting spreadsheet tutorials I found. I think I actually understand ARRAYFORMULA now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then, before we knew it, it was Hunt again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s really nice to get to solve Mystery Hunt again, and especially nice to do so on a team that was fairly actively trying not to win. GT generally tried not to add too many members this year, with some affiliated folks splitting off or hunting with other teams. During the hunt itself, we avoided backsolving puzzles that people were enjoying forward-solving, and encouraged people to be more confident before guessing answers. We ended up with a &amp;gt;50% guess accuracy&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, much higher than some of our past participations, and at least for the puzzles I participated in that took more than a few incorrect answers, I think they were all reasonable guesses or honest mistakes (&lt;span class=&#34;spoiler&#34;&gt;VALLICELLIANA&lt;/span&gt; is difficult to spell) rather than attempts at short-circuiting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, I did the hunt as part of a roughly 10-person west coast contingent who met up in real life (and who all tested negative for COVID shortly before or after arrival). I think I got roughly three times as much sleep as I did during the 2020 hunt, when we won, and I felt freer to hop onto puzzles that were greatly oversaturated with solvers, such as A Number of Games and How to Install a Handle, or to try less hard looking for extraction steps after doing the fun meat of a puzzle. I think a lot of team members took a similar approach; based on our solve log, we solved no metas between 3am and noon (ET) on either day, and generally had much starker dead zones of activity in the mornings than in past years.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021 MIT Mystery Hunt</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/2021-hunt</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 16:07:56 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/2021-hunt</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Note: if you are viewing this shortly after it’s published and somehow don’t want to be spoiled on Mystery Hunt, make sure this spoiler formatting shows up: &lt;span class=&#34;spoiler&#34;&gt;this text should be spoilered&lt;/span&gt;; if it doesn’t, try shift-refreshing. (There are Correct Ways to fix this, but I’m too lazy to do them. Sorry.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, we did it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://perpendicular.institute/&#34;&gt;✈✈✈ Galactic Trendsetters ✈✈✈ ran an MIT Mystery Hunt.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somehow, it slipped my mind until trying to write the 2020 year-end post that I’d probably want to write a post on all this. In fact, there was one major project that I started in 2019, but that I didn’t think of mentioning in my 2019 year-end post because it wasn’t ready to be announced at that time, and that I almost forgot that I had never mentioned. But this post is a pretty good place to announce it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Planning Mystery Hunt is a massive year-long endeavor. I didn’t have any leadership or otherwise high-responsibility roles, which made sense because I was busy writing a masters thesis for the first four months of Mystery Hunt planning. Because of that, and because I know many many other people on our team have written and will be writing blog posts (&lt;a href=&#34;https://fortenf.org/e/2021/01/28/mystery-hunt-2021-part-1.html&#34;&gt;Rahul’s post&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.npinsker.me/puzzles/retrospective&#34;&gt;Nathan’s post&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://mitadmissions.org/blogs/entry/two-hundred-puzzles-2/&#34;&gt;CJ’s post&lt;/a&gt;, maybe more to come?) I will focus on the things I did specifically. (So there is minimal discussion of the theme, overall organization, or big decisions like our COVID-19 response; I think the linked posts cover these well already.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;puzzle-writing-software&#34;&gt;Puzzle-Writing Software&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One part I did largely have “ownership” of, and that I sank a lot of time into, was maintaining our software for writing puzzles — the website where authors submitted puzzle ideas and drafts, testsolvers tested puzzles, and editors tracked and discussed the statuses of all the puzzles. This role was largely a continuation of me owning the same component for Galactic Puzzle Hunt since 2018, which itself grew out of the comparative advantage of having worked on it a little when &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/hunt&#34;&gt;writing with Random Fish for the 2015 MIT Mystery Hunt&lt;/a&gt;. There is some life lesson about specialization or pigeonholing to be learned here. But, to start at the beginning:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mysteryhunt/puzzle-editing/&#34;&gt;Puzzletron&lt;/a&gt; is a piece of PHP software used for organizing puzzle writing for puzzlehunts. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mysteryhunt/puzzle-editing/commit/f67a67d63aa78708c4ca94132f1dce9dbbc116ac&#34;&gt;first commit on GitHub&lt;/a&gt; says it was imported from Metaphysical Plant in 2011; it’s likely older. There are active commits each year until January 2018, and AMA responses from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/mysteryhunt/comments/am5s1d/were_setec_astronomy_and_we_just_ran_a_mystery/efjrzs4/&#34;&gt;Setec (2019)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/mysteryhunt/comments/eucu3x/ama_we_are_left_out_design_team_for_the_2020/ffnzq80/?utm_source=reddit&amp;amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;amp;context=3&#34;&gt;Left Out (2020)&lt;/a&gt; mentioning it, so I believe most if not all Mystery Hunt writing teams used and improved Puzzletron and passed it down over those years.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>45/101</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/45</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 23:06:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/45</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not a very completionist run. I graded myself pretty strictly though — both sides of every “and” need to count; “all” means literally all; fuzzy actions and phrases require full psychological commitment to qualify.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/45.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/45.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&amp;quot;101 Thiings To Do Before You Graduate&amp;quot; poster with 45 things crossed off&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020 MIT Mystery Hunt</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/2020-hunt</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 23:24:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/2020-hunt</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fifth year with ✈✈✈ Galactic Trendsetters ✈✈✈ (previously: &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/2019-hunt&#34;&gt;2019&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/2018-hunt&#34;&gt;2018&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/january&#34;&gt;2017&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/whoosh&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt;; writing with Random in &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/hunt&#34;&gt;2015&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We won!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But apparently I’m still really busy, so I’ll probably just focus on a few highlights of things I personally experienced and get this post out the door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The theme in a few sentences: As suggested by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/mysteryhunt/comments/eo475t/you_are_cordially_invited/&#34;&gt;the invitation&lt;/a&gt; sent out to teams, there was a wedding. It turned out to actually be a real wedding between two prolific puzzle writers on Left Out, the organizing team. To the surprise of everybody who expected either one, three, or maybe five subversions of this announcement, the wedding actually succeeded (a COIN that would prevent all love in the universe was briefly reported missing, but then immediately found by the bride). Instead, we joined the newlyweds on a trip to an amusement park called Penny Park, which we learned was struggling and closing this weekend. It was up to help its regain its popularity and stay open by solving puzzles. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/mysteryhunt/&#34;&gt;Mystery Hunt subreddit&lt;/a&gt; has lots of other cool links and discussions, including this &lt;a href=&#34;https://public.flourish.studio/visualisation/1267425/&#34;&gt;animated bar chart&lt;/a&gt;, so I won’t spend more time here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m pretty sure the best story I personally experienced was how we solved the metameta, the biggest puzzle that stood between us and winning hunt, and the moment at which we went, holy smokes we might have won Mystery Hunt! We got all the pennies required for the final metameta at Sunday 5:48:09am, and it took us until 12:47:30pm, just under &lt;em&gt;seven hours later&lt;/em&gt;, to solve it…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019 MIT Mystery Hunt</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/2019-hunt</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 19:39:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/2019-hunt</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(this post is sketchily backdated from February 2020)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fourth year with ✈✈✈ Galactic Trendsetters ✈✈✈. Past: &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/2018-hunt&#34;&gt;2018&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/january&#34;&gt;2017&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/whoosh&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt;, writing with Random in &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/hunt&#34;&gt;2015&lt;/a&gt;). Evidently I was unable to find the time or motivation to blog about this, and I can’t remember any particularly good stories, so let me just slip this backdated list post in the archives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The theme in a few sentences: The hunt organizers declare a new Molasses Awareness Day, but because they didn’t follow the proper procedure, throwing the world of Holidays into chaos, where “chaos” means molasses. This resulted in lots of puzzle-to-meta matching, since puzzles were in Holiday towns but metas were at lampposts between two towns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Highlights of puzzles I solved:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Good Walk Spoiled&lt;/strong&gt; (Holi): Happens to be about a topic I know well and find interesting. Fun steps. Justified use of substitution ciphers; the pasting into quipqiup was worth it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;State Machine&lt;/strong&gt; (President’s): A one-aha! one-step puzzle. Maybe more unfortunate because apparently this was not the only puzzle to use a specific aspect of a specific source material, but I didn’t know about that other puzzle so it’s fine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clued Connections&lt;/strong&gt; (Pi): I went to sleep near the end of this puzzle, so I didn’t see it through, but Floorpi was collectively called out by it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I Can’t Deal with These Endless Numbers&lt;/strong&gt; (Patriot’s): Incredible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loaded&lt;/strong&gt; (Arbor): Simple and self-contained enough.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018 MIT Mystery Hunt</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/2018-hunt</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 19:39:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/2018-hunt</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My third MIT Mystery Hunt with ✈✈✈ Galactic Trendsetters ✈✈✈ (also see: &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/january&#34;&gt;2017&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/whoosh&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt;, writing with Random in &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/hunt&#34;&gt;2015&lt;/a&gt;). It was a good hunt with a fun theme, solid puzzles, and extraordinary production quality, marred only by a fickle unlock structure and a handful of unnecessarily involved extractions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we had been told the hunt would be smaller than past years’ (now a controversial statement since the coin was &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; found particularly early) and we didn’t particularly want to win (yet), part of our team temporarily split off this year to hunt as Teammate. Based on our Discord channel, ✈✈✈ Galactic Trendsetters ✈✈✈ had 75 people this year, including remote solvers and people who dropped in and out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A short description of the hunt structure: This year’s hunt theme was &lt;em&gt;Inside Out&lt;/em&gt;, the Disney movie about anthropomorphized emotions. This was revealed through a kickoff that demonstrated the hunt’s extraordinary production quality, in which we watched the unveiling of the Health &amp;amp; Safety hunt, first directly, then in the Control Room with the emotions of a distraught hunter (Miss Terry Hunter) and a lot of beautiful memory orbs and scenery. After Terry’s emotions became overwhelmed in response to the theme, we had to help her emotions to allow her to complete the Health &amp;amp; Safety hunt. The intro round took place in the Control Room; we had to solve 34 regular puzzles and five metapuzzles (somewhat overlapping, with some regular puzzles belonging to more than one metapuzzle) to help each of the five emotions get back to the Control Room. The rest of the hunt consisted of recovering memory orbs from each of four Islands of Personality, each of which had its own theme and meta structure, and which we could choose the unlock order of.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I guess January is puzzles month</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/january</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2017 14:27:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/january</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;And it’s not even January any more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Thing negative two: Thing zero, which is at the bottom of this post, contains two puzzles by me. Skip there if that sounds interesting and text walls don’t.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thing negative one: I abandoned this blog (again). The last month has been a mess and much of it is political stuff of the sort that I’m the worst/slowest at writing about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thing one: I was on-site for a second MIT Mystery Hunt.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music II</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/music-ii</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 15:50:43 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/music-ii</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I first made myself commit to posting weekly, I was trying to make myself spend a little time every day of the week thinking and writing and whittling away at old drafts. Instead I’m here at 10:40 PM basically starting a brand-new post. Oh well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I last &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/music&#34;&gt;blogged about music in 2013&lt;/a&gt;. I tagged two other posts with “music” since then, but neither is particularly deep: &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/8-songs&#34;&gt;8 Songs for 18 Years&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/drop-in&#34;&gt;Drop-In Filler&lt;/a&gt;. Let’s continue the tradition of self-analysis part IIs from nowhere…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I meditated a little bit in &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/conversations&#34;&gt;Conversations&lt;/a&gt; about “lacking experience or interest in a lot of the commonly discussed culture.” I think this applies to me and music as well, although not as fully. Back in Taiwan, when mentally bracing myself for coming to the U.S. for college, I sometimes worried about not knowing enough about pop music and bands and not listening enough to popular albums, and having trouble integrating into the culture for this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turns out, among the communities I wandered into and friends I made, it was a more frequent obstacle that I didn’t know enough about classical music and composers. Whoops. Some of the names rang faint bells from either music class or conversations with high school friends who did do classical music, but I could not identify or remember any styles or eras, and would remember composers only by unreliable first letters or unusual substrings of their names.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brand New</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/brand-new</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 14:26:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/brand-new</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(all the times that you beat me unconscious I forgive)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;angst [&lt;span style=&#34;color:#c00;&#34;&gt;████████&lt;/span&gt;  ] &lt;span style=&#34;color:#c00;&#34;&gt;(8/10)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re overdue for one of these posts, I guess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(all the crimes incomplete – listen, honestly I’ll live)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last-ditch feeble attempts at cleaning and reorganizing my desk and shelf before I figuratively drowned in academics led to me finding&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
the Google physical linked puzzle, which I placed in the Kitchen Lounge to nerd-snipe people, successfully
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
a Burger King crown from the previous career fair
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
ID stickers from the Putnam, one of which is now on my keyboard cover cover (← not a typo), just because
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
assorted edibles, like candies and jellies, which I ate; as well as the half-finished Ziploc bag of candy from my FPOP, six months ago, which I just tossed in the trash
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
a box. It’s just, like, a box. I don’t know what goes or went into it
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel more in control of my living quarters. Marginally. Guess I’ll be fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(mr. cool, mr. right, mr. know-it-all is through)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pros and cons of having a departmental advisor in your area of interest:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Pro: the advisor knows something about the classes you want to take and can help you choose classes
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Con: the advisor knows something about the classes you want to take and can help you choose classes
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>whoosh</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/whoosh</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 08:19:46 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/whoosh</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I finally did it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was on-site for the 2016 MIT Mystery Hunt. I even &lt;em&gt;solved a metapuzzle&lt;/em&gt;. This year I hunted with ✈✈✈ Galactic Trendsetters ✈✈✈, the team primarily but not overwhelmingly formed from floorpi, my dorm floor. (Perhaps somewhat regrettably, I didn’t contribute to any events or runarounds or things given to HQ, unless you count attending a “recitation” for Student Simulator (round King Arthur, second from left).)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Also, I made this post. Has it been two weeks already? Okay, that’s not an unusual timeframe.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But wow, I got to touch so many puzzles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Non-spoilery comments on particularly memorable puzzles I did, which are disproportionately programming-related, if anybody wants to look at them (I am describing how to get to the puzzle from the round instead of linking because I’m lazy and links might rot but the instructions will hopefully survive archival (although turns out there’s actually a &lt;a href=&#34;http://huntception.com/toc.html&#34;&gt;table of contents&lt;/a&gt; so I don’t know what I’m doing)):&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 49 / Triple Back</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-49</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2015 00:25:46 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-49</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m not really satisfied with the execution, but eh, what the hell. My brain can only function at so much of its full capacity when it’s a few kilometers up in the sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://mellowmelon.wordpress.com/2009/12/20/puzzle-135/&#34;&gt;Triple Back&lt;/a&gt;, variant on &lt;a href=&#34;https://mellowmelon.wordpress.com/double-back/&#34;&gt;MellowMelon’s Double Back&lt;/a&gt;. Briefly, draw a closed loop through all square centers visiting each bold-outlined area exactly three (= ⌊π⌋) times. Shaded cells do not influence solving, only aesthetics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pause</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/pause</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2015 16:03:56 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/pause</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are 30 minutes until my laundry finishes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is 2:30 in the morning as I write this. Normal people are not awake at this time of day. It’s possible that normal MIT students are, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been meaning to blog for a while, but things happen and other things happen and still more things happen. From a state of total inexperience in the kitchen, I’ve already managed to single-handedly cook six six-person meals for my co-op, not to mention all the weird meals I make for myself (which is just as well, I don’t think they are of typically mentionable caliber.) I’ve already taken two exams in three of my classes and the big midterm for my fourth. Four puzzlehunts — Simmons, aquarium, Palantir, ΣUMS; five if you perhaps include Next Haunt. Six SIPB meetings. A few bottles of Soylent; I lost count and don’t want to check my room because that’ll disturb my roommate. Θ(3000) zephyrs. And after many weekends of eye-opening group practice, tonight I have to catch a flight to Rochester, NY for ACM-ICPC regionals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sharpies</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/sharpies</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2015 14:59:48 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/sharpies</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As readers of this blog probably know, I am not an MITAdmissions blogger. It was kind of disappointing at the moment, but now I rarely think about it except when I come up with good reasons why I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be an MITAdmissions blogger. One reason is that I am not very good at coming up with advice that could generalize to a wide audience, even an audience only as wide as people at or coming to the &amp;lsquo;Tvte. &lt;em&gt;(There can be only one!)&lt;/em&gt; This by itself probably wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be so bad because there&amp;rsquo;s plenty of generalizable advice to go around, but I also don&amp;rsquo;t like repeating well-known stuff. Don&amp;rsquo;t skip class, except when you really know when you&amp;rsquo;re doing, which you probably think you do when you skip class. Get enough sleep, maintain good study habits, set aside time to keep up with old friends, back up your zarking data, alternate alcoholic and nonalcoholic drinks, do not forget the factor of one-half when computing the area of a triangle. You get the picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s only one piece of advice I can say that I believe is generalizable to any degree, and in particular I think my past self would have appreciated and also had not heard, even in passing, from any other source: Get a Sharpie.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 48 / Double Back</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-48</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2015 23:15:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-48</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At least one person wants me to post. I’m not even going to try do a life summary. It’s too hard. Let’s just say:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
right now, my blog drafts contain a backlog of ~7500 words and counting;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
I was not accepted as an MIT Admissions blogger, which is bad because my blogging will continue to not reach a large audience, but good because my blogging will continue to not reach a large audience. Maybe it had something to do with the fact that, because the application form wouldn’t let me submit without any media, I panickedly cranked out the following puzzle in an hour or so to attach.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MIT Course Number Mnemonics</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/mit-mnemonics</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2015 23:45:41 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/mit-mnemonics</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I first realized it might be helpful to start trying to remember the correspondence between MIT courses and their numbers, I expected a list of mnemonics for this correspondence would be one of those Things That Should Exist On the Internet. I’m pretty surprised it doesn’t. I mean, MIT has, what, &lt;a href=&#34;http://web.mit.edu/facts/alum-association.html&#34;&gt;at least 100,000 alumni&lt;/a&gt;; as far as I know, nearly everybody who goes there speaks the number correspondence fluently, so they have to learn it; and the science of mnemonics has been with us since the ancient Greeks and people who understand its usefulness can’t be uncommon, especially not in such a prestigious institute of higher education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What gives?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure. Maybe it’s just that nobody has posted their mnemonic set on the Internet out of embarrassment? My mnemonics are pretty bad too, but hey, &lt;a href=&#34;https://meta.wikimedia.org/wiki/Cunningham%27s_Law&#34;&gt;Cunningham’s Law&lt;/a&gt; — if you’re reading, feel free to add better ones in the comments, or to criticize my horribly unenlightened and stereotypical characterizations of your courses, to make this thing better. Or maybe it’s out of concern that nobody else will find it useful? I get that feeling but my &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/commitment&#34;&gt;streak&lt;/a&gt; compels me to ignore it now, as it has for the last dozen posts or so. Or maybe they just didn’t optimize for search engine findability, so I can’t find it? I hope this post fixes that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually, I guess the most likely reason is that maybe most people don’t actually have &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; the course numbers memorized with perfect recall, only the handful of most common ones they and their friends are in, and it’s perfectly fine to ask for clarification when an unknown number comes up in conversation, so nobody ever feels like they need to bother with mnemonics for every single course. Feels sensible to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But anyway, I’m not most people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most comprehensive resource of courses and numbers, including their history, appears to have once been at &lt;code&gt;http://alumweb.mit.edu/clubs/sandiego/contents_courses.shtml&lt;/code&gt;. Many, many links point there. Unfortunately, it is dead and I cannot find its new home, if it has one. Fortunately, there is an &lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.is/xViRP&#34;&gt;archived version on archive.is&lt;/a&gt;; on the other hand, I am not sure whether any updates have occurred since it was archived. A more recent version with course populations from 2005 is &lt;a href=&#34;http://web.mit.edu/mollieb/www/blog/MIT%20course%20numbers.html&#34;&gt;this chart&lt;/a&gt; linked from the MIT Admissions blog post &lt;a href=&#34;http://mitadmissions.org/blogs/entry/numbers_are_names_too&#34;&gt;Numbers are names too&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2015 MIT Mystery Hunt</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/hunt</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 11:45:50 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/hunt</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, it’s been over a week, which is a long time for blog posts to be delayed after the event they’re documenting in probably all of the world except my blog. So.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess this post should start with a bit of background. I’ve been puzzlehunting for… wow, three and a half years now. I was introduced to puzzlehunts from AoPS, when some fellow members got together a team for &lt;a href=&#34;http://puzzle.cisra.com.au/2011/teamstats_AoPS.html&#34;&gt;CiSRA 2011&lt;/a&gt;, and I think I’ve participated to some degree in every known internet Australian puzzlehunt since.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But as for my experience with the MIT Mystery Hunt in particular, I sort of hunted with a decidedly uncompetitive AoPS team in 2012 (I think we solved one puzzle exactly), but my serious hunting career began when dzaefn recruited me into the Random team (then Random Thymes) &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/hunter&#34;&gt;for the 2013 hunt&lt;/a&gt; (and I did blog obliquely about it). We didn’t win (and I actually didn’t participate that much because I was traveling with family) but the next year (as One Fish Two Fish Random Fish Blue Fish (1f-2f-17f-255f (I am evidently in a parentheses mood today because as you’ve probably noticed, the amount and depth of parentheses in this sentence are positively alarming (lol)))) we won.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I do have a half-written post about that which will never get posted (and I &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; didn’t participate that much, because my family was moving that weekend) but okay, let’s just drop any semblance of chronological coherence on this blog and dump a short version of the list of puzzles and parts towards which I contributed solving, as I wrote them down one year ago:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
