<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Brian_2012 on Bounded-Error Log</title>
    <link>//blog.vero.site/tag/brian_2012</link>
    <description>Recent content in Brian_2012 on Bounded-Error Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 16:55:32 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//blog.vero.site/tag/brian_2012/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Gaming</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/gaming</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 16:55:32 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/gaming</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s another weekend, isn’t it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m out of deep things to say. I don’t usually have deep things to say. Sorry to anybody who subscribed hoping for more things like the last post. This is basically going to be a personal stream of consciousness post. But it’s a stream with a long ancestry, since I apparently wrote 400 words about it in a WordPress draft four years ago. This was way back before I even started writing post drafts in Markdown on my computer instead of directly in WordPress, so I guess it must be an interesting topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Four years ago, Brian&lt;sub&gt;2012&lt;/sub&gt; was suddenly struck by how many of the people he knew were such serious gamers. But let’s go back even earlier, shall we?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A long long time ago, when I was in elementary school or so, my parents had some sort of reward system where I had to do productive things, like study or do chores or write diary entries or practice the piano or something, to earn time on the computer for games. “Gaming time” was a currency. I enjoyed saving up lots of thirty-minute increments and knowing I had the freedom to using them slowly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That much I remember; the details of how it worked are very fuzzy and I’m not sure what I played in those thirty-minute increments either. I think there was Neopets and Runescape and Club Penguin. (My Neopets account still sees sporadic activity, because I get really really bored sometimes…)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;I reached the highest bank account level today (after almost exactly 12 years, apparently) &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/Jb9zyWcjRw&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/Jb9zyWcjRw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Brian Chen (@betaveros) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/betaveros/status/749362619044077568?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;July 2, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>