<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Akrasia on Bounded-Error Log</title>
    <link>//blog.vero.site/tag/akrasia</link>
    <description>Recent content in Akrasia on Bounded-Error Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2014 22:34:59 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//blog.vero.site/tag/akrasia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>[IOI 2014 Part -1] Prelude.hs</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/prelude</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2014 22:34:59 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/prelude</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Indexing debates are boring. Especially when you can just flagrantly disregard all concerns about memory safety (because C++ never had any in the first place) and write &lt;code&gt;int _array[100008], array = _array + 2;&lt;/code&gt; I do this alarmingly often; hence, the title. Hashtag firstworldanarchists. Three ± 1 cheers for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.haskell.org/ghc/docs/7.6-latest/html/libraries/array-0.4.0.1/Data-Array.html#v:array&#34;&gt;Haskell arrays&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway. One of the disadvantages of entering an international competition as the home team is a lack of time to completely absorb the idea that what is about to happen is a Big Thing. There was lots of time before the other international competitions I went to to spend uncomfortably on airplanes trying to adjust for the timezone difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not so for a competition in one’s own country. Right up to the night before entering the hotel that marks the beginning of everything, I’m still at home, furiously refreshing the AoPS IMO fora and Facebook for news (!!!), lazily solving trivial Codeforces Div II problems with &lt;del&gt;pointless&lt;/del&gt; point-free Haskell one-liners, and blogging. (There’s more, but I kind of want it to be a surprise.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, let’s set the rules. Well, there’s only one, honestly:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>