<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Command Line on Bounded-Error Log</title>
    <link>//blog.vero.site/tag/command-line</link>
    <description>Recent content in Command Line on Bounded-Error Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2013 18:33:17 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//blog.vero.site/tag/command-line/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sands of Time</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/time</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2013 18:33:17 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/time</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Random video! Although I feel that I’ve heard it earlier, my first conscious memory of getting linked to it is from &lt;a href=&#34;http://usamoarchive.wordpress.com/2012/03/01/youre-older-than-youve-ever-been/&#34;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt;. At first I thought it would be the right background music for this post, but upon further reflection I think it mainly suited me while I was writing this post. Well, it’s topical if you mentally replace “day” with “year”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/q2bo_u_YmW8&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34; title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway. Around this time a year ago, I paused my participation in big high-school competitions, for a variety of reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, I stopped attempting to make IMO both because I wouldn’t get that much from the training and because other people ought to have the opportunity. I was concerned that I might condition myself to only be able to do math with the short-term motivation of contests. Better to focus on college math and maybe some original research, I thought. During the year, I did lots of the former and very little of the latter. Meh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the IOI, my obvious next target: I was tired of training and going abroad while paranoid about whether my immune system would hold up. I didn’t feel that the IOI was worth that. To some degree, I also felt burned out about programming. Long story short, my treatment should end soon, and learning Haskell completely resolved the burnout problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the most important reason, I think, was that “high school was too short”. I started math competitions ridiculously early and didn’t spend much time exploring other interests. I thought I knew myself well enough that I could say I didn’t have many more interests at all, but I was completely wrong (psych nerds will reflexively note this to be the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dunning%E2%80%93Kruger_effect&#34;&gt;Dunning-Kruger effect&lt;/a&gt;). I coded lots in weird languages — Haskell, as mentioned previously, plus Scala, plus all manner of other magical command line tools. I wrote my first math problem and submitted it officially, picked up a new instrument, went to a debate competition, served as an unimportant tech guy for MUN, discovered and became hooked on Pentatonix, participated in three puzzle hunts in Australia and one in Massachusetts, figured out my rough political stance, rode a boat, got retweeted by &lt;span class=&#34;citation&#34; data-cites=&#34;eevee&#34;&gt;@eevee&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class=&#34;citation&#34; data-cites=&#34;Kyrgyzstan_News&#34;&gt;@Kyrgyzstan_News&lt;/span&gt;, increased my Neopets™ fortune by over 3400%, and lurked on FurAffinity a little too much.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>