<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>knowledge on Bounded-Error Log</title>
    <link>//blog.vero.site/tag/knowledge</link>
    <description>Recent content in knowledge on Bounded-Error Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2012 13:34:15 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//blog.vero.site/tag/knowledge/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>On writing</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/on-writing</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2012 13:34:15 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/on-writing</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;warning&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: My 2012 self wrote this. It’s a bit dated, but it’s okay, and also is of historical interest for featuring me explaining the CSS I learned from English class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every time I notice that I have hoarded a large number of strange assignments and essays from another school year of work I get all guilty. First there’s the knowledge about ancient Chinese dynasties and plant hormones that I only have shadows of recollections of, which makes me wonder whether all the time and effort invested by teachers, classmates, and myself have gone wasted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know, though, that given that I still sense these shadows, it shouldn’t be difficult to look up and relearn this stuff if I ever need to do so. This brings me to the non-factual parts of the learning, such as writing skills with all its variations. There’s persuasive writing, which I don’t use much because I can’t usually even persuade myself to take a side in anything, let alone others. There’s descriptive writing mode, which I don’t use much because the most vividly describable things I encounter are food, and the shallowness of piling flowery adjectives together to talk about food just makes me cringe nowadays. Previously, I wrote at least two such compositions in sixth grade. Blech.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>