<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>conversations on Bounded-Error Log</title>
    <link>//blog.vero.site/tag/conversations</link>
    <description>Recent content in conversations on Bounded-Error Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 13:10:21 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//blog.vero.site/tag/conversations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Conversations</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/conversations</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 13:10:21 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/conversations</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the most unexpectedly different facets of life during my internship has been the meals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not talking about the food; it’s certainly different in a fantastic way (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/DropboxTuckShop/?fref=ts&#34;&gt;Dropbox’s food (link to Facebook page)&lt;/a&gt; is like something out of a high-end restaurant), but I knew that before coming already. Also of note is the way I started eating ∞% more ramen over the weekends than I did over the entire school year at MIT, because here I can’t buy that many groceries without them spoiling and am amazingly lazy in this new environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, this (deadlined, so not that well-thought-out, but whatever) post is about conversations at meals, which happen basically every lunch and some dinners when my team eats together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve never had any regular experience like it. Of course I’ve had many meals at home with family, but they feel different because, well, it’s family and we have so many topics in common. I went to the same school for twelve years and we didn’t generally use a cafeteria; we just ate at our desks in our classrooms, or while doing things like attending club meetings or taking makeup tests. Sometimes if people felt like it they would push desks together to eat, but eating by oneself was totally normal. (At last, I feel like that was what it was. It seems so far away now that I don’t trust my memory, which is pretty sad… I faintly suspect I would have this experience in a more stereotypical American high school. But this is mostly just based off the cafeteria in &lt;cite&gt;Mean Girls&lt;/cite&gt;, a movie I only watched in its entirety on the flight here, which is weird because I know I’ve seen the “The limit does not exist!” part much much earlier. /aside)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And at MIT? “Time is an illusion. Lunchtime doubly so.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am glad for these conversations over lunch because I get to know my team more personally (and don’t have to awkwardly eat alone in the bathroom), but they’ve also given me a lot of time to ponder my (lack of) conversation skills.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
