<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Speeches on Bounded-Error Log</title>
    <link>//blog.vero.site/tag/speeches</link>
    <description>Recent content in Speeches on Bounded-Error Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2014 13:04:16 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//blog.vero.site/tag/speeches/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>[IOI 2014 Part 4] Shades of Xanthous</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/xanthous</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2014 13:04:16 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/xanthous</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;No, I didn’t forget. Not for one minute. I was doing homework. I am very happy because that means I was actually carrying out my priorities as I envisioned them. I’ve probably edited this post too many times, though. Meh. But it’s the first weekend after finishing summer homework, so here we go again!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fun fact: This is by far my favorite post title in the entire series. Possibly in the entire history of this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the morning of the last day of official IOI activities, there were a bunch of cultural activities, e.g. writing Chinese characters calligraphically, doing tricks with the diabolo, or picking up beans with chopsticks, and noncultural activities, e.g. getting somebody to pour water into a cup on your head while he or she was blindfolded. Due to the last activity I got wet, but my shirt dried really quickly. And alas, even though I had taken calligraphy summer classes a long time ago, my calligraphy was awful — robotic, lifeless strokes without the right aesthetic proportions to make up for it. Blargh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, lunch followed, and then it was time for the closing ceremony, in the same building as the other ceremonies and contests. Our team caught the ending song of in a Chinese musical being rehearsed as we walked into the auditorium. While we waited for everybody, we milled about waving flags that our various teachers had brought, including not only Taiwan’s flag but also flags of my school, thoughtfully brought by teachers who had volunteered. A little later our leader told us that all the leaders had discussed the matter during a meeting and decided that we shouldn’t bring any flags to the stage while receiving our medals, so we were going to have to make do with being patriotic and school-respecting off stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were a few performances, including two aboriginal music performances and the musical we had seen rehearsed ealier, which was a fun rock musical rendition of some Chinese tale that seemed to have been sharply abridged, giving it the plot depth of a Wikipedia stub-article synopsis — a conflict, boy-meets-girl-and-falls-in-love, and a lamenting Aesop song conclusion with thrillingly vague general applicability. But the singing and counterpointing and atmosphere were good. I guess it was proportional to the relative importance of the performance to the closing ceremony. The program interleaved them with the long-awaited medal presentations: one round of bronze medalists, one round of silver, one round of gold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dum-dum-dum-dum, medals! The home team advantage was really obvious here; the cheering and the medal-presenter handshakes were both significantly more forceful for Taiwan’s medalists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/gold.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/gold.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;I think our leader made this. Thanks.&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
I think our leader made this. Thanks.
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[IOI 2014 Part 1] Everything is More Exciting with Lightsabers</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/lightsabers</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2014 17:31:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/lightsabers</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Okay, I guess it was really naïve of me to suppose that I could get any considerable amount of blogging done before the IOI ended. Onward…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We left off at the end of the practice session. As if somebody were taking revenge against us for not having to suffer through any airplane trips, we were served a cold airplane meal for lunch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seriously, the box had a sticker that noted its manufacturer as something something Air Kitchen and another translucent sticker that badly covered an inscription saying the same thing in much bigger letters. It contained a cold apple salad, a cold chicken bun, a cold flat plastic cylinder of orange juice, and a package of plastic utensils that was exactly like the utensils that came with every airplane meal ever. I was disappointed, but at least the salad tasted okay, and I ate an extra one because two of my teammates volunteered theirs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To pass the time, we played an extra-evil &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ninety-nine_(addition_card_game)&#34;&gt;ninety-nine&lt;/a&gt; variant. Apparently this is a very Taiwanese game because lots of student guides were teaching their teams the game, although our special cards differ from the ones Wikipedia lists in a lot of ways and our evil variant created more opportunity for sabotage and counter-sabotage and bluffing. 7s are used to draw your replacement card from somebody else’s hand, and that person cannot draw again and will have one less card; aces are used to swap your entire hand with somebody else, who also cannot draw a card; small-value cards can be combined to form special values (e.g. play a 2 and 5 for the effect of a 7) but after playing a combination you can only draw one replacement card; and later, to speed up the game, we added a rule where all 9s had to be unconditionally discarded without replacement but would still get shuffled back into the draw pile. Players lose if it’s their turn and they have no playable cards, including no cards at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we were playing and repeatedly reveling in everybody ganging up to beat the winner from the last round, an instrumental version of “You Are My Sunshine” played on repeat in the background for literally the entire time. It wasn’t a very good version either. If you didn’t listen carefully for the fade-out and few seconds of silence at the end of each loop, you’d think that the loop was only one verse long.  After the miserable excuse for lunch, we entered the place the opening ceremony, and an orchestra played a few songs that I can finally hope gave the contestants a feeling of Taiwanese culture. I recognized &lt;a href=&#34;https://zh.wikipedia.org/zh-tw/%E6%9C%9B%E6%98%A5%E9%A2%A8&#34;&gt;「望春風」&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>