<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>politics on Bounded-Error Log</title>
    <link>//blog.vero.site/tag/politics</link>
    <description>Recent content in politics on Bounded-Error Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 12:26:52 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//blog.vero.site/tag/politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s Complicated</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/complicated</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 12:26:52 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/complicated</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On November 8th, 2016, Donald Trump was elected the 45th President of the United States. Along with a Republican House and Senate majority, to boot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world around me is still hurting and reeling from the shock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make no mistake, I am scared. I am scared of the policies and executive orders and legal decisions to come that may strip away many civil rights and send the environment down a worse track faster than anyone expected, and I’m barely in any of the groups that have the most to lose. I have no idea what it’s like to go through this as any of you. I am sorry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I am also scared that this fear is driving my friends and my community away from talking to the people we need to talk to if we want to make sure this doesn’t happen again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve heard a lot of people vilify Trump and Trump supporters. &lt;a href=&#34;https://nmnnmnnmmnnnmnrnmnmnnmn.wordpress.com/2016/11/09/1067/&#34;&gt;Anecdotally, so have others&lt;/a&gt;. It’s an understandable reaction, but a fragile one. 60 million people voted for Trump. &lt;a href=&#34;http://waitbutwhy.com/2016/11/its-going-to-be-okay.html&#34;&gt;Quoting &lt;em&gt;Wait But Why&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, “[P]eople with kids and parents and jobs and dogs and calendars on their wall with piano lessons and doctors appointments and birthday parties written in the squares. Full, three-dimensional people who voted for what they hope will be a better future for themselves and their family.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People voted for Trump. Why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://fivethirtyeight.com/features/trumps-base-is-blue-collar-his-voters-looking-for-a-return-to-better-times/&#34;&gt;FiveThirtyEight profiling a few blue-collar voters&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/wonk/wp/2016/11/08/a-new-theory-for-why-trump-voters-are-so-angry-that-actually-makes-sense/&#34;&gt;The Washington Post interviewing an author who spent a lot of time in rural Wisconsin&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2016/11/11/us/politics/the-women-who-helped-donald-trump-to-victory.html?smid=fb-nytimes&amp;amp;smtyp=cur&#34;&gt;The New York Times on women&lt;/a&gt;. If the articles’ reasons for voting Trump could be summarized in one word, it would certainly be “economy”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then FiveThirtyEight tempers it a little bit with this reminder that &lt;a href=&#34;http://fivethirtyeight.com/features/the-mythology-of-trumps-working-class-support/&#34;&gt;Trump’s supporters are on average more well-off than others&lt;/a&gt;. Here’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2016/07/11/george-saunders-goes-to-trump-rallies&#34;&gt;The New Yorker visiting a bunch of Trump rallies&lt;/a&gt;. SupChina discusses &lt;a href=&#34;http://supchina.com/2016/11/03/many-first-generation-chinese-immigrants-supporting-donald-trump/&#34;&gt;first-generation Chinese immigrants supporting Trump&lt;/a&gt; and racism is a bullet point there, but apparently it’s partly rallied around rap lyrics about robbery that advise to “find a Chinese neighborhood” to steal from, so…? I am not going to go any deeper into this rabbit hole. Then here’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.motherjones.com/kevin-drum/2016/03/trump-voters-are-not-angry-about-economy-really&#34;&gt;Mother Jones arguing against the economy being a big factor at all&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2016/10/15/13286498/donald-trump-voters-race-economic-anxiety&#34;&gt;Vox saying it &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; about racial resentment&lt;/a&gt;. Here’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bloomberg.com/view/articles/2016-11-11/revenge-of-the-deplorables&#34;&gt;Bloomberg on the Clinton campaign’s failure to persuade&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://thefederalist.com/2016/11/11/how-jon-stewart-and-the-daily-show-elected-donald-trump/&#34;&gt;The Federalist on “hyper-liberal late-night comedy”&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.washingtontimes.com/news/2016/nov/9/donald-trump-and-the-new-american-revolution/&#34;&gt;The Washington Times on Trump’s optimism&lt;/a&gt;. I could find hundreds more out there just by Googling, and so could you; and chances are if you’re enough of a voracious reader to be reading my humble blog, you’ve already read some of these.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s complicated.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>