<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>airports on Bounded-Error Log</title>
    <link>//blog.vero.site/tag/airports</link>
    <description>Recent content in airports on Bounded-Error Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2012 07:44:51 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//blog.vero.site/tag/airports/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>[IMO 2012 Part 1] Dangerous Metal Chopsticks</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/metal-chopsticks</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2012 07:44:51 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/metal-chopsticks</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s time to begin the epic blogging journey. The detailed version of this year’s amazing IMO, because I decided that a perfectionist guy like myself could not possibly liveblog and be satisfied with both the quality of the posts and being able to fully enjoy the actual event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our story begins in a hotel in Taiwan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The night before departure, us six contestants and Prof. Lin gathered in a hotel. This was entirely necessary because our flight left at something like five o’clock in the morning. After checking over the flight plans and relevant phone numbers in a conference room, we enjoyed a pretty extensive buffet dinner, what would easily be the best meal we would get to have for at least a week, the highlight of which was a fish steak that looked and tasted exactly like fried egg. Afterwards we did some emergency shopping and prepared a convenience-store breakfast for consumption three o’clock the next day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I’ve complained before, we have an 11-hour difference to get used to, and that morning I had gotten myself to sleep as late as 6 AM trying (successfully, much to my amazement) to complete an iPod OS system update. I didn’t think I could pass airport security with the sort of consciousness I had when I finally slept that morning, so I reverted with the rest of the team to an 11 PM curfew. Oh well. The seven of us left the hotel after 3 AM, setting off in a huge 30-person bus for the airport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luggage drop-off was mostly uneventful. I realized that the airline didn’t seem to like passengers bringing two bags onto the airplane, and decided to distribute my bag with all the winter clothes in it into my luggage and my backpack. Little did we know what would happen to the luggage…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>