<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Competitions on Bounded-Error Log</title>
    <link>//blog.vero.site/tag/competitions</link>
    <description>Recent content in Competitions on Bounded-Error Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2014 16:01:28 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//blog.vero.site/tag/competitions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>[IOI 2014 Outtakes]</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/outtakes</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2014 16:01:28 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/outtakes</guid>
      <description>Miscellaneous observations that didn’t make it into a compelling narrative, sometimes because I have forgotten exactly when they happened, sometimes because I only remembered when they happened after blogging about it, sometimes because it just seemed too tangential, sometimes just because of the circumference of the mooooooooooooooooon! (That made no sense and I’m not going to remember what I’m alluding to in a few months.)   During the first day a guy came into the secret computer room that the Taiwan team had concealed themselves in, saw us watching anime (SAO 2 among others), and innocently asked, “Are you the Japanese team?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[IOI 2014 Part 4] Shades of Xanthous</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/xanthous</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2014 13:04:16 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/xanthous</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;No, I didn’t forget. Not for one minute. I was doing homework. I am very happy because that means I was actually carrying out my priorities as I envisioned them. I’ve probably edited this post too many times, though. Meh. But it’s the first weekend after finishing summer homework, so here we go again!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fun fact: This is by far my favorite post title in the entire series. Possibly in the entire history of this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the morning of the last day of official IOI activities, there were a bunch of cultural activities, e.g. writing Chinese characters calligraphically, doing tricks with the diabolo, or picking up beans with chopsticks, and noncultural activities, e.g. getting somebody to pour water into a cup on your head while he or she was blindfolded. Due to the last activity I got wet, but my shirt dried really quickly. And alas, even though I had taken calligraphy summer classes a long time ago, my calligraphy was awful — robotic, lifeless strokes without the right aesthetic proportions to make up for it. Blargh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, lunch followed, and then it was time for the closing ceremony, in the same building as the other ceremonies and contests. Our team caught the ending song of in a Chinese musical being rehearsed as we walked into the auditorium. While we waited for everybody, we milled about waving flags that our various teachers had brought, including not only Taiwan’s flag but also flags of my school, thoughtfully brought by teachers who had volunteered. A little later our leader told us that all the leaders had discussed the matter during a meeting and decided that we shouldn’t bring any flags to the stage while receiving our medals, so we were going to have to make do with being patriotic and school-respecting off stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were a few performances, including two aboriginal music performances and the musical we had seen rehearsed ealier, which was a fun rock musical rendition of some Chinese tale that seemed to have been sharply abridged, giving it the plot depth of a Wikipedia stub-article synopsis — a conflict, boy-meets-girl-and-falls-in-love, and a lamenting Aesop song conclusion with thrillingly vague general applicability. But the singing and counterpointing and atmosphere were good. I guess it was proportional to the relative importance of the performance to the closing ceremony. The program interleaved them with the long-awaited medal presentations: one round of bronze medalists, one round of silver, one round of gold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dum-dum-dum-dum, medals! The home team advantage was really obvious here; the cheering and the medal-presenter handshakes were both significantly more forceful for Taiwan’s medalists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/gold.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/gold.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;I think our leader made this. Thanks.&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
I think our leader made this. Thanks.
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[IOI 2014 Part 2] One Line to Solve Them All</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/one-line</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2014 23:49:14 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/one-line</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I started trying to sleep at 9 the night before the contest, tossed and turned in bed until 10, then fell asleep and got up at 3:35 in the morning. Blah. At that point, I went to the bathroom and applied some chapstick before trying to go back to sleep until 6. After breakfast, I grabbed a few minutes of sleep on the bus to the convention center where our contest would be, then slept on a sofa outside the actual contest hall alongside most of the rest of our team as we waited for a very long time until it was okay for us to enter. Competitions really mess with one’s sleep schedule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, much too soon, we could enter. Day 1 of the contest was about to start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The laptops were as yesterday, although they were protected with a white screensaver that indicated my name and ID as well as a countdown to the start of the contest. I was glad to see that my mousepad and all my writing utensils had survived without me. Somebody had the sense of humor to project an online stopwatch with an animated bomb fuse onto the screens to indicate the remaining time, which, once again, there was a lot of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I conferred briefly with Paul (TZW (alphaveros (?))) about vim settings for a bit, but there were still fifteen minutes left or so. I idly stretched, practiced typing my &lt;code&gt;.vimrc&lt;/code&gt; on an imaginary keyboard, and watched as the US dude two tables to my left unplugged his laptop’s mouse and rearranged absolutely everything on his table using the surface under his chair as swap space. (Well, that was how I mentally described it at the time, pending further revelations. (hint hint))&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then it began. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[IOI 2014 Part 0] Waiting</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/waiting</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2014 21:30:53 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/waiting</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yes, I know day 1 of the contest already ended and is probably a more interesting topic to blog about, but I finished writing this last night just before the internet was cut off to quarantine the contestants from the leaders, who received the problems and began translating them. I didn’t know about this until it was too late, which is why I’ve been waiting since yesterday to post this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To provide a counterpoint to the last post, one of the many, &lt;em&gt;many&lt;/em&gt; advantages of entering an international competition is that you get to meet a lot more people you already know, so there’s less time spent being socially awkward. While waiting for stuff to happen, aside from all the expected time spent with the Taiwan team, I also talked to, played games with, and otherwise entertained a whole lot of people I already knew, including my schoolmates (no less than fourteen of them were volunteers) and some of the college students who had shepherded us around during olympiad training.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which is a good thing, too, because there was a lot of waiting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First I waited for my teammates; my parents had decided to take me to the hotel (Fullon Shenkeng) directly, since I had a lot of stuff, and I had arrived early. This took about an hour, after which we had lunch. Then I waited for the hotel to give us our room cards, which took about five hours, after which we had dinner. Finally, at night, I waited for the Codeforces system tests. Very nerve-wracking. But I’m getting ahead of myself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rise from the Ashes</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/rise</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2014 19:27:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/rise</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After the first stage of selection camp, I was very nervous because I was fifth place in a selection sequence that would finally result in a team of four.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I screwed myself over on the first mock test by committing to a bad implementation method on a problem that was hard to get points on. My method seemed simple, but the memory usage leaked out in a way that was confusing and hard to patch; unfortunately, I tried to patch it in increasingly desperate and convoluted ways rather than scrapping the method, and thus missed out on many of the points elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the second test I failed to read the last problem carefully and spent too much of my time on the second problem, once again missing out on a lot of relatively easy points. I had optimized and optimized and pushed my quadratic runtime down to linearithmic, which would allow me to get the points for the last subtask — or so I thought. But with 10 minutes left I had all but one testcase right, and after desperately rereading my code, I realized that I had a string comparison stuck in an inner loop that could make my runtime degenerate to quadratic if the input string had lots of the same digit. In order to have a solidly linearithmic algorithm, I would have to implement a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Suffix_array&#34;&gt;suffix array&lt;/a&gt;. Ten minutes? I gave up. (The problem setters told me afterwards that hashing would have worked too; I didn’t think of that at all. Oops.) I spent the 10 minutes reading the last problem and still failed to read it carefully. So that did not go very well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, as the title probably gave away, during the third and fourth mock tests everything went much better than expected. :)  There are two good reasons:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adventures in Cabal Installations</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/cabal</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2014 15:51:16 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/cabal</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First Google Code Jam!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The format of this competition, allowing us to run programs on our own machines, brought up a very interesting issue for me: what programming language should I be using? (I had had similar considerations for IPSC 2013, but GCJ’s problems are closer to the traditional ACM-ICPC style.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The obvious choice is C++, the language I use for roughly every other competition, but its safety (or lack thereof) is not very appealing. I need speed, but not &lt;em&gt;that much&lt;/em&gt; speed. Unfortunately I still haven’t gotten around to learning any other friendlier mid-level languages (on the list: D, Go, or Rust), so I have no close substitutes for C++ right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python is certainly available for a reliable arbitrary-length integer type, if nothing else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for non-candidates, Java has &lt;code&gt;BigInteger&lt;/code&gt; and memory safety, but all in all I decided the benefits are too minor and it’s too ugly without operator overloading. Scala is probably way too slow. So I don’t expect to be writing either language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only difficult choice I have to make is, of course, Haskell — which can be quite fast, even while it’s ridiculously type-safe and expressive and referentially transparent and easy to reason about, once you’ve:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;figured out how to do the problem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;scrapped step 1 and &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; figured out how to do the problem &lt;em&gt;functionally&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gotten the thing to compile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if I can handle step 1, step 2 is by no means a simple task, as my struggle to implement a mere &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/haskell&#34;&gt;Sieve of Eratosthenes&lt;/a&gt; efficiently shows. That is fun, but not at all intuitive; I am doubtful I can do this under contest conditions. It is extremely difficult to transfer my skills in learning how to implement, say, a segment tree or treap into this language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But! Google links to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.go-hero.net/jam/10/round/0&#34;&gt;programming language breakdown for 2010 Qualification Round&lt;/a&gt; as an example, and much to my surprise, Haskell ranks somewhere between sixth and tenth place in popularity (depending on what you sort by), so there are functional superprogrammers who can presumably do something like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it happens, I ended up implementing all four solutions to the qualification rounds in Haskell, because of the relaxed time limit and lack of any involved algorithms and data structures. I think it was worth it. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sands of Time</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/time</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2013 18:33:17 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/time</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Random video! Although I feel that I’ve heard it earlier, my first conscious memory of getting linked to it is from &lt;a href=&#34;http://usamoarchive.wordpress.com/2012/03/01/youre-older-than-youve-ever-been/&#34;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt;. At first I thought it would be the right background music for this post, but upon further reflection I think it mainly suited me while I was writing this post. Well, it’s topical if you mentally replace “day” with “year”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/q2bo_u_YmW8&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34; title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway. Around this time a year ago, I paused my participation in big high-school competitions, for a variety of reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, I stopped attempting to make IMO both because I wouldn’t get that much from the training and because other people ought to have the opportunity. I was concerned that I might condition myself to only be able to do math with the short-term motivation of contests. Better to focus on college math and maybe some original research, I thought. During the year, I did lots of the former and very little of the latter. Meh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the IOI, my obvious next target: I was tired of training and going abroad while paranoid about whether my immune system would hold up. I didn’t feel that the IOI was worth that. To some degree, I also felt burned out about programming. Long story short, my treatment should end soon, and learning Haskell completely resolved the burnout problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the most important reason, I think, was that “high school was too short”. I started math competitions ridiculously early and didn’t spend much time exploring other interests. I thought I knew myself well enough that I could say I didn’t have many more interests at all, but I was completely wrong (psych nerds will reflexively note this to be the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dunning%E2%80%93Kruger_effect&#34;&gt;Dunning-Kruger effect&lt;/a&gt;). I coded lots in weird languages — Haskell, as mentioned previously, plus Scala, plus all manner of other magical command line tools. I wrote my first math problem and submitted it officially, picked up a new instrument, went to a debate competition, served as an unimportant tech guy for MUN, discovered and became hooked on Pentatonix, participated in three puzzle hunts in Australia and one in Massachusetts, figured out my rough political stance, rode a boat, got retweeted by &lt;span class=&#34;citation&#34; data-cites=&#34;eevee&#34;&gt;@eevee&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class=&#34;citation&#34; data-cites=&#34;Kyrgyzstan_News&#34;&gt;@Kyrgyzstan_News&lt;/span&gt;, increased my Neopets™ fortune by over 3400%, and lurked on FurAffinity a little too much.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ridiculously Long-Winded Programming Babble</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/programming</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2012 22:08:28 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/programming</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Okay I don’t actually know how this pointless rambling got so long. I know the longer it is the more people will just tend to skim, because I do that all the time. So I went back and refactored—er, rewrote all the somewhat tangential bits (wow these puns are too easy) into footnotes. Manually. Obviously if I have to do this again I’ll write a script for it. But the post is still really long, and I bet nobody will read the whole thing. Oh well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life updates: I got out of the hospital Friday two-and-a-half weeks ago, went to the preliminaries of NPSC (a national team programming contest) with classmates, threw up a lot, went back into the hospital, and came out again. I wrote a lot of stuff about the experience and how much it sucked (hint: &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt;) when I started this draft around that time, but now putting so much detail in this post feels weird. I’m mostly good now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three years ago NPSC was the only programming contest I really knew of; now I’ve participated in quite a few more, both online and locally, but it’s still the only contest I’ve entered that gives you real-time verdicts. I believe it inherits this from being modeled after ACM-ICPC, but that’s for college people and I’m less clear on how it works. All the other contests, namely &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.topcoder.com/&#34;&gt;TopCoder&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.codeforces.com/&#34;&gt;CodeForces&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://usaco.org/&#34;&gt;USACO&lt;/a&gt;, and the other local individual competition (there doesn’t appear to be an English name so for the purpose of this post I’ll just call it “Nameless Local”; there’s a nation-wide competition in one-and-a-half weeks!), have system tests after the contest that don’t allow you to resubmit afterwards.&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; class=&#34;footnoteRef&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; They all give pretests that you get to know about right away, just to catch super-silly non-algorithmic mistakes like failing to remove the debug statements or reading input from the wrong place, but these contain weak test cases and don’t guarantee that the solution will pass the system tests and get full score.  After roughly parsing the rules on the IOI’s website, I believe the IOI (at least this year; I don’t know if it has evolved or anything) allows real-time testing and feedback with a confusing bunch of restrictions: how it apparently works is there are free “public tests”, and you can get results for a “release test” using the official test cases by using a “release token”, which you get two of every half hour. Additionally, there is apparently a cap of 64 submissions per problem, but I’m pretty sure it’s the kind of cap that honest competitors can safely ignore, like the 100-per-group in Australian puzzlehunts. Well, at least it tells us the organizers think in binary. Or octal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[IMO 2012 Part 2] The Hotel of Deception</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/hotel</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2012 12:45:41 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/hotel</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We finally arrived at the hotel at 3:30, meeting another local from Taiwan, Mr. Chen, who helped us carry some of our stuff off the bus. Po-Chiang, our guide, was waiting inside. We took more pictures and finally lugged the meager stuff we had off to our hotel rooms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At least, we tried. I started to realize that there was much more to this hotel than it seemed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, of course, was the confusing placement of rooms with numbers starting with 4 and 5 on the fourth floor (which would be the fifth floor by our numbering system, where the lobby is floor 1; but here the lobby was assigned 0. Off-by-one errors just waiting to happen here.) Secondly were the completely indecipherable signs. I don’t remember the details, but the first signs we saw read something like “560 ~ 540: left; 520 ~ 540: right”. Occasionally there would be weird slashes or half-slashes between the numbers instead (later I finally realized they were slanted, Comic-Sans-style capital Ys, or “and” in Spanish). Are these closed, open, or half-open intervals? And why the heck are their upper and lower bounds in a different order!?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We wandered through the corridors, peeking down each one, trying to figure out whether the numbers were increasing or decreasing and whether a parity argument (for those of you not fluent in math lingo, that means odds and evens) allowed for the existence of our room. Who knew the simple act of finding one’s living quarters could be so mathematically tasking? In the end, our rooms were in the last corridor, just about diametrically opposite to the elevators on the half of our floor. Oh well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The room was pretty nice overall. The furniture and basic facilities were quite complete, with a sparkly bathroom and a couple tables and chairs of various shapes. The closet was big and had a safe, which was rather important because just about everybody we had met had warned us over and over again about all the incredibly skilled thieves, muggers, and pickpockets in Argentina. It was probably much safer (no pun intended) in the hotel, but with all of these warnings (later we would even find a notice from the hotel warning us to lock our doors) I was never entirely certain. There were lots of lights controlled by a set of confusing switches on either side of our beds. There was at least one white immovable divider cunningly disguised as a switch, one switch that didn’t ever seem to do anything, and one that turned everything off. The last one made a little sense after a while because it had pictures of stars and a moon on it, but the whole setup was still pretty non-user-friendly in my opinion.  The awesome part was that our room was connected with the one next door with a tiny midway corridor, so by keeping the connecting doors unlocked, the four of us (me, WL, CPT, KYL) could share one room key and just hang out really conveniently. The other two had a room connected to one with two guys from Cyprus. I don’t think they interacted that much, although I know we got an inequality from them one of the days before the contest. We observed that Jensen didn’t work on it and didn’t really touch it afterwards, still living under the mistaken and highly deluded assumption that there was no way the PSC would choose an inequality now that they finally realized that everybody knew Muirhead.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[IMO 2012 Part 1] Dangerous Metal Chopsticks</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/metal-chopsticks</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2012 07:44:51 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/metal-chopsticks</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s time to begin the epic blogging journey. The detailed version of this year’s amazing IMO, because I decided that a perfectionist guy like myself could not possibly liveblog and be satisfied with both the quality of the posts and being able to fully enjoy the actual event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our story begins in a hotel in Taiwan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The night before departure, us six contestants and Prof. Lin gathered in a hotel. This was entirely necessary because our flight left at something like five o’clock in the morning. After checking over the flight plans and relevant phone numbers in a conference room, we enjoyed a pretty extensive buffet dinner, what would easily be the best meal we would get to have for at least a week, the highlight of which was a fish steak that looked and tasted exactly like fried egg. Afterwards we did some emergency shopping and prepared a convenience-store breakfast for consumption three o’clock the next day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I’ve complained before, we have an 11-hour difference to get used to, and that morning I had gotten myself to sleep as late as 6 AM trying (successfully, much to my amazement) to complete an iPod OS system update. I didn’t think I could pass airport security with the sort of consciousness I had when I finally slept that morning, so I reverted with the rest of the team to an 11 PM curfew. Oh well. The seven of us left the hotel after 3 AM, setting off in a huge 30-person bus for the airport.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>