<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sat on Bounded-Error Log</title>
    <link>//blog.vero.site/tag/sat</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sat on Bounded-Error Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 23:59:53 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//blog.vero.site/tag/sat/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Quixotic Reimagining of Standardized Tests (Part 2)</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/quixotic-2</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 23:59:53 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/quixotic-2</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you remember, &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/quixotic-1&#34;&gt;Part 1 was here&lt;/a&gt; and my goal is to construct a theoretical system of standardized tests that I would be satisfied by. Here’s what I’ve got. As usual, because of the &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/commitment&#34;&gt;daily posting streak I have openly committed to&lt;/a&gt;, standard disclaimers apply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’d have a first-tier test like the SAT, except this will be &lt;em&gt;explicitly designed&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; to distinguish among the high performers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of the test is to assess &lt;em&gt;basic&lt;/em&gt; proficiency in reading, writing, and mathematics. Nothing else. Most good students, those who have a shot at “good colleges” and know it, will be able to ace this test with minimal effort and can spend their time studying for other things or engaging in other pursuits. Students who don’t will still have to study and it will probably be boring, but the hope is that, especially if you’re motivated to get into a good college, there won’t be much of that studying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For colleges, the intention of this test is to allow them to require this test score from everybody without having to &lt;a href=&#34;http://mitadmissions.org/blogs/entry/the-difficulty-with-data&#34;&gt;put up disclaimers&lt;/a&gt; that go like,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;there is really not a difference in our process between someone who scores, say, a 740 on the SAT math, and someone who scores an 800 on the SAT math. So why, as the commentor asks, is there such a difference in the admit rate? &lt;em&gt;Aha! Clearly we DO prefer higher SAT scores!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Well no, we don’t. What we prefer are things which &lt;em&gt;may coincide&lt;/em&gt; with higher SAT scores…
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quixotic Reimagining of Standardized Tests (Part 1)</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/quixotic-1</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2015 23:19:42 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/quixotic-1</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Life update: I got my driver’s license from the place where I learned to drive. Then I drove home from there with my mom, and it was zarking &lt;em&gt;terrifying&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, WordPress says it has protected my blog from 3&lt;sup&gt;8&lt;/sup&gt; spam comments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Early in the morning tomorrow, I have a small surgical operation, so I can’t sleep too late. (Well, it ended up being pretty late anyway. Darn.) Therefore I think I’m going to do something unprecedented on this blog for the &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/commitment&#34;&gt;daily posting streak&lt;/a&gt;: I’m going to post an incomplete non-expository post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, the only purpose of the title is to get initials that are four consecutive letters of the alphabet..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the more argumentative post sequences on my blog involved ranting against standardized tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My very first stab was probably the &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/test&#34;&gt;silly satire&lt;/a&gt; directed at the test everybody has to take that takes up two hours per day of an entire week. Once college became a thing in my life, I wrote a &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/2400&#34;&gt;humblebrag rant&lt;/a&gt; after I took the SAT and then a &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/sat&#34;&gt;summary post&lt;/a&gt; after I snagged this subject for an English class research paper and finished said paper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should be plenty clear that I am not ranting against this part of the system because it’s disadvantageous to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it should also be said that I’ve read some convincing arguments for using standardized tests &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; in college admissions (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newrepublic.com/article/119321/harvard-ivy-league-should-judge-students-standardized-tests&#34;&gt;Pinker&lt;/a&gt;, then &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.scottaaronson.com/blog/?p=2003&#34;&gt;Aaronson&lt;/a&gt;). Despite the imperfections of tests, they argue, the alternatives are likely to be less fair and more easily gamed. The fear that selecting only high test-scorers will yield a class of one-dimensional boring thinkers is unfounded. And the idea that standardized tests “reduce a human being to a number” may be uncomfortable for some, but it makes no sense to prioritize avoiding a vague feeling of discomfort over trusting reliable social science studies. Neither article, you will note, advocates selecting &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; of one’s college admits based on highest score. Just a certain unspecified proportion, one that’s probably a lot larger than it is today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And although I wish the first article linked its studies, I mostly agree with their arguments. So this puts me in a tricky position. These positions I’ve expressed seem hard to reconcile! So, after arguing about all this with a friend who told me things like&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
I think you fail to understand how anti-intellectual american society is
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Re-Re-Revisiting the SAT</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/sat</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2014 00:54:03 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/sat</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First, I got worked up about the test. Then I got a score and ranted about it on this blog. (I’m still uncertainly hoping that didn’t come off as arrogant. Let me add, I did not get a perfect PSAT.) Then a friend pitched to me the idea that I write an article about it for my school newspaper, which I did. It was far too long. As if that weren’t enough, I then decided to examine whether the SAT was an accurate prediction of “academic ability and success” for my English research paper. Now I’ve come full circle to this blog, where I’m going to try to synthesize and conclude everything, free of the shackles of the research paper format, to allow me to move on with my life. This post contains bits lifted from all three essays and lots of new stuff; I’ve been editing it for so long that I feel like I have it memorized. Its word count is around that of the newspaper article &lt;em&gt;plus&lt;/em&gt; the research paper, i.e. far far far too long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But whatever, nobody reads this blog anyway and I have to get this out of my system. When I said I wanted to “move on with my life”, I really meant my winter homework. Oops!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer:&lt;/strong&gt; I am not an admissions officer. I have not yet even been accepted to a prestigious university (despite rumors to the contrary…), for whatever definition of “prestigious”, unlike some of the bloggers I’m referencing. So some of this is pure speculation. On the other hand, some of it is researched and referenced, and I think the pure speculation still makes sense. That’s why I’m posting it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, here we go…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with the question of accurate prediction. The SAT is a useful predictor, but not as useful as one might assume. Intuitively, it ought to be more accurate than other metrics because it’s a &lt;em&gt;standardized&lt;/em&gt; test, whereas GPAs other awards vary by habits of teacher and region and are hard to compare objectively. But as a &lt;a href=&#34;http://research.collegeboard.org/sites/default/files/publications/2012/7/researchreport-2008-5-validity-sat-predicting-first-year-college-grade-point-average.pdf&#34;&gt;study from the College Board &lt;em&gt;itself&lt;/em&gt; (PDF)&lt;/a&gt; found:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
the correlation of HSGPA [high-school GPA] and FYGPA [first-year GPA in college] is 0.36 (Adj. r = 0.54), which is slightly higher than the multiple correlation of the SAT (critical reading, math, and writing combined) with FYGPA (r = 0.35, Adj. r = 0.53).
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Okay, I got a 2400. Happy now?</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/2400</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 22:59:07 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/2400</guid>
      <description>&lt;ins datetime=&#34;2017-11-25T01:23:34-0500&#34;&gt;
Note from the future, 2017: I am fairly unhappy with this rant as it stands — it makes many points I still agree with, but it just sounds sooo pretentious — but it is one of very few posts to actually receive a link from an external post I’m aware of, so I guess I should let it stand for historical interest. I wrote this years ago; please don’t take it out of context.
&lt;/ins&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have to admit, I got unhealthily worked up about getting this score.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the purposes of college, I only ever wanted a score that wouldn’t be a deal-breaker — anything above 2300 would be enough. Any other time I had left would be better spent in other endeavors. Such endeavors might help on the college app, but more importantly, I’d also get to enjoy them.&lt;/p&gt;
So why am I here? Partly it’s because my classmates got worked up about it. Somebody specifically requested me to post my score somewhere. And partly it’s because there couldn’t be a better way at the moment to establish my authority to (yet again) rant against standardized tests here. 
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“Everyone is a genius. But if you judge a fish by its ability to climb a tree, it will live its whole life believing that it is stupid.”
&lt;p class=&#34;source&#34;&gt;
— &lt;a href=&#34;http://quoteinvestigator.com/2013/04/06/fish-climb/&#34;&gt;not actually Albert Einstein&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>