<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Singing on Bounded-Error Log</title>
    <link>//blog.vero.site/tag/singing</link>
    <description>Recent content in Singing on Bounded-Error Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2014 13:04:16 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//blog.vero.site/tag/singing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>[IOI 2014 Part 4] Shades of Xanthous</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/xanthous</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2014 13:04:16 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/xanthous</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;No, I didn’t forget. Not for one minute. I was doing homework. I am very happy because that means I was actually carrying out my priorities as I envisioned them. I’ve probably edited this post too many times, though. Meh. But it’s the first weekend after finishing summer homework, so here we go again!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fun fact: This is by far my favorite post title in the entire series. Possibly in the entire history of this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the morning of the last day of official IOI activities, there were a bunch of cultural activities, e.g. writing Chinese characters calligraphically, doing tricks with the diabolo, or picking up beans with chopsticks, and noncultural activities, e.g. getting somebody to pour water into a cup on your head while he or she was blindfolded. Due to the last activity I got wet, but my shirt dried really quickly. And alas, even though I had taken calligraphy summer classes a long time ago, my calligraphy was awful — robotic, lifeless strokes without the right aesthetic proportions to make up for it. Blargh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, lunch followed, and then it was time for the closing ceremony, in the same building as the other ceremonies and contests. Our team caught the ending song of in a Chinese musical being rehearsed as we walked into the auditorium. While we waited for everybody, we milled about waving flags that our various teachers had brought, including not only Taiwan’s flag but also flags of my school, thoughtfully brought by teachers who had volunteered. A little later our leader told us that all the leaders had discussed the matter during a meeting and decided that we shouldn’t bring any flags to the stage while receiving our medals, so we were going to have to make do with being patriotic and school-respecting off stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were a few performances, including two aboriginal music performances and the musical we had seen rehearsed ealier, which was a fun rock musical rendition of some Chinese tale that seemed to have been sharply abridged, giving it the plot depth of a Wikipedia stub-article synopsis — a conflict, boy-meets-girl-and-falls-in-love, and a lamenting Aesop song conclusion with thrillingly vague general applicability. But the singing and counterpointing and atmosphere were good. I guess it was proportional to the relative importance of the performance to the closing ceremony. The program interleaved them with the long-awaited medal presentations: one round of bronze medalists, one round of silver, one round of gold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dum-dum-dum-dum, medals! The home team advantage was really obvious here; the cheering and the medal-presenter handshakes were both significantly more forceful for Taiwan’s medalists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/gold.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/gold.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;I think our leader made this. Thanks.&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
I think our leader made this. Thanks.
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/music</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2013 23:13:54 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/music</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Isn’t it weird to suddenly talk about this topic?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t think that I have ever talked about music any more than briefly in passing. It might be confusing to my &lt;em&gt;finger quotes&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;audience&lt;/em&gt;, and I worry I’ll seem inconsistent.&lt;/p&gt;
Well, a foolish consistency is the hobgoblin of little minds. If you wonder, “I didn’t know that you sang and played the piano, or you liked music in that way — or, at all…” please note that I didn’t know either. 
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For most of my life, I was just a shower singer to myself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[IMO 2012 Part 6] Mostly Not About Excursions</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/not-excursions</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2012 08:40:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/not-excursions</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yes. I know it’s been more than a month. Blogging motivation decreases, but the responsibility of that &lt;em&gt;stay tuned&lt;/em&gt; doesn’t go away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s okay. It’s all worth it because the stuff in the games room is absolutely ridiculous. Warning: huge post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/p4.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/p4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;[IMO 2012 Problem 4 on a cake.&#34; title=&#34;Problem 4 Cake&#34; width=&#34;474&#34; height=&#34;252&#34; class=&#34;size-full wp-image-1317&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
Our old friend, the monster of a functional equation, in edible form. In the games room. Did I mention abso-zarking-lutely ridiculous?
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>