<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Death on Bounded-Error Log</title>
    <link>//blog.vero.site/tag/death</link>
    <description>Recent content in Death on Bounded-Error Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 15:22:19 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//blog.vero.site/tag/death/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Pangs</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/pangs</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 15:22:19 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/pangs</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have this memory —&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was a tiny kid, lying in bed and trying to fall asleep, and I started thinking about death and nonexistence, and I thought about how one day I wouldn’t exist any more, that there wouldn’t &lt;em&gt;be&lt;/em&gt; a me thinking my thoughts and perceiving my perspective, and suddenly I was terrified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got up and knocked on my parents’ bedroom door and asked them about this. Maybe. Or maybe I didn’t because the fear was less crippling than the social awkwardness of randomly knocking on my parents’ door in the middle of the night to ask them a question like that; I don’t remember. It was a long time ago, okay?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mortality</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/mortality</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 21:00:51 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/mortality</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Faux-philosophical blog content, posted as part of a &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/commitment&#34;&gt;daily posting streak I have openly committed to&lt;/a&gt;; standard disclaimers apply)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a hard essay to write because (1) it’s very irrational and I should (and I do) know better — death by car accident is much more likely than death by an airplane crash, but the latter is scarier because it’s more vivid and we have less control over it, and (2) people don’t like talking about it. When I tried writing it, though, I realized I already burned through most of the down-to-earth worries in the posts I made between April and August of 2010. They still coherently and accurately sum up my current thoughts surprisingly well. And most of the irrational, overly philosophical fears appeared in &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/midnight&#34;&gt;Thoughts at Midnight&lt;/a&gt;. So there used to be a lot of fluff here like this, which was inducing procrastination because I don’t know what to include and what to cut, but now that I have a daily deadline, I cut most of it. Here’s what’s left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One, xkcd:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts at Midnight</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/midnight</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2015 00:49:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/midnight</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;These are the thoughts that sometimes keep me awake at night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are things I don’t want to think about. These are things I’ve spent hours thinking about, never productively. They are worrying, but unlike typical worries in my life, it is fundamentally impractical to take steps to resolve or mitigate them, after which I may rest assured that I’ve done my best. The reason is that they also happen to be either untestable/unfalsifiable or only testable if one incurs absurd and irreversible costs, mainly dying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I explain them away to myself successfully and move on. Sometimes I read what I’ve written and think about these thoughts and do the cognitive equivalent of looking at them funny, as I’m expecting most readers to feel if they get that far — why would anybody be bothered, or afraid, or soul-crushingly panicked about these things? Life is so busy, there are literally more than sixty-four items on my HabitRPG to-do list, and besides, there are so many serious global issues humanity is actually facing right now, and people who are actually deprived of basic rights and resources and have to struggle to stay alive. How can I possibly be bothered by these absurd remote thoughts?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I know that other times I do feel those emotions exactly. And if I stare &lt;em&gt;just right&lt;/em&gt;, I can feel those emotions bubbling beneath the surface in me. Sometimes I can’t explain the issues away to myself, and a deep soul-sucking pang grows in my stomach. I’m irrational — I’m afraid of some of these thoughts — and I have submitted to the fact that there are some edges of my irrationality that would not be worth the effort to fix if just not thinking about them is better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes these thoughts make me wish I were not so rational. Sometimes they even make me wish I were religious; it would be easier if (I believed) consciousness were, somehow, special. I suspect if I tried really hard, I could make myself believe something like that sincerely. But I think that’s a betrayal of myself I’m not willing to take. I think there are better ways to remain happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to maximize happiness. Thinking about more general moral principles will help with that, but the remoteness of these particular thoughts is such that I doubt I’ll ever have to make a choice that would benefit from me having thought about them. At least, I think the chance is small enough to not be worth the negative utility spent thinking about them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So: “There is nothing to fear but fear itself.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I feel frustrated: not thinking about something just doesn’t seem like a solution. I don’t know how to come to terms with just how irrational happiness fundamentally is. And I still can’t resist thinking about them sometimes…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>