<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Memories on Bounded-Error Log</title>
    <link>//blog.vero.site/tag/memories</link>
    <description>Recent content in Memories on Bounded-Error Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2015 13:40:30 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//blog.vero.site/tag/memories/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>8 Songs for 18 Years</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/8-songs</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2015 13:40:30 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/8-songs</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At some point I thought, hmm, maybe this blog would benefit from some more sentimental, memory-capturing music/videos, like I chose for my &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/time&#34;&gt;end of 2013 post&lt;/a&gt; or my &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/rewind&#34;&gt;end of 2014 post&lt;/a&gt;. (Yeah, I link to my own posts alarmingly often. I think that’s kind of weird. I don’t know.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, because you’re reading this already, I decided to follow through with that idea. There’s no particular significance for posting this now — it’s not my birthday or anything, as the title might suggest; it just has a nice ring to it — except of course that I’m starting to get mildly desperate for content for my &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/commitment&#34;&gt;daily posting streak exercise&lt;/a&gt;. Standard disclaimers apply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is mostly for my future self. I should note that, although I like these songs, this is not a list of my absolute most favorite songs ever. You can tell because there isn’t any Coldplay or fun. (the band.) Instead, each of these songs was chosen to be meaningful to myself and my life in at least two different ways that generally don’t overlap with the other songs. This was difficult but I think I managed it — you know, how constraint breeds creativity and everything? Also, they’re arranged by approximate chronological order of impact. But it also means that this list isn’t going to be that meaningful to anybody other than myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, I have a long list of class-of-2015 sentimental songs, which I’m not including here because I think there are so many that they deserve a separate post. Will I avoid procrastinating and feeling awkward for long enough to make such a post? Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;shrugs&lt;/em&gt; Whatever, enjoy the music or stop reading now if you want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1: Simon &amp;amp; Garfunkel - Scarborough Fair/Canticle&lt;/strong&gt; 
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/-Jj4s9I-53g&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
  Not only is Scarborough Fair one of my mom’s favorite songs, I’ve bumped into it three entirely separate times while solving puzzles. I always love counterpoint and I find the effect here especially haunting.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Points on Photography</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/photography</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2015 23:55:52 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/photography</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Uncohesive blog content, posted as part of a &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/commitment&#34;&gt;daily posting streak I have openly committed to&lt;/a&gt;; standard disclaimers apply. Whew, made it by a few minutes…)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This essay was partly inspired by but mostly orthogonal in purpose to dzaefn’s essay on a similar subject, &lt;a href=&#34;https://zyxyvy.wordpress.com/2012/04/09/humans-photographs-and-names/&#34;&gt;Humans, Photographs, and Names&lt;/a&gt;. I agree with many of its points, although I deviate in that I think it’s more important for my Facebook picture to identify me than to inform about me (there’s the rest of Facebook, plus my maybe half a dozen other sites, for doing so). Part of the problem for me there, and part of the reason I hang on to my nine-letter random handle from fourth grade, is that my names, first and last, are so commonplace. Among the people who share them (according to DuckDuckGo) are a New York Times tech writer, more than one computer science professor, a photographer, a couple doctors, and some guy who did some sort of graphics work for a short clip and two movies. This means that, to somebody not already in my social circles trying to match me to my account, my Facebook photo is my primary tool for disambiguating myself from all these other people, and I don’t think there is anything that could do that job quite as precisely as a picture of my actual face and body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, I agree enough to be bothered by having a profile picture suffering from “the whole extent of photographic informational void”. I always planned to add some GIMP layers to the photo to indicate context and content more precisely. Except I procrastinated and it got more and more awkward to do this as time went by, since as far as I know, normal people update their profile pictures only to reflect more recent events, especially when they’re important. Like, you know, &lt;em&gt;graduating from high school&lt;/em&gt;? So yes, I’ve been waiting to do this for an entire year now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eh, to hell with awkwardness. That’s the spirit of this daily-posting exercise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Fun fact: The code in what I’m about to set as my profile picture, if I don’t procrastinate even more, is real IOI 2014 code I submitted successfully (for &lt;a href=&#34;https://betaveros.wordpress.com/2014/07/26/one-line/&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;rail&lt;/code&gt;, as previously featured&lt;/a&gt;; the visually selected fragment was the key fix for the final bug I fixed). Except I actually had to manually retype my code printout to get the picture because I lacked the foresight (sound familiar?) to save an electronic copy of my IOI submissions.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, I’m glad this isn’t a smiling photo because I feel like it’s easier to appreciate happy posts from a person whom one associates with a serious face, than serious posts from a person whom one associates with a happy face, and I want both types of posts to impact people when I post them. I could be overgeneralizing from my own feelings though. If you are reading this and want to chat me feedback (as way more than one of you has been doing), I’d welcome more data points on this issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s not what I &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; wanted to rant about in this post, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>