<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Education on Bounded-Error Log</title>
    <link>//blog.vero.site/tag/education</link>
    <description>Recent content in Education on Bounded-Error Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2015 23:16:46 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//blog.vero.site/tag/education/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bilingualism II</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/bilingualism-ii</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2015 23:16:46 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/bilingualism-ii</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;我本來還想把這一篇用英文跟中文各打一次來實際比較看看，但這已經被困在草稿匣夠久了。一直做重複、吹毛求疵、沒有效率的修改本來就是我寫心情文時的弊病，如果再要求修改時要保持兩種語言版本的同步的話，大概寫到天荒地老都寫不完。（如果讀者沒有讀過我最近亂發的文章，故事都是這樣的：我覺得我在草稿匣累積了太多寫一半的文章，所以在畢業後，我&lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/commitment&#34;&gt;在六月十一號決定從那天開始每天發文，直到我出國&lt;/a&gt;，目的是強迫自己把那些草稿寫完，中間還亂發很多其他我本來大概不會寫下來的東西。其實還滿有成就感的。另外，如果你的中文沒有很爛的話，如果你在任何地方認為我寫的中文不流暢或是可以寫得更好，請毫不留情的留言批評。這也是一件我發現我在寫中文方面很缺乏的經驗，我會很感謝。當然，根據以往經驗，懇求讀者留言沒什麼機會成功。）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you came to this blog or this post hoping to read English, sorry not sorry. It’s only fair, really, given how many people on Facebook can’t read the massive English textwall posts I’ve spammed them with for so long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;常常有人訝異我的英文這麼好。有時候這些人還會問我怎麼學的－－碰到這種問題我都不知道要怎麼回答。喔，很簡單啊，只要選擇在一個主要說英文的國家出生，然後跟一群從國外回來的同學一起讀有80%的課是用英文上的學校連續讀十二年就好了。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;偶爾也有人知道我是雙語部的或在不同的情況下認識我，反而會覺得我的中文比他們預期的好，例如我的駕訓班教練。其實我在雙語部還是上了十二年的國文課，進度理論上跟其他學校一樣（「理論上」三個字要強調），我也跟身旁很多親戚朋友用中文溝通了更久。比奧林匹亞競賽的經驗應該也讓我認識的上普通國語教學學校的學生，比其他雙語部同學認識的多。所以這應該也不奇怪吧。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;但是。其實我對這兩個語言的精熟度其實還是差很多。日常對話沒問題，不過我對英文細枝末節的部分瞭解的比中文多太多太多了。家裡有不止一本「常見英語錯誤」類的書，我小時候會當小說讀－－我是一個很奇怪的人。在學校課程中，我編輯自己或他人的英文文章是一天到晚的事情，什麼奇怪的句子跟構造都碰過、想過、修理過。還有些時候，我會很自然的寫出一個英文單字，然後發現我不知道為什麼自己會知道這個單字的意思，但就是有一種感覺告訴我，對，subsist的意思就是「存活於只有最基本的需求被滿足的情況」。跟中文比較：有時候，直覺也會告訴我有某一個成語是可以用的，但我只能清楚想到這個成語的兩、三個字。聽起來很「對」，不過我就是想不到第四個字是什麼，或是怕前三個字換成錯別字，再加上懷疑整個成語意思根本不是我模糊腦袋裡現在浮現的，因為我認得這些字字面上的意思，但無法說服自己為什麼它們合在一起可以解釋成這種意思，最後只好放棄，用國小白話文的措詞就好了。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
「總覺得，我在用任何偏離國小程度的白話文的詞彙的時候都是假裝的。」
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我在舊一點的草稿寫出了這個句子，不過那一串「的」字讓我覺得怪怪的，現在想想，沒有人跟我討論過寫出這種或其他奇怪的句子時應該怎麼辦。哪一些「的」可以省略？有辦法把句子重寫（recast）避開嗎？還是不管它，我覺得它聽起來很奇怪純粹是錯覺，多讀一點中文就會發現根本沒什麼大不了的？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;使用兩種語言的方法也差很多。看看這個部落格就知道了。我相信我在學校雙語部外的大部分台灣朋友不會試著去理解我關於自己長篇大論的英文作文，但長篇大論的文章還是我最認真表達自己的地方。反觀我的中文短文，都通常是那種搞笑、釣讚、裝弱的文。（不，我真的很弱。）我不時會發現自己在網上逛到一個陌生人的心情文，看得津津有味。我們之間的關係頂多是朋友的朋友的朋友，我只知道我跟他應該都喜歡數學這個共同點罷了，但因為語言，我在那些瞬間覺得自己瞭解他勝於瞭解幾乎所有在我身邊講中文的朋友。我自己怎麼看這件事都覺得不合理，有點慚愧。&lt;/p&gt;
我回去讀了&lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/bilingualism&#34;&gt;我第一次寫的關於雙語的文章&lt;/a&gt;，可能有一點過火：後來證實，在我的朋友中似乎真的有會純粹為了抒發感情而寫七言律詩的人。而且，我講中文的朋友圈裡，文學類佔的比例本來就應該比他們在整個社會裡佔的比例少很多。在學校跟在生活裡，吸收英文多於中文（而且數學多於英文）是我做的選擇，只是我自己不知道選擇的中介點好不好罷了。是否，我花在跟講中文的親戚朋友互動的力氣不夠？ 
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;想寫這一堆字的靈感有一部分來自一次返校活動（九月，可以算出這篇文章停滯在草稿期的時間的下界）。我跟同學在玩一些返校活動的遊戲，我在同學之間嘴裡不停的蹦出笑話，開玩笑的挑逗人。有可能有一點過火，沒有很嚴重不過我的確覺得說了一些我希望我沒說的話。之後，我又跟同學坐在教室暢談了一段時間，聊各種高三、準畢業生的事情。可能有一個小時吧，細節不重要，重點是這引發我想到我說中文的時候好像只會有想說的話沒有說，而好像幾乎沒有過類似的交談。我跟家人、親戚、其他學校的同學沒有辦法以同樣自然的方式交談。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quixotic Reimagining of Standardized Tests (Part 2)</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/quixotic-2</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 23:59:53 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/quixotic-2</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you remember, &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/quixotic-1&#34;&gt;Part 1 was here&lt;/a&gt; and my goal is to construct a theoretical system of standardized tests that I would be satisfied by. Here’s what I’ve got. As usual, because of the &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/commitment&#34;&gt;daily posting streak I have openly committed to&lt;/a&gt;, standard disclaimers apply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’d have a first-tier test like the SAT, except this will be &lt;em&gt;explicitly designed&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; to distinguish among the high performers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of the test is to assess &lt;em&gt;basic&lt;/em&gt; proficiency in reading, writing, and mathematics. Nothing else. Most good students, those who have a shot at “good colleges” and know it, will be able to ace this test with minimal effort and can spend their time studying for other things or engaging in other pursuits. Students who don’t will still have to study and it will probably be boring, but the hope is that, especially if you’re motivated to get into a good college, there won’t be much of that studying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For colleges, the intention of this test is to allow them to require this test score from everybody without having to &lt;a href=&#34;http://mitadmissions.org/blogs/entry/the-difficulty-with-data&#34;&gt;put up disclaimers&lt;/a&gt; that go like,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;there is really not a difference in our process between someone who scores, say, a 740 on the SAT math, and someone who scores an 800 on the SAT math. So why, as the commentor asks, is there such a difference in the admit rate? &lt;em&gt;Aha! Clearly we DO prefer higher SAT scores!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Well no, we don’t. What we prefer are things which &lt;em&gt;may coincide&lt;/em&gt; with higher SAT scores…
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quixotic Reimagining of Standardized Tests (Part 1)</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/quixotic-1</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2015 23:19:42 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/quixotic-1</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Life update: I got my driver’s license from the place where I learned to drive. Then I drove home from there with my mom, and it was zarking &lt;em&gt;terrifying&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, WordPress says it has protected my blog from 3&lt;sup&gt;8&lt;/sup&gt; spam comments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Early in the morning tomorrow, I have a small surgical operation, so I can’t sleep too late. (Well, it ended up being pretty late anyway. Darn.) Therefore I think I’m going to do something unprecedented on this blog for the &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/commitment&#34;&gt;daily posting streak&lt;/a&gt;: I’m going to post an incomplete non-expository post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, the only purpose of the title is to get initials that are four consecutive letters of the alphabet..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the more argumentative post sequences on my blog involved ranting against standardized tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My very first stab was probably the &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/test&#34;&gt;silly satire&lt;/a&gt; directed at the test everybody has to take that takes up two hours per day of an entire week. Once college became a thing in my life, I wrote a &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/2400&#34;&gt;humblebrag rant&lt;/a&gt; after I took the SAT and then a &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/sat&#34;&gt;summary post&lt;/a&gt; after I snagged this subject for an English class research paper and finished said paper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should be plenty clear that I am not ranting against this part of the system because it’s disadvantageous to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it should also be said that I’ve read some convincing arguments for using standardized tests &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; in college admissions (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newrepublic.com/article/119321/harvard-ivy-league-should-judge-students-standardized-tests&#34;&gt;Pinker&lt;/a&gt;, then &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.scottaaronson.com/blog/?p=2003&#34;&gt;Aaronson&lt;/a&gt;). Despite the imperfections of tests, they argue, the alternatives are likely to be less fair and more easily gamed. The fear that selecting only high test-scorers will yield a class of one-dimensional boring thinkers is unfounded. And the idea that standardized tests “reduce a human being to a number” may be uncomfortable for some, but it makes no sense to prioritize avoiding a vague feeling of discomfort over trusting reliable social science studies. Neither article, you will note, advocates selecting &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; of one’s college admits based on highest score. Just a certain unspecified proportion, one that’s probably a lot larger than it is today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And although I wish the first article linked its studies, I mostly agree with their arguments. So this puts me in a tricky position. These positions I’ve expressed seem hard to reconcile! So, after arguing about all this with a friend who told me things like&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
I think you fail to understand how anti-intellectual american society is
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#pyconapac2014</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/pycon</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2014 22:26:53 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/pycon</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Late post. As usual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It started with an online competition — write programs, solve problems, get points. I wouldn’t call the problems easy, but they weren’t hard either. So I solved all of them. To make it even less impressive, only about twenty people submitted anything at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the result was just what it was: I ended up with a free ticket to &lt;a href=&#34;https://tw.pycon.org/2014apac/en/&#34;&gt;PyCon APAC 2014&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Re-Re-Revisiting the SAT</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/sat</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2014 00:54:03 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/sat</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First, I got worked up about the test. Then I got a score and ranted about it on this blog. (I’m still uncertainly hoping that didn’t come off as arrogant. Let me add, I did not get a perfect PSAT.) Then a friend pitched to me the idea that I write an article about it for my school newspaper, which I did. It was far too long. As if that weren’t enough, I then decided to examine whether the SAT was an accurate prediction of “academic ability and success” for my English research paper. Now I’ve come full circle to this blog, where I’m going to try to synthesize and conclude everything, free of the shackles of the research paper format, to allow me to move on with my life. This post contains bits lifted from all three essays and lots of new stuff; I’ve been editing it for so long that I feel like I have it memorized. Its word count is around that of the newspaper article &lt;em&gt;plus&lt;/em&gt; the research paper, i.e. far far far too long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But whatever, nobody reads this blog anyway and I have to get this out of my system. When I said I wanted to “move on with my life”, I really meant my winter homework. Oops!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer:&lt;/strong&gt; I am not an admissions officer. I have not yet even been accepted to a prestigious university (despite rumors to the contrary…), for whatever definition of “prestigious”, unlike some of the bloggers I’m referencing. So some of this is pure speculation. On the other hand, some of it is researched and referenced, and I think the pure speculation still makes sense. That’s why I’m posting it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, here we go…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with the question of accurate prediction. The SAT is a useful predictor, but not as useful as one might assume. Intuitively, it ought to be more accurate than other metrics because it’s a &lt;em&gt;standardized&lt;/em&gt; test, whereas GPAs other awards vary by habits of teacher and region and are hard to compare objectively. But as a &lt;a href=&#34;http://research.collegeboard.org/sites/default/files/publications/2012/7/researchreport-2008-5-validity-sat-predicting-first-year-college-grade-point-average.pdf&#34;&gt;study from the College Board &lt;em&gt;itself&lt;/em&gt; (PDF)&lt;/a&gt; found:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
the correlation of HSGPA [high-school GPA] and FYGPA [first-year GPA in college] is 0.36 (Adj. r = 0.54), which is slightly higher than the multiple correlation of the SAT (critical reading, math, and writing combined) with FYGPA (r = 0.35, Adj. r = 0.53).
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Okay, I got a 2400. Happy now?</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/2400</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 22:59:07 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/2400</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;warning&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt; from the future, 2017-11-25: I am fairly unhappy with this rant as it stands — it makes many points I still agree with, but it just sounds sooo pretentious — but it is one of very few posts to actually receive a link from an external post I’m aware of, so I am letting it stand for historical interest. I wrote this years ago; please don’t take it out of context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have to admit, I got unhealthily worked up about getting this score.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the purposes of college, I only ever wanted a score that wouldn’t be a deal-breaker — anything above 2300 would be enough. Any other time I had left would be better spent in other endeavors. Such endeavors might help on the college app, but more importantly, I’d also get to enjoy them.&lt;/p&gt;
So why am I here? Partly it’s because my classmates got worked up about it. Somebody specifically requested me to post my score somewhere. And partly it’s because there couldn’t be a better way at the moment to establish my authority to (yet again) rant against standardized tests here. 
&lt;blockquote&gt;
“Everyone is a genius. But if you judge a fish by its ability to climb a tree, it will live its whole life believing that it is stupid.”
&lt;p class=&#34;source&#34;&gt;
— &lt;a href=&#34;http://quoteinvestigator.com/2013/04/06/fish-climb/&#34;&gt;not actually Albert Einstein&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fiction</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/fiction</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2013 11:54:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/fiction</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“I like fantasy books! I used to read a lot of Eoin Colfer.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What does that mean, &lt;em&gt;used to&lt;/em&gt;? You don’t read anymore? That’s so &lt;em&gt;sa-a-a-ad&lt;/em&gt;…”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our teacher and I had this conversation during our first English class, and I realized I agreed with her. Well, no, of course I still read: news articles, r/AskReddit threads, and the books we get assigned in class. But not fiction, almost. As I later mentioned to my teacher, I followed Sam Hughes’ &lt;a href=&#34;http://qntm.org/ra&#34;&gt;Ra&lt;/a&gt; avidly (something I highly recommend). That was it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does my present self still think of Eoin Colfer? Although I adored the &lt;i&gt;Artemis Fowl&lt;/i&gt; books when I was younger, my interest faded, but not before I had recommended it to my sister. The conversation spurred me to get out the seventh &lt;i&gt;Artemis Fowl&lt;/i&gt; book, which I had stopped reading halfway through a year ago, and finish it. It was still true that I didn’t like it as much, because I couldn’t feel the high stakes strongly in the book and I found that the joking asides compounded the problem. But a few days later, when we took a trip to the Taipei library, I found the eighth book and borrowed it, plowing through nine-tenths of the book before we left. The ending seemed to be happy but still felt counterintuitively poignant for me. In any case, I had closure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what’s the lesson? Authors vary in output too. I was naïve to suppose that because I found this book boring, I had outgrown all books that were even vaguely similar. In the same trip, I also borrowed a bunch of other random fantasy books, plus a realistic fiction book about a teenage pregnancy, just for kicks. It turned out to be surprisingly good. In a week, I read four books, cover to cover, despite a typical load of homework and chemo.&lt;/p&gt;
Any excuses I made before about not having enough time simply don’t hold water. Still, I have yet to figure out if this sort of reading is sustainable, because not every book is so engrossing. Far from it… 
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a flip side, of course — writing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/test</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2013 21:58:01 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/test</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Parts of this (a majority of questions, I hope) are intended as satire. Other parts of this are silliness created to blow off steam from being coerced into spending nine unproductive hours. Still other parts exist simply because I wanted to have equally many questions per test. Also, 256th post w00t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;
“Verbal Reasoning”
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Directions:&lt;/em&gt; The questions in this test are multiple-choice. Each question has four possible choices. Read each question and decide which answer is the best answer. Find the row in your answer sheet that matches the number of the question. In that row, fill in the oval corresponding to the answer you selected. 
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
height : tall :: size :
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type:upper-alpha;&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
big
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
hot
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
random
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
soft
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;malapert : effrontery :: argute :&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matrix Intuition</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/matrix</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2012 17:01:29 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/matrix</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stopped by a friend’s house a few days ago to do homework, which somehow devolved into me analyzing what programming language I should try to learn next in a corner, which is completely irrelevant to the rest of this post. Oops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, in normal-math-curriculum-land, my classmates are now learning about matrices. How to add them, how to multiply them, how to calculate the determinant and stuff. Being a nice person, and feeling somewhat guilty for my grade stability despite the number of study hours I siphoned off to puzzles and the like, I was eager to help confront the monster. Said classmate basically asked me what they were for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, what a hard question. But of course given the curriculum it’s the only interesting problem I think could be asked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was hurrying through the high-school curriculum I remember having to learn the same thing and not having any idea what the heck was happening. Matrices appeared in that section as a messy, burdensome way to solve equations and never again, at least not in an interesting enough way to make me remember. I don’t have my precalc textbook, but a supplementary precalc book completely confirms my impressions and “matrix” doesn’t even appear in my calculus textbook index. They virtually failed to show up in olympiad training too. I learned that Po-Shen Loh knew how to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.math.cmu.edu/~ploh/docs/math/mop2009/alg-comb.pdf&#34;&gt;kill a bunch of combinatorics problems with them (PDF)&lt;/a&gt;, but not in the slightest how to do that myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhere else, during what I’m guessing was random independent exploration, I happened upon the signed-permutation-rule (a.k.a. &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leibniz_formula_for_determinants&#34;&gt;Leibniz formula&lt;/a&gt;) for evaluating determinants, which made a lot more sense for me and looked more beautiful and symmetric&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;math display&#34;&gt;\[\det(A) = \sum_{\sigma \in S_n} \text{sgn}(\sigma) \prod_{i=1}^n A_{i,\sigma_i}\]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On writing</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/on-writing</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2012 13:34:15 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/on-writing</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;warning&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: My 2012 self wrote this. It’s a bit dated, but it’s okay, and also is of historical interest for featuring me explaining the CSS I learned from English class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every time I notice that I have hoarded a large number of strange assignments and essays from another school year of work I get all guilty. First there’s the knowledge about ancient Chinese dynasties and plant hormones that I only have shadows of recollections of, which makes me wonder whether all the time and effort invested by teachers, classmates, and myself have gone wasted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know, though, that given that I still sense these shadows, it shouldn’t be difficult to look up and relearn this stuff if I ever need to do so. This brings me to the non-factual parts of the learning, such as writing skills with all its variations. There’s persuasive writing, which I don’t use much because I can’t usually even persuade myself to take a side in anything, let alone others. There’s descriptive writing mode, which I don’t use much because the most vividly describable things I encounter are food, and the shallowness of piling flowery adjectives together to talk about food just makes me cringe nowadays. Previously, I wrote at least two such compositions in sixth grade. Blech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glowstick Memories</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/glowstick</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2012 22:37:50 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/glowstick</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So. It looks like I’ve officially graduated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have to wonder whether it really means anything. Taiwan’s system classifies the grades neatly into 6/3/3 sections, but then our bilingual department also uses the somewhat illogical and faintly sexist freshman-sophomore-junior-senior naming thing, in which the big jump happened last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neither of these naming issues, of course, really matter. Shakespeare says, “A rose by any other name would smell as sweet.” Nor, I would think, do the different color of uniforms we have to wear (pink, if you didn’t know.) But AP classes probably count for something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am going to take AP Biology. Why did I pick AP Biology anyway? It seemed like a reasonable default choice. I guess I would like to know something more about the mysteries of life and consciousness to guide my philosophical side, and many of the other courses looked too murderously intense. The perfect stepping stones into the giant hamster wheel of overachievement that everybody is crazy about here. But then I learned I still received eight chapters to study by myself during summer vacation, alongside the English reading assignment. Oh well, so much for relaxation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know, I used to think of this issue, about all the academic work we students pile onto ourselves and all the ensuing stress and chaos, from a strange detached third-person viewpoint. Not everybody has a mind that is fit for all that brainwork. Some people have to do the artistic, imaginative things. Some people cannot function optimally in our intense learning environment. Somehow, imperceptibly, according to my apparently not-all-that-bad grades, I put myself in the crazy book-grinding category, and I am having second thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t feel the energy for all this intense future yet… The past is still so close, so vivid, so attractive. Our graduation trip, for instance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Note-taking</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/note-taking</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2012 18:43:09 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/note-taking</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Finally getting into geography honors. And surviving, somehow, with grades that still might count as ridiculous-in-a-good-way. The one big change I’m getting used to is the need to take actual hardcore &lt;em&gt;notes&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For eight years, most classes I’ve gone to, both inside or outside school, have been straight from a book or handout, which would be so easily read and comprehended (…to me) that any notes would be a waste of energy. A couple science teachers would make us take notes and count them as a grade. All you had to do to get an A was write down most of the important bits, even if the chapter sections were written in exaggerated cursive that took up half the page and there were random teddy bears straddling the margins, as in my notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a stage in maybe seventh grade where I told myself I would make neat, doodle-free notes that actually summarized the stuff in biology (the easy seventh-grade kind (not that we still remember all of it)), and to get to that goal I would force myself to use only one page for each section, with a special way to mark the vocabulary words. It helped studying a little, but the stage didn’t last, and I ended up doodling again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even when the going finally got tough and understanding became a nontrivial task, I still had irrelevant embellishments and a bunch of artificial fonts for my “notes”. Even in the days when I was free to go to the Chiao-Tung University for classes twice a week (and still get consistently ridiculous grades, judging by the score breakdowns the prof gave us after every test), my notes looked like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/notes-lhopital.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-1030&#34; title=&#34;L&#39;Hopital notes&#34; src=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/notes-lhopital.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;[L&#39;Hopital notes]&#34; width=&#34;474&#34; height=&#34;335&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
Exhibit A: mathematical analysis/advanced calculus notes, circa 2010
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bilingualism</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/bilingualism</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2012 22:11:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/bilingualism</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, as triggered by my confrontation with the Chinese book report (remember? whatever the answer is, it’s okay): a reflection on my incompetence at dealing with two languages, and why this matters, or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can think in both languages. It’s a natural product of our school environment. The two languages often have to complement each other; most of the nerdy terms or globally relevant allusions are English-exclusive (I couldn’t talk coherently about SOPA in any language other than English!), but a lot of cultural and geographical staples around here are Chinese only. And sometimes there are unexpected holes where an innocuous-looking phrase simply has a few too many connotations to translate perfectly (the example I always get stuck on, and have yet to solve satisfactorily with anything short of a full sentence recasting, is “appreciate”.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>