<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dancing on Bounded-Error Log</title>
    <link>//blog.vero.site/tag/dancing</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dancing on Bounded-Error Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2014 17:31:10 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//blog.vero.site/tag/dancing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>[IOI 2014 Part 1] Everything is More Exciting with Lightsabers</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/lightsabers</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2014 17:31:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/lightsabers</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Okay, I guess it was really naïve of me to suppose that I could get any considerable amount of blogging done before the IOI ended. Onward…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We left off at the end of the practice session. As if somebody were taking revenge against us for not having to suffer through any airplane trips, we were served a cold airplane meal for lunch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seriously, the box had a sticker that noted its manufacturer as something something Air Kitchen and another translucent sticker that badly covered an inscription saying the same thing in much bigger letters. It contained a cold apple salad, a cold chicken bun, a cold flat plastic cylinder of orange juice, and a package of plastic utensils that was exactly like the utensils that came with every airplane meal ever. I was disappointed, but at least the salad tasted okay, and I ate an extra one because two of my teammates volunteered theirs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To pass the time, we played an extra-evil &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ninety-nine_(addition_card_game)&#34;&gt;ninety-nine&lt;/a&gt; variant. Apparently this is a very Taiwanese game because lots of student guides were teaching their teams the game, although our special cards differ from the ones Wikipedia lists in a lot of ways and our evil variant created more opportunity for sabotage and counter-sabotage and bluffing. 7s are used to draw your replacement card from somebody else’s hand, and that person cannot draw again and will have one less card; aces are used to swap your entire hand with somebody else, who also cannot draw a card; small-value cards can be combined to form special values (e.g. play a 2 and 5 for the effect of a 7) but after playing a combination you can only draw one replacement card; and later, to speed up the game, we added a rule where all 9s had to be unconditionally discarded without replacement but would still get shuffled back into the draw pile. Players lose if it’s their turn and they have no playable cards, including no cards at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we were playing and repeatedly reveling in everybody ganging up to beat the winner from the last round, an instrumental version of “You Are My Sunshine” played on repeat in the background for literally the entire time. It wasn’t a very good version either. If you didn’t listen carefully for the fade-out and few seconds of silence at the end of each loop, you’d think that the loop was only one verse long.  After the miserable excuse for lunch, we entered the place the opening ceremony, and an orchestra played a few songs that I can finally hope gave the contestants a feeling of Taiwanese culture. I recognized &lt;a href=&#34;https://zh.wikipedia.org/zh-tw/%E6%9C%9B%E6%98%A5%E9%A2%A8&#34;&gt;「望春風」&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>