<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>blogging on Bounded-Error Log</title>
    <link>//blog.vero.site/tag/blogging</link>
    <description>Recent content in blogging on Bounded-Error Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 22:17:26 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//blog.vero.site/tag/blogging/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking a Step Back</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/step-back</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 22:17:26 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/step-back</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There’s some point in the decline of a blog’s activity at which you just can’t apologize with a straight face for not posting any more. Only ironically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I brainstormed reasons why I’m not blogging. It took a while for me to find a reason that felt right, but I think it’s mostly the concern that I don’t have anything important to say, and I’m just spamming people’s inboxes or Facebook feeds. I make fun of my perfectonist tendencies, but they haven’t gone away and have been exacerbated by how public this blog feels now. There’s also a general feeling permeating life that I should be trying to present myself professionally to people, because like a diamond, the Internet is forever.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Musings on Time Pressure</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/musings-pressure</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 15:44:20 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/musings-pressure</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I hate doing things under time pressure, but I have to admit I do a lot more things when time pressure exists. One of the things is writing. Another is posting the things I write. They aren’t very good, but they’re better than writing that doesn’t exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(in case you forgot, I’m still posting this pretty much only because &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/no-excuses&#34;&gt;I made myself post once every weekend&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s interesting that I can impose time pressure on myself by declaring commitment devices by fiat and it works. Other people have developed other methods of doing this — I recently discovered &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.themostdangerouswritingapp.com/&#34;&gt;The Most Dangerous Writing App&lt;/a&gt;, which puts time pressure on you to type every five seconds or it deletes everything you wrote. There are many other ways it’s done.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Excuses</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/no-excuses</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2016 14:08:54 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/no-excuses</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wow, this has been the longest silence on this blog in a long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can’t justify it with lack of time either. Interning at Dropbox takes up all of my weekdays, but my weekends are much freer than I’m used to. I carelessly let two weeks at home in Taiwan pass by without doing much about blogging, and once again a lot of my few blog drafts have drifted into the temporally awkward zone, being too far away from the events they are about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neither is it for lack of things happening. At MIT, there was the &lt;a href=&#34;http://thetech.com/2016/06/10/senior-house-turnaround-announced&#34;&gt;Senior House turnaround and freshman moratorium&lt;/a&gt;. I can’t even begin to sum up the discussion around this issue, but I think &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@hollyhaney/an-open-letter-to-chancellor-barnhart-from-a-senior-house-resident-efc107e789ab#.a1psbheao&#34;&gt;the best response I’ve read is this open letter&lt;/a&gt;. Then there’s the &lt;a href=&#34;http://seniorhouse.mit.edu/&#34;&gt;official Senior House response&lt;/a&gt;. But that’s enough links, since I imagine the chances that this issue is relevant to you &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; you’d need this blog to link you to them if you’re reading this are pretty low. (Then again, the chances that you’re reading this are already pretty low. Although the chances &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; are reading this right now is 100%.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pause</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/pause</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2015 16:03:56 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/pause</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are 30 minutes until my laundry finishes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is 2:30 in the morning as I write this. Normal people are not awake at this time of day. It’s possible that normal MIT students are, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been meaning to blog for a while, but things happen and other things happen and still more things happen. From a state of total inexperience in the kitchen, I’ve already managed to single-handedly cook six six-person meals for my co-op, not to mention all the weird meals I make for myself (which is just as well, I don’t think they are of typically mentionable caliber.) I’ve already taken two exams in three of my classes and the big midterm for my fourth. Four puzzlehunts — Simmons, aquarium, Palantir, ΣUMS; five if you perhaps include Next Haunt. Six SIPB meetings. A few bottles of Soylent; I lost count and don’t want to check my room because that’ll disturb my roommate. Θ(3000) zephyrs. And after many weekends of eye-opening group practice, tonight I have to catch a flight to Rochester, NY for ACM-ICPC regionals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sharpies</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/sharpies</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2015 14:59:48 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/sharpies</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As readers of this blog probably know, I am not an MITAdmissions blogger. It was kind of disappointing at the moment, but now I rarely think about it except when I come up with good reasons why I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be an MITAdmissions blogger. One reason is that I am not very good at coming up with advice that could generalize to a wide audience, even an audience only as wide as people at or coming to the &amp;lsquo;Tvte. &lt;em&gt;(There can be only one!)&lt;/em&gt; This by itself probably wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be so bad because there&amp;rsquo;s plenty of generalizable advice to go around, but I also don&amp;rsquo;t like repeating well-known stuff. Don&amp;rsquo;t skip class, except when you really know when you&amp;rsquo;re doing, which you probably think you do when you skip class. Get enough sleep, maintain good study habits, set aside time to keep up with old friends, back up your zarking data, alternate alcoholic and nonalcoholic drinks, do not forget the factor of one-half when computing the area of a triangle. You get the picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s only one piece of advice I can say that I believe is generalizable to any degree, and in particular I think my past self would have appreciated and also had not heard, even in passing, from any other source: Get a Sharpie.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C-c-c-Combo Breaker!</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/combo</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2015 07:10:20 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/combo</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I made it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/rekt&#34;&gt;misstep on the fourth day&lt;/a&gt; I managed to post one post every day, completing the rest of the &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/commitment&#34;&gt;streak&lt;/a&gt;! This post is scheduled to go out around the time my plane takes off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m free!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d insert a &lt;cite&gt;Frozen&lt;/cite&gt; gif here if I could find a good one, but I don’t like any of the ones I found and besides, copyright is an issue. So instead:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/cliques.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/cliques.png&#34; alt=&#34;source: Wikimedia Commons, public domain&#34; width=&#34;585&#34; height=&#34;468&#34; class=&#34;size-full wp-image-3257&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:VR_complex.svg&#34;&gt;Wikimedia Commons&lt;/a&gt;, public domain
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IMO2007.C6. In a mathematical competition some competitors are friends. Friendship is always mutual. Call a group of competitors a clique if each two of them are friends. (In particular, any group of fewer than two competitiors is a clique.) The number of members of a clique is called its size.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given that, in this competition, the largest size of a clique is even, prove that the competitors can be arranged into two rooms such that the largest size of a clique contained in one room is the same as the largest size of a clique contained in the other room.&lt;/p&gt;
Author: Vasily Astakhov, Russia
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you remember where I first posted this to break a combo, you have an excellent memory and/or spend too much time stalking me. If you remember the &lt;em&gt;context&lt;/em&gt; under which I posted this to break a combo, you have a better memory than I do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was my streak a success? On the bright side, I definitely generated lots of posts, many of which were radical departures from my old blogging habits:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/99&#34;&gt;card game documentation&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/nuclear&#34;&gt;weird short stories&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/nuclear-ii&#34;&gt;sequels to weird short stories&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
an essay (liberally defined) with &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/quixotic-1&#34;&gt;two&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/quixotic-2&#34;&gt;parts&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
an essay with &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/more-fiction-1&#34;&gt;two&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/more-fiction-2&#34;&gt;parts&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/more-fiction-2-5&#34;&gt;half&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
another &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/college-emails&#34;&gt;bar graph&lt;/a&gt; that is actually documented,
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
a ridiculous &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/phone&#34;&gt;literate Haskell post&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
numerous &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/1024&#34;&gt;facetious&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/zzz&#34;&gt;Paintbrush&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/double-post&#34;&gt;dragons&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
a &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/signal&#34;&gt;post about a post on a side blog&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/index-txt&#34;&gt;and&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/897&#34;&gt;of&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/drop-in&#34;&gt;course&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/a-list&#34;&gt;metric&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/sheep&#34;&gt;zarktons&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/2857&#34;&gt;of&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/numbers-bmp&#34;&gt;shameless&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/clicker&#34;&gt;filler&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also had lots of fun conversations about my posts, such as:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Commitment</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/commitment</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2015 08:43:25 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/commitment</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Obligatory life update: I have graduated &lt;a href=&#34;https://motivatedgrammar.wordpress.com/2012/01/24/a-brief-history-of-speaking-about-graduation/&#34;&gt;[from]&lt;/a&gt; high school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that’s not what this post is about. I &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/scheduled-blogging&#34;&gt;contemplated setting up a schedule for my blogging&lt;/a&gt; three long years ago, and decided against it, because I didn’t think writing was a high enough priority for me. Well, I am setting up a schedule now: &lt;strong&gt;I am going to post something on this blog every day&lt;/strong&gt; until I have to leave the country (which is happening once before college, so it’s not for as long as you think; but I might decide to continue the schedule anyway after I get back. We’ll see when the time comes.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>