<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Procrastination on Bounded-Error Log</title>
    <link>//blog.vero.site/category/procrastination</link>
    <description>Recent content in Procrastination on Bounded-Error Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2015 09:08:33 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//blog.vero.site/category/procrastination/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>College Emails</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/college-emails</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2015 09:08:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/college-emails</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Frivolous blog content, posted as part of a &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/commitment&#34;&gt;daily posting streak I have openly committed to&lt;/a&gt;; standard disclaimers apply)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of boredom and curiosity, I &lt;a href=&#34;https://betaveros.github.io/bars-college.html&#34;&gt;graphed how many emails colleges sent me&lt;/a&gt;, excluding the colleges I actually applied to. I am being extremely polite and just calling them emails. I’ve wanted to make this for a long time, but it wasn’t until I saw this &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/message/my-failed-experiment-in-time-travel-3aa2240a6bc0&#34;&gt;post about an email experiment&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;http://waxy.org/links/&#34;&gt;waxy.org/links&lt;/a&gt; that I understood which tools I could use to quantify my emails. (And then I actually made it and procrastinated posting it here for two months. If you look at my GitHub page or activity you might have seen it already, though. Oops.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t think the results were expected. Other than saying that, I leave the interpretation up to the reader because I’m on a tight blogging schedule. Cool? Cool.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>74 Days</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/74-days</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2013 18:14:21 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/74-days</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I did it!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/test</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2013 21:58:01 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/test</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Parts of this (a majority of questions, I hope) are intended as satire. Other parts of this are silliness created to blow off steam from being coerced into spending nine unproductive hours. Still other parts exist simply because I wanted to have equally many questions per test. Also, 256th post w00t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;
“Verbal Reasoning”
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Directions:&lt;/em&gt; The questions in this test are multiple-choice. Each question has four possible choices. Read each question and decide which answer is the best answer. Find the row in your answer sheet that matches the number of the question. In that row, fill in the oval corresponding to the answer you selected. 
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
height : tall :: size :
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type:upper-alpha;&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
big
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
hot
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
random
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
soft
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;malapert : effrontery :: argute :&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>