<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Taiwan on Bounded-Error Log</title>
    <link>//blog.vero.site/tag/taiwan</link>
    <description>Recent content in Taiwan on Bounded-Error Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2015 23:32:37 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//blog.vero.site/tag/taiwan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>[CIMC 2015 Part 3] Monsters and Pandas and Tigers, Oh My!</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/cimc-2015-part-3</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2015 23:32:37 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/cimc-2015-part-3</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My inner perfectionist is crying that I have to post this, in particular over my pathetic &lt;a href=&#34;http://snowclones.org/2007/05/22/x-y-and-z-oh-my/&#34;&gt;snowclone&lt;/a&gt; title, but my inner pragmatist knows that, judging by my old blogging patterns, it’s now or never.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;18.06: 56%, haven’t touched it in a while, but I think I can do lots more on the plane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a non-contestant, I confess I feel totally uninvested in the results and find the Closing Ceremony boring. All contestants go up, country by country, and have their awards read off. No effort is made to make any sort of buildup to a climax. But maybe this is for the best; we don’t want anybody feeling shafted or discouraged from continuing to do math due to a mere elementary-/middle-school competition. Meanwhile, though, I’m browsing reddit on my phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After this ceremony, the entire Taiwan delegation spends some time walking around outside while the guides make confused phone calls trying to decide where we eat lunch. My parents offer me some potato chips they bought somewhere, which are (as the label is really eager to point out) baked, not fried. Some time passes this way; eventually, the guides figure it out and we go through amazingly long queues to eat at the cafeteria, as usual. Then we are sent to a massive shopping mall for the afternoon, a place so large that its exits have number labels that go up into the double digits so that people don’t get lost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I take trippy failed panorama photos from the bus windows. &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/trippy-panorama.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/trippy-panorama.jpg?w=652&#34; alt=&#34;[trippy panorama of a shopping mall]&#34; width=&#34;652&#34; height=&#34;427&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter size-large wp-image-3321&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  The exit our group is supposed to use and remember is number 9. However, since just about everybody else from the competition is clustered around that exit, we choose to enter through a neighboring one, which is somewhat surprisingly numbered 5.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hunter on Vacation</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/hunter</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 16:18:58 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/hunter</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/rainbow.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/rainbow.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;Very faint rainbow&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
Faint rainbow
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So winter vacation started and parents had planned a trip to southern Taiwan, to get closer to nature and walk around and stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, the MIT Mystery Hunt, the absolute granddaddy of all the other puzzlehunts in terms of age, structure, and size, happened this weekend. Originally, I didn’t have a team and just planned to look at the puzzles after they got archived and &lt;s&gt;try solving some puzzles&lt;/s&gt; read the solutions while constantly thinking, “How could anybody ever solve that?” Because of that, I wasn’t planning to even bring my laptop at first; then I could force myself to study some long-overdue ring theory during the nights. I was taken aback by a private message on Saturday morning from somebody with many different names inviting me to remote-solve for Random Thymes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>English Names</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/english-names</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2012 23:08:46 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/english-names</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;warning&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: I wrote this in 2012. Maybe it’s kind of amusing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some reason, everybody around here seems to think that adding English characters, no matter how broken or meaningless, confers an added sense of quality or superiority. I don’t really understand the mindset here but it’s the only explanation I can come up with. It’s certainly not to make the lives of our English-speaking population any easier.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>