<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Taiwan on Bounded-Error Log</title>
    <link>//blog.vero.site/tag/taiwan</link>
    <description>Recent content in Taiwan on Bounded-Error Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2015 23:32:37 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//blog.vero.site/tag/taiwan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>[CIMC 2015 Part 3] Monsters and Pandas and Tigers, Oh My!</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/cimc-2015-part-3</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2015 23:32:37 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/cimc-2015-part-3</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My inner perfectionist is crying that I have to post this, in particular over my pathetic &lt;a href=&#34;http://snowclones.org/2007/05/22/x-y-and-z-oh-my/&#34;&gt;snowclone&lt;/a&gt; title, but my inner pragmatist knows that, judging by my old blogging patterns, it’s now or never.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;18.06: 56%, haven’t touched it in a while, but I think I can do lots more on the plane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a non-contestant, I confess I feel totally uninvested in the results and find the Closing Ceremony boring. All contestants go up, country by country, and have their awards read off. No effort is made to make any sort of buildup to a climax. But maybe this is for the best; we don’t want anybody feeling shafted or discouraged from continuing to do math due to a mere elementary-/middle-school competition. Meanwhile, though, I’m browsing reddit on my phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After this ceremony, the entire Taiwan delegation spends some time walking around outside while the guides make confused phone calls trying to decide where we eat lunch. My parents offer me some potato chips they bought somewhere, which are (as the label is really eager to point out) baked, not fried. Some time passes this way; eventually, the guides figure it out and we go through amazingly long queues to eat at the cafeteria, as usual. Then we are sent to a massive shopping mall for the afternoon, a place so large that its exits have number labels that go up into the double digits so that people don’t get lost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I take trippy failed panorama photos from the bus windows. &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/trippy-panorama.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/trippy-panorama.jpg?w=652&#34; alt=&#34;[trippy panorama of a shopping mall]&#34; width=&#34;652&#34; height=&#34;427&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter size-large wp-image-3321&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self vs. Other</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/self-vs-other</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2015 23:59:54 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/self-vs-other</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My mom says I blog too much about myself. I am completely guilty of that and this post is mostly not an exception. Sorry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not that I wouldn’t like to write posts about others and for others. But I know more about myself so obviously there’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/WriteWhoYouKnow&#34;&gt;more I can write about myself&lt;/a&gt;. It’s kind of a habit, and it’s been a very personally helpful habit. I discover lots of things when I write introspectively. But I’m a very weird person and a lot of the insightful things I discover when doing this are things I doubt I can generalize to other people. I tried getting a lot of my friends to join HabitRPG when I discovered it, but it was nowhere as effective on them as it was on me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What else could I blog about? What else do people blog about?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;World-event-inspired topics?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[IOI 2014 Part 4] Shades of Xanthous</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/xanthous</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2014 13:04:16 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/xanthous</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;No, I didn’t forget. Not for one minute. I was doing homework. I am very happy because that means I was actually carrying out my priorities as I envisioned them. I’ve probably edited this post too many times, though. Meh. But it’s the first weekend after finishing summer homework, so here we go again!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fun fact: This is by far my favorite post title in the entire series. Possibly in the entire history of this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the morning of the last day of official IOI activities, there were a bunch of cultural activities, e.g. writing Chinese characters calligraphically, doing tricks with the diabolo, or picking up beans with chopsticks, and noncultural activities, e.g. getting somebody to pour water into a cup on your head while he or she was blindfolded. Due to the last activity I got wet, but my shirt dried really quickly. And alas, even though I had taken calligraphy summer classes a long time ago, my calligraphy was awful — robotic, lifeless strokes without the right aesthetic proportions to make up for it. Blargh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, lunch followed, and then it was time for the closing ceremony, in the same building as the other ceremonies and contests. Our team caught the ending song of in a Chinese musical being rehearsed as we walked into the auditorium. While we waited for everybody, we milled about waving flags that our various teachers had brought, including not only Taiwan’s flag but also flags of my school, thoughtfully brought by teachers who had volunteered. A little later our leader told us that all the leaders had discussed the matter during a meeting and decided that we shouldn’t bring any flags to the stage while receiving our medals, so we were going to have to make do with being patriotic and school-respecting off stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were a few performances, including two aboriginal music performances and the musical we had seen rehearsed ealier, which was a fun rock musical rendition of some Chinese tale that seemed to have been sharply abridged, giving it the plot depth of a Wikipedia stub-article synopsis — a conflict, boy-meets-girl-and-falls-in-love, and a lamenting Aesop song conclusion with thrillingly vague general applicability. But the singing and counterpointing and atmosphere were good. I guess it was proportional to the relative importance of the performance to the closing ceremony. The program interleaved them with the long-awaited medal presentations: one round of bronze medalists, one round of silver, one round of gold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dum-dum-dum-dum, medals! The home team advantage was really obvious here; the cheering and the medal-presenter handshakes were both significantly more forceful for Taiwan’s medalists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/gold.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/gold.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;I think our leader made this. Thanks.&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
I think our leader made this. Thanks.
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Naturally, after the normal medals had been exhausted, the three full scorers received bags with prizes that may forever remain unknown to my sorry self, as well as a standing ovation from everybody in the auditorium. The orchestra had been going through ABBA songs during the ceremony, and very considerately played “The Winner Takes It All” for this part. It was impossible not to mentally fill in the lyrics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
The winner takes it all&lt;br /&gt;The loser has to fall&lt;br /&gt;It’s simple and it’s plain&lt;br /&gt;Why should I complaiiiiiiiin?
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speeches followed. Most were just average forgettable speeches, but Forster gave another speech that was somehow even better than the one he gave at the opening ceremony, with nonstop golden quotables such as:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hunter on Vacation</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/hunter</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 16:18:58 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/hunter</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/rainbow.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/rainbow.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;Very faint rainbow&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
Faint rainbow
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So winter vacation started and parents had planned a trip to southern Taiwan, to get closer to nature and walk around and stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, the MIT Mystery Hunt, the absolute granddaddy of all the other puzzlehunts in terms of age, structure, and size, happened this weekend. Originally, I didn’t have a team and just planned to look at the puzzles after they got archived and &lt;s&gt;try solving some puzzles&lt;/s&gt; read the solutions while constantly thinking, “How could anybody ever solve that?” Because of that, I wasn’t planning to even bring my laptop at first; then I could force myself to study some long-overdue ring theory during the nights. I was taken aback by a private message on Saturday morning from somebody with many different names inviting me to remote-solve for Random Thymes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Me: !!!!!!!!!!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>English Names</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/english-names</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2012 23:08:46 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/english-names</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;warning&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: I wrote this in 2012. Maybe it’s kind of amusing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some reason, everybody around here seems to think that adding English characters, no matter how broken or meaningless, confers an added sense of quality or superiority. I don’t really understand the mindset here but it’s the only explanation I can come up with. It’s certainly not to make the lives of our English-speaking population any easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were sharing songs in Chinese class with literary techniques, and there were a bunch of songs, including mine, by this pretty famous singer with the stage name &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fish_Leong&#34;&gt;Fish Leong&lt;/a&gt;. Okay, it’s kind of cute and it’s a translated homophonic Cantonese pun, so it makes some sense, although I wonder what people would think the name meant if mentioned without any context. There was this more obscure guy a couple seasons back in the reality TV singing competition (see, no original shows around here) whose name was Quack. &lt;em&gt;smacks head&lt;/em&gt; It’s also kind of cute if you only know that the word is the sound a duck makes, which probably holds for most of the audience. But still, it takes just five seconds to &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quack&#34;&gt;put it into Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;. Oops?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>