<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>gridderface on Bounded-Error Log</title>
    <link>//blog.vero.site/tag/gridderface</link>
    <description>Recent content in gridderface on Bounded-Error Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2015 13:01:08 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//blog.vero.site/tag/gridderface/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 46 / Fillomino [LITS &#43; Extra Region &#43; Walls &#43; Anti-Walls &#43; Inequality &#43; Tapa &#43; Masyu]</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-46</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2015 13:01:08 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-46</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
5:27 PM &lt;strong&gt;phenomist&lt;/strong&gt;: do you use gridderface to make pretty puzzles?&lt;br /&gt;
…&lt;br /&gt;
5:52 PM &lt;strong&gt;phenomist&lt;/strong&gt;: actually nvm excel is probably easier lol
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay I’m sorry this is a horrible puzzle where the rules don’t make sense and I didn’t even get it testsolved. I just wanted an image to concisely demonstrate the capabilities of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/betaveros/gridderface&#34;&gt;gridderface&lt;/a&gt;, my puzzle marking and creation program, for the project homepage, after somebody expressed interest in using the program to write a puzzle. Then I got tremendously carried away.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 36 / Fillomino [LITS]</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-36</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 18:29:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-36</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mathgrant.blogspot.tw/2012/11/monday-mutant-119-polyominous-tetra.html&#34;&gt;mathgrant’s hybrid type&lt;/a&gt;: a Fillomino (write a number in every empty cell so that every group of cells with the same number that is connected through its edges has that number of cells) where each tetromino has had their 4s replaced by one of L, I, T, or S describing their shape, and they obey the rules of LITS — they can touch if they are not congruent, they must all be connected, and their squares cannot form a 2x2 block.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gridderface 0.5</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/gridderface-0-5</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2012 17:53:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/gridderface-0-5</guid>
      <description>Okay, I give up. Here it is: Gridderface is a (quoting the project description, which I wrote anyway so whatever) “keyboard inferface for marking grid-based puzzles in Java” that I’ve been working on for too long. It is open-source under the GPL v3.
Basically, it’s a thing you can paste logic puzzle images into to solve them in, like people do in Paint, when you can’t or don’t want to print them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>