<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>notes on Bounded-Error Log</title>
    <link>//blog.vero.site/tag/notes</link>
    <description>Recent content in notes on Bounded-Error Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2012 18:43:09 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//blog.vero.site/tag/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Note-taking</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/note-taking</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2012 18:43:09 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/note-taking</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Finally getting into geography honors. And surviving, somehow, with grades that still might count as ridiculous-in-a-good-way. The one big change I’m getting used to is the need to take actual hardcore &lt;em&gt;notes&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For eight years, most classes I’ve gone to, both inside or outside school, have been straight from a book or handout, which would be so easily read and comprehended (…to me) that any notes would be a waste of energy. A couple science teachers would make us take notes and count them as a grade. All you had to do to get an A was write down most of the important bits, even if the chapter sections were written in exaggerated cursive that took up half the page and there were random teddy bears straddling the margins, as in my notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a stage in maybe seventh grade where I told myself I would make neat, doodle-free notes that actually summarized the stuff in biology (the easy seventh-grade kind (not that we still remember all of it)), and to get to that goal I would force myself to use only one page for each section, with a special way to mark the vocabulary words. It helped studying a little, but the stage didn’t last, and I ended up doodling again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even when the going finally got tough and understanding became a nontrivial task, I still had irrelevant embellishments and a bunch of artificial fonts for my “notes”. Even in the days when I was free to go to the Chiao-Tung University for classes twice a week (and still get consistently ridiculous grades, judging by the score breakdowns the prof gave us after every test), my notes looked like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/notes-lhopital.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-1030&#34; title=&#34;L&#39;Hopital notes&#34; src=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/notes-lhopital.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;[L&#39;Hopital notes]&#34; width=&#34;474&#34; height=&#34;335&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
Exhibit A: mathematical analysis/advanced calculus notes, circa 2010
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>