<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cars on Bounded-Error Log</title>
    <link>//blog.vero.site/tag/cars</link>
    <description>Recent content in cars on Bounded-Error Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2015 15:31:12 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//blog.vero.site/tag/cars/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2^10 Words</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/1024</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2015 15:31:12 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/1024</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Vacuous content for &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/commitment&#34;&gt;posting streak&lt;/a&gt;. Disclaimers apply, particularly “entirely unlike anything previously on this blog”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/cars&#34;&gt;Like I said&lt;/a&gt;, studying. Furiously.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scary Cars</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/cars</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2015 22:27:14 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/cars</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Part of a &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/commitment&#34;&gt;daily posting streak&lt;/a&gt; but for once I don’t think I need to apply the disclaimers to this. If you thought for even one second that the title was a palindrome, I’ve succeeded. It’s not. I don’t have a good title. Okay, maybe slap the disclaimers onto that part.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first time I drove a car was on 5/18. I think. I might be off by a day or so. Most of that day’s lesson was spent learning to go forward and backward, accelerate and decelerate smoothly, and turn the wheel without getting my hands tangled up. My coach made me count out loud how many circles I was turning: 一圈半圈半圈一圈etc. It felt kind of stupid when I was doing it, but I guess in the end it helped, and eventually once I got the hang of turning the wheel, I just subvocalized it and my coach also tacitly stopped bothering me about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first time I activated a turn signal light was probably on 5/26. That was the day I wrote in my TIL log that, when you turn the steering wheel back from the direction you were turning, the turn signal lights turn off automatically. After you think about it, this is a pretty sensible thing for turn signal lights to do, but when I first learned this my mind was utterly blown. Wow!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s like when you’re turning and you turn on the turn signal and it starts clicking this steady beat to increase the dramatic tension, like you’re doing a trick in a sports driving game and you have to quickly hit the right sequence of buttons on the controller. Then you actually turn the corner and then turn the wheel back, and as the wheel makes its smooth sliding sound back to its upright position, the beat stops like a resounding V7 to I resolution, as if to congratulate you on executing a beautiful turn without crashing into another car or driving off the side of the road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s what it feels like, anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On slow days, when you’re halfway through a turn but the drivers ahead of you are waiting in a queue that stretches on forever on the practice track, you can shift to the parking gear and use the turn signal’s beat as a metronome and sing along to it too. I do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or, of course, there’s the obligatory xkcd:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/turn_signals.png&#34; alt=&#34;xkcd&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>