<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hardware on Bounded-Error Log</title>
    <link>//blog.vero.site/tag/hardware</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hardware on Bounded-Error Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2014 21:30:53 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//blog.vero.site/tag/hardware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>[IOI 2014 Part 0] Waiting</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/waiting</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2014 21:30:53 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/waiting</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yes, I know day 1 of the contest already ended and is probably a more interesting topic to blog about, but I finished writing this last night just before the internet was cut off to quarantine the contestants from the leaders, who received the problems and began translating them. I didn’t know about this until it was too late, which is why I’ve been waiting since yesterday to post this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To provide a counterpoint to the last post, one of the many, &lt;em&gt;many&lt;/em&gt; advantages of entering an international competition is that you get to meet a lot more people you already know, so there’s less time spent being socially awkward. While waiting for stuff to happen, aside from all the expected time spent with the Taiwan team, I also talked to, played games with, and otherwise entertained a whole lot of people I already knew, including my schoolmates (no less than fourteen of them were volunteers) and some of the college students who had shepherded us around during olympiad training.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which is a good thing, too, because there was a lot of waiting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First I waited for my teammates; my parents had decided to take me to the hotel (Fullon Shenkeng) directly, since I had a lot of stuff, and I had arrived early. This took about an hour, after which we had lunch. Then I waited for the hotel to give us our room cards, which took about five hours, after which we had dinner. Finally, at night, I waited for the Codeforces system tests. Very nerve-wracking. But I’m getting ahead of myself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>