<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>me in 2004 on Bounded-Error Log</title>
    <link>//blog.vero.site/tag/me-in-2004</link>
    <description>Recent content in me in 2004 on Bounded-Error Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2015 23:57:41 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//blog.vero.site/tag/me-in-2004/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Tests (and a Mysterious New Student)</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/old-tests</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2015 23:57:41 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/old-tests</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Short &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/commitment&#34;&gt;streak&lt;/a&gt; post. And for the uninformed, I’m using &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spivak_pronoun&#34;&gt;Spivak pronouns&lt;/a&gt; for this post just because.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally, when people I don’t already know through math competitions ask me or my parents about something like how to teach their intelligent child to make em really good at math, or even English or whatever, I am skeptical by default because there seem to be a lot of Taiwanese parents who have alarmingly rigid and largely baseless expectations or assumptions about what their children ought to be interested in and excel at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can lead a horse to water, and honestly I think you could find a way to force it to drink if you really wanted to, but you can’t make it enjoy the process of being force-fed. Um. &lt;a href=&#34;https://english.stackexchange.com/questions/36489/eat-is-to-feed-as-drink-is-to-what&#34;&gt;Force-watered? Force-hydrated?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can teach your child math and English, and you could make em ace all eir tests, but you probably can’t make em enjoy the test so much that e decides to create more diabolical versions of these tests to give to eir fictional characters in eir stories for fun!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are all &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;actual illustrations&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; from the old stories I mentioned in &lt;a href=&#34;https://betaveros.wordpress.com/2015/07/24/more-fiction-part-2-5/&#34;&gt;part 2.5 of “More Fiction”&lt;/a&gt;. Stories I wrote in 2004. As a first-grader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is kind of horrifying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/test6blurred.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/test6blurred.png?w=652&#34; alt=&#34;test6blurred&#34; width=&#34;652&#34; height=&#34;458&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter size-large wp-image-3231&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>