<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Graduation on Bounded-Error Log</title>
    <link>//blog.vero.site/tag/graduation</link>
    <description>Recent content in Graduation on Bounded-Error Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2015 09:34:22 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//blog.vero.site/tag/graduation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Glowstick Fragments</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/fragments</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2015 09:34:22 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/fragments</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/glowstick&#34;&gt;Echoes.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the HSR we kill time with weird games from Kevan Davis’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://kevan.org/fdgp/&#34;&gt;Freeze-Dried Games Pack&lt;/a&gt;, mostly Thirty-One. Then we’re there!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the bus we kill time with karaoke, until people complain. Sorry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lunch at Chinese restaurant. Beach resort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spend the first one and a half hours holed up in my hotel room watching television, first a quiz show where the host asks foreigners living in Taiwan questions about the country’s culture and society, then Disney and Cartoon Network cartoons. During the commercial breaks I do cryptic crosswords I had brought along. This is something I self-deprecatingly talk about for the rest of the trip, but I have no regrets because the three cartoons I watch are literally my top three guilty pleasure cartoons, &lt;cite&gt;Ben 10&lt;/cite&gt;, &lt;cite&gt;Teen Titans Go!&lt;/cite&gt;, and &lt;cite&gt;Jake Long: American Dragon&lt;/cite&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I wander around and join some guys playing pool. I do better than I expect, once pocketing three balls in sequential moves. There is also a Kinect with a dancing game, which I also score surprisingly well at and have lots of fun playing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dinner, in which I eat 小卷 (“pencil squids”?) with way way way too much wasabi. I stuff myself and walk around chatting and eventually learn there are freshly-made 手卷 (“&lt;i&gt;temaki&lt;/i&gt;” / “hand roll”) downstairs. Since there’s lots of time I wait until I’m less full and eat two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Group activity outside corresponds eerily to the one three years ago: shouting, dancing, waving glowsticks, arbitrary dance moves, punishment games, cooperation games, a competition where the guide gives out points that don’t matter like on &lt;cite&gt;Whose Line Is It Anyway?&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Empty promises… but okay. Class songs. (This is the explicit version. This song is well above the normal offensiveness rating of this blog and I usually prefer official videos, instead of shady lyric videos probably made from Windows Movie Maker that might get taken down, but honestly I find the pathetic execution of censorship in the VEVO version more offensive.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ins date=&#34;2019-02-05T16:58:07-0500&#34;&gt;
edit from the future: There used to be an explicit YouTube video of Shots by LMFAO ft. Lil Jon here, which has since been taken down for obvious reasons. Yes, it is a very crude song. I never went to a party that was a tenth as wild as the song describes. Maybe it was my means of vicarious escape.
&lt;/ins&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glowstick Memories</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/glowstick</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2012 22:37:50 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/glowstick</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So. It looks like I’ve officially graduated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have to wonder whether it really means anything. Taiwan’s system classifies the grades neatly into 6/3/3 sections, but then our bilingual department also uses the somewhat illogical and faintly sexist freshman-sophomore-junior-senior naming thing, in which the big jump happened last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neither of these naming issues, of course, really matter. Shakespeare says, “A rose by any other name would smell as sweet.” Nor, I would think, do the different color of uniforms we have to wear (pink, if you didn’t know.) But AP classes probably count for something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am going to take AP Biology. Why did I pick AP Biology anyway? It seemed like a reasonable default choice. I guess I would like to know something more about the mysteries of life and consciousness to guide my philosophical side, and many of the other courses looked too murderously intense. The perfect stepping stones into the giant hamster wheel of overachievement that everybody is crazy about here. But then I learned I still received eight chapters to study by myself during summer vacation, alongside the English reading assignment. Oh well, so much for relaxation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know, I used to think of this issue, about all the academic work we students pile onto ourselves and all the ensuing stress and chaos, from a strange detached third-person viewpoint. Not everybody has a mind that is fit for all that brainwork. Some people have to do the artistic, imaginative things. Some people cannot function optimally in our intense learning environment. Somehow, imperceptibly, according to my apparently not-all-that-bad grades, I put myself in the crazy book-grinding category, and I am having second thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t feel the energy for all this intense future yet… The past is still so close, so vivid, so attractive. Our graduation trip, for instance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>