<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>coding on Bounded-Error Log</title>
    <link>//blog.vero.site/tag/coding</link>
    <description>Recent content in coding on Bounded-Error Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2012 22:11:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//blog.vero.site/tag/coding/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Technological Fails Continue</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/technological-fails-continue</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2012 22:11:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/technological-fails-continue</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;warning&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: My 2012 self wrote this. It is preserved for historical interest and amusement, and does not reflect my current beliefs or attitudes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hardware:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The laptop I’m typing this on is over two years old. This is not a lot by some measures, but weird spontaneous glitches are starting to accumulate to the point where they’re getting on my nerves. The internet card still needs an extra reset to start working half the time, and occasionally warrants a full reboot, which costs five minutes. The USB ports are loopy, some windows just show up black when they feel like it, and there’s a steadily climbing whir in the background. I’m kind of anticipating the moment the whole thing just drops dead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I’m not about to run out of computers to use (there’s a noisy XP desktop that also barely works despite handling all our print jobs, but also one spanking new eight-core CPU laptop, which Dad considered a valuable enough investment (?)) but such a loss is still not something to be dismissed lightly. And the externalized cost is far more important and chilling. Who knows how many kids in the Congo had to mine coltan, or how much conflict has occurred over the crude oil, or what awful conditions those sweatshop-assembly workers are going through? Annie Leonard’s words still resonate with me from when we were first shown the video a year ago. Which is more recent than this laptop, so that doesn’t mean that much. I think a couple months ago I would have absolutely no second thoughts about getting a new one, though. Yup, I’m in a quandary (ha ha vocabulary) on the balance between desensitization and compulsive hoarding of stuff.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>