<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Media on Bounded-Error Log</title>
    <link>//blog.vero.site/tag/media</link>
    <description>Recent content in Media on Bounded-Error Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 12:26:52 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//blog.vero.site/tag/media/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s Complicated</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/complicated</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 12:26:52 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/complicated</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On November 8th, 2016, Donald Trump was elected the 45th President of the United States. Along with a Republican House and Senate majority, to boot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world around me is still hurting and reeling from the shock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make no mistake, I am scared. I am scared of the policies and executive orders and legal decisions to come that may strip away many civil rights and send the environment down a worse track faster than anyone expected, and I’m barely in any of the groups that have the most to lose. I have no idea what it’s like to go through this as any of you. I am sorry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I am also scared that this fear is driving my friends and my community away from talking to the people we need to talk to if we want to make sure this doesn’t happen again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve heard a lot of people vilify Trump and Trump supporters. &lt;a href=&#34;https://nmnnmnnmmnnnmnrnmnmnnmn.wordpress.com/2016/11/09/1067/&#34;&gt;Anecdotally, so have others&lt;/a&gt;. It’s an understandable reaction, but a fragile one. 60 million people voted for Trump. &lt;a href=&#34;http://waitbutwhy.com/2016/11/its-going-to-be-okay.html&#34;&gt;Quoting &lt;em&gt;Wait But Why&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, “[P]eople with kids and parents and jobs and dogs and calendars on their wall with piano lessons and doctors appointments and birthday parties written in the squares. Full, three-dimensional people who voted for what they hope will be a better future for themselves and their family.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People voted for Trump. Why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://fivethirtyeight.com/features/trumps-base-is-blue-collar-his-voters-looking-for-a-return-to-better-times/&#34;&gt;FiveThirtyEight profiling a few blue-collar voters&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/wonk/wp/2016/11/08/a-new-theory-for-why-trump-voters-are-so-angry-that-actually-makes-sense/&#34;&gt;The Washington Post interviewing an author who spent a lot of time in rural Wisconsin&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2016/11/11/us/politics/the-women-who-helped-donald-trump-to-victory.html?smid=fb-nytimes&amp;amp;smtyp=cur&#34;&gt;The New York Times on women&lt;/a&gt;. If the articles’ reasons for voting Trump could be summarized in one word, it would certainly be “economy”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then FiveThirtyEight tempers it a little bit with this reminder that &lt;a href=&#34;http://fivethirtyeight.com/features/the-mythology-of-trumps-working-class-support/&#34;&gt;Trump’s supporters are on average more well-off than others&lt;/a&gt;. Here’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2016/07/11/george-saunders-goes-to-trump-rallies&#34;&gt;The New Yorker visiting a bunch of Trump rallies&lt;/a&gt;. SupChina discusses &lt;a href=&#34;http://supchina.com/2016/11/03/many-first-generation-chinese-immigrants-supporting-donald-trump/&#34;&gt;first-generation Chinese immigrants supporting Trump&lt;/a&gt; and racism is a bullet point there, but apparently it’s partly rallied around rap lyrics about robbery that advise to “find a Chinese neighborhood” to steal from, so…? I am not going to go any deeper into this rabbit hole. Then here’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.motherjones.com/kevin-drum/2016/03/trump-voters-are-not-angry-about-economy-really&#34;&gt;Mother Jones arguing against the economy being a big factor at all&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2016/10/15/13286498/donald-trump-voters-race-economic-anxiety&#34;&gt;Vox saying it &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; about racial resentment&lt;/a&gt;. Here’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bloomberg.com/view/articles/2016-11-11/revenge-of-the-deplorables&#34;&gt;Bloomberg on the Clinton campaign’s failure to persuade&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://thefederalist.com/2016/11/11/how-jon-stewart-and-the-daily-show-elected-donald-trump/&#34;&gt;The Federalist on “hyper-liberal late-night comedy”&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.washingtontimes.com/news/2016/nov/9/donald-trump-and-the-new-american-revolution/&#34;&gt;The Washington Times on Trump’s optimism&lt;/a&gt;. I could find hundreds more out there just by Googling, and so could you; and chances are if you’re enough of a voracious reader to be reading my humble blog, you’ve already read some of these.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Islam, Headlines, and Definitions</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/islam-headlines</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2016 15:29:43 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/islam-headlines</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post’s topic might be the most controversial thing I’ve posted here ever. I hope the points I want to make aren’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the excuses for not blogging I came up with and then deleted while &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/no-excuses&#34;&gt;rambling about not blogging&lt;/a&gt; was that I’m getting more feelings about real-world real-person issues, things that people take heated positions on — it’s not topics like what food I ate or what games I’m playing in fourth grade any more — and my identity is pretty public here, so who knows what’ll happen. Oh well. I’m probably just paranoid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s also delayed, as the articles I’m talking about are old; the latest two news items are the shootings of Alton Sterling and Philando Castile and then the police shooting at the Dallas rally. That was also really sad, but I don’t think I have anything insightful to say about it. Let me point you to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://mitadmissions.org/blogs/entry/black-lives-matter&#34;&gt;MIT Admissions post, “Black Lives Matter”&lt;/a&gt;, and then for something a bit more optimistic out of a huge range of possible choices, &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@Mandela/my-white-boss-talked-about-race-in-america-and-this-is-what-happened-fe10f1a00726#.wtnr99lp1&#34;&gt;this Medium article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although after I started writing this post, the story about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.indiatimes.com/news/world/muslim-man-hugs-isis-militant-armed-wearing-suicide-vest-before-explosion-saves-hundreds-of-lives-258126.html&#34;&gt;a Muslim man preventing an ISIS suicide bomber&lt;/a&gt; came out, so now this is mildly relevant again. Anyway, I guess the delay is no different from how I put up life posts weeks after the life event happens. So today, I bring you two old news articles about Islam that my friends shared and discussed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Green: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/todd-green-phd/is-islam-responsible-for-_b_10449060.html&#34;&gt;Is Islam Responsible For The Orlando Nightclub Shooting?&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
King: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nydailynews.com/news/world/king-isis-terrorists-aren-muslims-evil-men-article-1.2699463&#34;&gt;ISIS terrorists aren’t Muslims — they’re just evil men hell-bent on carnage and destruction&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
The second one first, whose argument is, to be frank, weak. I think this piece from &lt;cite&gt;The Atlantic&lt;/cite&gt; by Wood, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2015/03/what-isis-really-wants/384980/&#34;&gt;“What ISIS Really Wants”&lt;/a&gt;, is a better-researched overview of ISIS while still being pretty readable. One caveat is that it’s somewhat old. But its central claim is quite the opposite: 
&lt;blockquote&gt;
[The] Islamic State is Islamic. &lt;em&gt;Very&lt;/em&gt; Islamic. … [T]he religion preached by its most ardent followers derives from coherent and even learned interpretations of Islam.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a long, long piece, so to get a feel for the evidence, here are some key quotes:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[IOI 2014 Part 4] Shades of Xanthous</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/xanthous</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2014 13:04:16 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/xanthous</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;No, I didn’t forget. Not for one minute. I was doing homework. I am very happy because that means I was actually carrying out my priorities as I envisioned them. I’ve probably edited this post too many times, though. Meh. But it’s the first weekend after finishing summer homework, so here we go again!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fun fact: This is by far my favorite post title in the entire series. Possibly in the entire history of this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the morning of the last day of official IOI activities, there were a bunch of cultural activities, e.g. writing Chinese characters calligraphically, doing tricks with the diabolo, or picking up beans with chopsticks, and noncultural activities, e.g. getting somebody to pour water into a cup on your head while he or she was blindfolded. Due to the last activity I got wet, but my shirt dried really quickly. And alas, even though I had taken calligraphy summer classes a long time ago, my calligraphy was awful — robotic, lifeless strokes without the right aesthetic proportions to make up for it. Blargh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, lunch followed, and then it was time for the closing ceremony, in the same building as the other ceremonies and contests. Our team caught the ending song of in a Chinese musical being rehearsed as we walked into the auditorium. While we waited for everybody, we milled about waving flags that our various teachers had brought, including not only Taiwan’s flag but also flags of my school, thoughtfully brought by teachers who had volunteered. A little later our leader told us that all the leaders had discussed the matter during a meeting and decided that we shouldn’t bring any flags to the stage while receiving our medals, so we were going to have to make do with being patriotic and school-respecting off stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were a few performances, including two aboriginal music performances and the musical we had seen rehearsed ealier, which was a fun rock musical rendition of some Chinese tale that seemed to have been sharply abridged, giving it the plot depth of a Wikipedia stub-article synopsis — a conflict, boy-meets-girl-and-falls-in-love, and a lamenting Aesop song conclusion with thrillingly vague general applicability. But the singing and counterpointing and atmosphere were good. I guess it was proportional to the relative importance of the performance to the closing ceremony. The program interleaved them with the long-awaited medal presentations: one round of bronze medalists, one round of silver, one round of gold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dum-dum-dum-dum, medals! The home team advantage was really obvious here; the cheering and the medal-presenter handshakes were both significantly more forceful for Taiwan’s medalists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/gold.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/gold.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;I think our leader made this. Thanks.&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
I think our leader made this. Thanks.
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>