<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mnemonics on Bounded-Error Log</title>
    <link>//blog.vero.site/tag/mnemonics</link>
    <description>Recent content in mnemonics on Bounded-Error Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2015 23:45:41 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//blog.vero.site/tag/mnemonics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>MIT Course Number Mnemonics</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/mit-mnemonics</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2015 23:45:41 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/mit-mnemonics</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I first realized it might be helpful to start trying to remember the correspondence between MIT courses and their numbers, I expected a list of mnemonics for this correspondence would be one of those Things That Should Exist On the Internet. I’m pretty surprised it doesn’t. I mean, MIT has, what, &lt;a href=&#34;http://web.mit.edu/facts/alum-association.html&#34;&gt;at least 100,000 alumni&lt;/a&gt;; as far as I know, nearly everybody who goes there speaks the number correspondence fluently, so they have to learn it; and the science of mnemonics has been with us since the ancient Greeks and people who understand its usefulness can’t be uncommon, especially not in such a prestigious institute of higher education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What gives?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure. Maybe it’s just that nobody has posted their mnemonic set on the Internet out of embarrassment? My mnemonics are pretty bad too, but hey, &lt;a href=&#34;https://meta.wikimedia.org/wiki/Cunningham%27s_Law&#34;&gt;Cunningham’s Law&lt;/a&gt; — if you’re reading, feel free to add better ones in the comments, or to criticize my horribly unenlightened and stereotypical characterizations of your courses, to make this thing better. Or maybe it’s out of concern that nobody else will find it useful? I get that feeling but my &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/commitment&#34;&gt;streak&lt;/a&gt; compels me to ignore it now, as it has for the last dozen posts or so. Or maybe they just didn’t optimize for search engine findability, so I can’t find it? I hope this post fixes that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually, I guess the most likely reason is that maybe most people don’t actually have &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; the course numbers memorized with perfect recall, only the handful of most common ones they and their friends are in, and it’s perfectly fine to ask for clarification when an unknown number comes up in conversation, so nobody ever feels like they need to bother with mnemonics for every single course. Feels sensible to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But anyway, I’m not most people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most comprehensive resource of courses and numbers, including their history, appears to have once been at &lt;code&gt;http://alumweb.mit.edu/clubs/sandiego/contents_courses.shtml&lt;/code&gt;. Many, many links point there. Unfortunately, it is dead and I cannot find its new home, if it has one. Fortunately, there is an &lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.is/xViRP&#34;&gt;archived version on archive.is&lt;/a&gt;; on the other hand, I am not sure whether any updates have occurred since it was archived. A more recent version with course populations from 2005 is &lt;a href=&#34;http://web.mit.edu/mollieb/www/blog/MIT%20course%20numbers.html&#34;&gt;this chart&lt;/a&gt; linked from the MIT Admissions blog post &lt;a href=&#34;http://mitadmissions.org/blogs/entry/numbers_are_names_too&#34;&gt;Numbers are names too&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>