<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Names on Bounded-Error Log</title>
    <link>//blog.vero.site/tag/names</link>
    <description>Recent content in Names on Bounded-Error Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 20:27:44 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//blog.vero.site/tag/names/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>More Fiction (Part 2.5)</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/more-fiction-part-2-5</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 20:27:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/more-fiction-part-2-5</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is not Part 3. It’s just two things I thought of tacking on to &lt;a href=&#34;https://betaveros.wordpress.com/2015/07/04/more-fiction-2/&#34;&gt;part 2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What can I say? Part 2s are easy blog post fodder; Part 2 appendixes are even easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One, there’s one other wall I run into often during those rare attempts when I get motivated enough to try to write a story: naming characters is hard. At least, it provides an excellent motivational roadblock whenever I even consider committing a story to paper, a point before I’ve actually written anything at which I think “maybe I should give up and go on Facebook instead” and proceed to do so. Aggh. And I think there’s more than one reason for this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
I have trouble coming up with names to some degree. Sure, it’s easy to browse BabyNames.com and look for choices, but a lot of the names there are really weird and contemplating them for every unimportant character kind of rips me out of the immersed mindset.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Reading great stories in English class and elsewhere may have gotten me feeling like every name ought to be a deep meaningful allusion, or at least pun fodder. I feel like I will regret it if I write a story and, a few months and/or chapters down the road, realize I missed a better name or the name I chose has some undesirable connotations in context or provides an atmosphere-ruining coincidence.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I think the real kicker is simply that some part of me is terrified of the awkwardness of giving a character the same name as anybody I know, because then they might read the story and wonder if the character is somehow based on them. And too many of the names that I consider common enough to not lure readers off into looking for hidden meanings are used up that way. This is obviously worst if the character is an antagonist. But it seems just as awkward if the character is a protagonist in accord with everything I’ve written, i.e. a paper-thin character blatantly created for escapist purposes. I am already kind of terrified I might ever meet anybody with the same name as one of my mentally established characters even though I haven’t actually written anything about him. And there’s a well-established convention of &lt;a href=&#34;http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/OneSteveLimit&#34;&gt;not reusing a first name in a work&lt;/a&gt;, so this gets even harder with every work; I’m just as worried, what if somebody thinks this character is related to the other character in that story I wrote in second grade? Oh no!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s like not reusing variable names in a programming language where everything is in the same scope. Positively nightmarish.&lt;/p&gt;
And I actually discovered some evidence this is a thing in my past: I found some stories I wrote in 2004. They are possibly the most extreme exemplification of &lt;a href=&#34;http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/WriteWhatYouKnow&#34;&gt;Write What You Know&lt;/a&gt; imaginable: the main character, Michael, goes to school and makes friends. That’s all.
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/illustration.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/illustration.png&#34; alt=&#34;Illustration courtesy Brian2004&#34; width=&#34;540&#34; height=&#34;543&#34; class=&#34;size-full wp-image-3223&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
Illustration courtesy Brian&lt;sub&gt;2004&lt;/sub&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I kind of want to share these stories, but fast-forward a few years and you’ll see that a classmate named Michael entered my grade and we stayed in the same grade until we graduated.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>