<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>puzzle on Bounded-Error Log</title>
    <link>//blog.vero.site/tag/puzzle</link>
    <description>Recent content in puzzle on Bounded-Error Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 10:34:38 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//blog.vero.site/tag/puzzle/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Puzzlehunts</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzlehunts</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 10:34:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzlehunts</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;series&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;not part of the ongoing series, but you can almost pretend it is. This sentence and the one before it are not a puzzle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine a word search.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now imagine you aren’t told what words to look for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now imagine you aren’t told it’s a word search.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now imagine it isn’t a word search.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;footer&gt;
— &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gmpuzzles.com/blog/2013/04/ask-dr-sudoku-13-puzzle-hunting/&#34;&gt;Mike Develin, via Thomas Snyder&lt;/a&gt; (aka Dr. Sudoku)
&lt;/footer&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post aims to be a fairly comprehensive introduction to puzzlehunts and their puzzles, a single post where I can just point people. I erred towards comprehensiveness in this post because I am not aware of any similar resources, especially for puzzlers interested in trying harder puzzlehunts who might not know any more experienced puzzlers to solve with. It’s possible to start solving some puzzles after reading much shorter guides, e.g. Puzzled Pint’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.puzzledpint.com/files/3513/8254/7894/2013_10_22_Puzzling_Basics_Infographic.pdf&#34;&gt;“Puzzling Basics” (PDF)&lt;/a&gt;, so feel free to skip around, stop reading midway through, or bookmark this to read only after you’ve spent more time solving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-a-puzzlehunt&#34;&gt;What is a Puzzlehunt?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;puzzlehunt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an event where people, usually in teams, solve a series of &lt;strong&gt;puzzles&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not a very useful definition. The more interesting question is, what is the kind of “puzzle”&lt;a href=&#34;#fn2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that appears in a puzzlehunt? The concept of a puzzlehunt puzzle is fuzzy and difficult to define precisely. Just about any hard rule one might try to state will be broken by some puzzle, sometimes deliberately. Still, here are some common features of puzzlehunt puzzles:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018 MIT Mystery Hunt</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/2018-hunt</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 19:39:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/2018-hunt</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My third MIT Mystery Hunt with ✈✈✈ Galactic Trendsetters ✈✈✈ (also see: &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/january&#34;&gt;2017&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/whoosh&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt;, writing with Random in &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/hunt&#34;&gt;2015&lt;/a&gt;). It was a good hunt with a fun theme, solid puzzles, and extraordinary production quality, marred only by a fickle unlock structure and a handful of unnecessarily involved extractions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we had been told the hunt would be smaller than past years’ (now a controversial statement since the coin was &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; found particularly early) and we didn’t particularly want to win (yet), part of our team temporarily split off this year to hunt as Teammate. Based on our Discord channel, ✈✈✈ Galactic Trendsetters ✈✈✈ had 75 people this year, including remote solvers and people who dropped in and out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A short description of the hunt structure: This year’s hunt theme was &lt;em&gt;Inside Out&lt;/em&gt;, the Disney movie about anthropomorphized emotions. This was revealed through a kickoff that demonstrated the hunt’s extraordinary production quality, in which we watched the unveiling of the Health &amp;amp; Safety hunt, first directly, then in the Control Room with the emotions of a distraught hunter (Miss Terry Hunter) and a lot of beautiful memory orbs and scenery. After Terry’s emotions became overwhelmed in response to the theme, we had to help her emotions to allow her to complete the Health &amp;amp; Safety hunt. The intro round took place in the Control Room; we had to solve 34 regular puzzles and five metapuzzles (somewhat overlapping, with some regular puzzles belonging to more than one metapuzzle) to help each of the five emotions get back to the Control Room. The rest of the hunt consisted of recovering memory orbs from each of four Islands of Personality, each of which had its own theme and meta structure, and which we could choose the unlock order of.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I guess January is puzzles month</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/january</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2017 14:27:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/january</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;And it’s not even January any more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Thing negative two: Thing zero, which is at the bottom of this post, contains two puzzles by me. Skip there if that sounds interesting and text walls don’t.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thing negative one: I abandoned this blog (again). The last month has been a mess and much of it is political stuff of the sort that I’m the worst/slowest at writing about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thing one: I was on-site for a second MIT Mystery Hunt.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>whoosh</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/whoosh</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 08:19:46 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/whoosh</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I finally did it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was on-site for the 2016 MIT Mystery Hunt. I even &lt;em&gt;solved a metapuzzle&lt;/em&gt;. This year I hunted with ✈✈✈ Galactic Trendsetters ✈✈✈, the team primarily but not overwhelmingly formed from floorpi, my dorm floor. (Perhaps somewhat regrettably, I didn’t contribute to any events or runarounds or things given to HQ, unless you count attending a “recitation” for Student Simulator (round King Arthur, second from left).)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Also, I made this post. Has it been two weeks already? Okay, that’s not an unusual timeframe.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But wow, I got to touch so many puzzles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Non-spoilery comments on particularly memorable puzzles I did, which are disproportionately programming-related, if anybody wants to look at them (I am describing how to get to the puzzle from the round instead of linking because I’m lazy and links might rot but the instructions will hopefully survive archival (although turns out there’s actually a &lt;a href=&#34;http://huntception.com/toc.html&#34;&gt;table of contents&lt;/a&gt; so I don’t know what I’m doing)):&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three for the Price of One (Meta)</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/three-for-one</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2015 13:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/three-for-one</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;And that’s another year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As usual, &lt;a href=&#34;http://bpchen.scripts.mit.edu/2015/&#34;&gt;you can check your answers here.&lt;/a&gt; Text above this horizontal rule is not part of the puzzle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solvers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol type=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yoshiap @ 11-20 13:31:56&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When Is My Birthday Again?</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/birthday-again</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 13:00:25 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/birthday-again</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As usual, &lt;a href=&#34;http://bpchen.scripts.mit.edu/2015/&#34;&gt;you can check your answers here.&lt;/a&gt; Text above this horizontal rule is not part of the puzzle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solvers (in my local UTC−5 because I’m lazy):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol type=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lewis Chen (phenomist) @ 11-19 05:03:07&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jack Lance @ 11-19 10:39:11&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yoshiap @ 11-20 03:29:54&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anticron</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/anticron</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2015 13:00:59 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/anticron</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I did not get this successfully testsolved, although, for whatever comfort it may provide, I did engage in several interactive rounds of nerfing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As usual, &lt;a href=&#34;http://bpchen.scripts.mit.edu/2015/&#34;&gt;you can check your answers here.&lt;/a&gt; Text above this horizontal rule is not part of the puzzle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solvers:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Signature Puzzle</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/signature-puzzle</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2015 13:00:06 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/signature-puzzle</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As usual, there had to be something here. In fact, this year, there are several somethings. Hype!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is based on an idea by chaotic_iak. &lt;a href=&#34;http://bpchen.scripts.mit.edu/2015/&#34;&gt;You can check your answers here.&lt;/a&gt; Text above this horizontal rule is not part of the puzzle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ins datetime=&#34;2015-11-17T21:15:09+00:00&#34;&gt;
ETA 11/17 16:15 UTC−5: Adjusted spacing between the bottom numbers after feedback. The puzzle is otherwise the same, and solving should not be significantly impacted.
&lt;/ins&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solvers (in my local UTC−5 because I’m lazy):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol type=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yoshiap @ 11-17 18:28:34&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Throwback Thursday Puzzles!</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/tbt-puzzles</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 23:39:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/tbt-puzzles</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wow, there are so many cool things in my old folder. I could probably create and schedule enough filler posts to make my &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/commitment&#34;&gt;streak&lt;/a&gt; last through my week-long trip and back. I guess I won’t, though, because I don’t want to dilute my textwall-draft brand more than necessary and there are a few text posts that I fully intend to post before leaving. Or at least one. Although on second thought, it’s possible they might actually not be as interesting as posts like this one about the adorable me from the past. As Pablo Picasso once said, “Youth has no age.” (Yes, I totally just went on BrainyQuote and searched for “youth”. Forgive me, please.) Oh well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today’s throwback theme is old puzzles! Particularly picture ones! In reverse chronological order by last modified time, because I said so! All the image puzzles are puzzlehunty in the sense that you’re supposed to end up with a single word or short phrase as your final answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;p06pre2&#34;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;art/hidd3n/p06pre2.png&lt;/code&gt; (2010/10/31)
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/p06pre2.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/p06pre2.png&#34; alt=&#34;p06pre2&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3210&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; A straightforward one to start. I have no idea what’s with the filename, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;purity2logic&#34;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;haxxor/purity2/logic.html&lt;/code&gt; (2010/10/10?)
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My file hierarchy is really weird. I don’t think this time stamp is when I wrote the puzzle because it was part of a silly static site setup I created (but never actually put anywhere), and I probably edited and regenerated stuff like the breadcrumbs many times, but it’ll have to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is also funny because the title of the HTML file is “Logic Puzzles” and the description starts, “These puzzles were made when I was really bored…”, but there’s only one puzzle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, it’s better than an under construction page, I guess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll quote the entirety of the old instructions as I wrote them, even though they’re really verbose, since it’s easy to scroll past them:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mortality</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/mortality</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 21:00:51 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/mortality</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Faux-philosophical blog content, posted as part of a &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/commitment&#34;&gt;daily posting streak I have openly committed to&lt;/a&gt;; standard disclaimers apply)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a hard essay to write because (1) it’s very irrational and I should (and I do) know better — death by car accident is much more likely than death by an airplane crash, but the latter is scarier because it’s more vivid and we have less control over it, and (2) people don’t like talking about it. When I tried writing it, though, I realized I already burned through most of the down-to-earth worries in the posts I made between April and August of 2010. They still coherently and accurately sum up my current thoughts surprisingly well. And most of the irrational, overly philosophical fears appeared in &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/midnight&#34;&gt;Thoughts at Midnight&lt;/a&gt;. So there used to be a lot of fluff here like this, which was inducing procrastination because I don’t know what to include and what to cut, but now that I have a daily deadline, I cut most of it. Here’s what’s left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One, xkcd:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/leaving.png&#34; alt=&#34;xkcd&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two, bonus quote: As really-long-term readers know, I have had a reason to think that I might actually die in the past few years, a real reason that has stayed with me and gotten me thinking now and then about what &lt;em&gt;my&lt;/em&gt; meaning of life is, instead of a short-lived fuzzy philosophical feeling obtained from reading &lt;cite&gt;Tuesdays with Morrie&lt;/cite&gt; (which is not to say that &lt;cite&gt;Tuesdays with Morrie&lt;/cite&gt; isn’t a good book; I just suspect no book can convey everything a personal experience can.) Anyway, it’s over in all likelihood, but the point is that in the middle, I wrote an essay for class in ninth grade, which I find equally coherent and equally representative of my views. The conclusion runs thus:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2015 MIT Mystery Hunt</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/hunt</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 11:45:50 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/hunt</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, it’s been over a week, which is a long time for blog posts to be delayed after the event they’re documenting in probably all of the world except my blog. So.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess this post should start with a bit of background. I’ve been puzzlehunting for… wow, three and a half years now. I was introduced to puzzlehunts from AoPS, when some fellow members got together a team for &lt;a href=&#34;http://puzzle.cisra.com.au/2011/teamstats_AoPS.html&#34;&gt;CiSRA 2011&lt;/a&gt;, and I think I’ve participated to some degree in every known internet Australian puzzlehunt since.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But as for my experience with the MIT Mystery Hunt in particular, I sort of hunted with a decidedly uncompetitive AoPS team in 2012 (I think we solved one puzzle exactly), but my serious hunting career began when dzaefn recruited me into the Random team (then Random Thymes) &lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/post/hunter&#34;&gt;for the 2013 hunt&lt;/a&gt; (and I did blog obliquely about it). We didn’t win (and I actually didn’t participate that much because I was traveling with family) but the next year (as One Fish Two Fish Random Fish Blue Fish (1f-2f-17f-255f (I am evidently in a parentheses mood today because as you’ve probably noticed, the amount and depth of parentheses in this sentence are positively alarming (lol)))) we won.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I do have a half-written post about that which will never get posted (and I &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; didn’t participate that much, because my family was moving that weekend) but okay, let’s just drop any semblance of chronological coherence on this blog and dump a short version of the list of puzzles and parts towards which I contributed solving, as I wrote them down one year ago:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commemorating Obvious Milestones Involving Chronological Sustenance</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/comics</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/comics</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, there had to be something here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately I don’t have time for anything more complex, so here’s a low-effort illogical puzzle for the occasion. (It &lt;em&gt;has&lt;/em&gt; been testsolved, at least. Thanks, Yoshiap.) It also features a brand new category, so as not to distract the people on LMI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don’t already know what occasion it is, it’s easy to find out by looking through my archives or possibly anywhere else I’ve left a trail online. Or you could solve the puzzle! (Or you could &lt;ins datetime=&#34;2014-11-20T12:29:52+00:00&#34;&gt;scroll down to read the solution!&lt;/ins&gt;) If this puzzle had an answer, it would be a nine-letter word, although like most of mathematics, it’s less about the answer than about the path you take to get there…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ins datetime=&#34;2017-11-24T18:36:41-0500&#34;&gt;
2017 edit: A warning that this has somewhat linkrotted and is harder to solve, but theoretically still possible.
&lt;/ins&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MUMS Puzzle Hunt 2013</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/mums</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2013 21:44:24 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/mums</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/informatix.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//blog.vero.site/img/informatix.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;Informatix [MUMS Puzzle Hunt 2013]&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I somehow managed to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ms.unimelb.edu.au/~mums/puzzlehunt/teamstats.html?team=not+AoPS&#34;&gt;get 25 points all by myself&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ms.unimelb.edu.au/~mums/puzzlehunt/&#34;&gt;MUMS Puzzle Hunt 2013&lt;/a&gt;. Well, I pestered chaotic_iak a little with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ms.unimelb.edu.au/~mums/puzzlehunt/2013/puzzles/3.3_Diagnosus_ghQ3AcbJ.html&#34;&gt;3.3 Diagnosus (.html with animated .gif)&lt;/a&gt; but we still didn’t recognize all the Pokémon until hint 3, at which point Google sufficed for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is nowhere near the top, but compared to the usual results of whatever AoPS team I form, it’s amazing. By far the best result of AoPS was on CiSRA in 2010 (46th with 58 points), before I discovered puzzle hunts in AoPS; unfortunately due to people getting older and the influx of younger and younger people to the fora, there are less possible teammates each year and they have less time, so here I am by myself. (Also I could have accepted an invitation from a guy in the some-form-of-Elephant team, but I figure if you can win two MUMS hunts in a row you don’t need any more people.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all: Yay!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gridderface 0.5</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/gridderface-0-5</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2012 17:53:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/gridderface-0-5</guid>
      <description>Okay, I give up. Here it is: Gridderface is a (quoting the project description, which I wrote anyway so whatever) “keyboard inferface for marking grid-based puzzles in Java” that I’ve been working on for too long. It is open-source under the GPL v3.
Basically, it’s a thing you can paste logic puzzle images into to solve them in, like people do in Paint, when you can’t or don’t want to print them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>