<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>double back on Bounded-Error Log</title>
    <link>//blog.vero.site/tag/double-back</link>
    <description>Recent content in double back on Bounded-Error Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2015 00:25:46 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//blog.vero.site/tag/double-back/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 49 / Triple Back</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-49</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2015 00:25:46 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-49</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m not really satisfied with the execution, but eh, what the hell. My brain can only function at so much of its full capacity when it’s a few kilometers up in the sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://mellowmelon.wordpress.com/2009/12/20/puzzle-135/&#34;&gt;Triple Back&lt;/a&gt;, variant on &lt;a href=&#34;https://mellowmelon.wordpress.com/double-back/&#34;&gt;MellowMelon’s Double Back&lt;/a&gt;. Briefly, draw a closed loop through all square centers visiting each bold-outlined area exactly three (= ⌊π⌋) times. Shaded cells do not influence solving, only aesthetics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 48 / Double Back</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-48</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2015 23:15:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-48</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At least one person wants me to post. I’m not even going to try do a life summary. It’s too hard. Let’s just say:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
right now, my blog drafts contain a backlog of ~7500 words and counting;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
I was not accepted as an MIT Admissions blogger, which is bad because my blogging will continue to not reach a large audience, but good because my blogging will continue to not reach a large audience. Maybe it had something to do with the fact that, because the application form wouldn’t let me submit without any media, I panickedly cranked out the following puzzle in an hour or so to attach.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 35 / Double Back</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-35</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2013 22:42:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-35</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is another &lt;a href=&#34;https://mellowmelon.wordpress.com/double-back/&#34;&gt;MellowMelon’s Double Back&lt;/a&gt;. Briefly, draw a closed loop through all square centers visiting each bold-outlined area twice. Shaded cells do not influence solving, only aesthetics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s mostly easy, I think. It’s okay if you don’t know what the theme means. (Yes, chao, I want more contrib points.) Also, WordPress seems to have stopped automatically linking images to their files. Hmm.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 26 / Double Back</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-26</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2012 08:48:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-26</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;That’s not a picture. Why is it recreated as one? Oh well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can interpret this as me about reaching level 8.1 (the user ranking) on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rankk.org/&#34;&gt;rankk&lt;/a&gt; or complaining about how infuriating level 8.1 (the puzzle) is. I’m torn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one of a bunch of &lt;a href=&#34;https://mellowmelon.wordpress.com/double-back/&#34;&gt;MellowMelon’s Double Backs&lt;/a&gt;. Briefly, draw a closed loop through all square centers visiting each bold-outlined area twice. Shaded cells do not influence solving, only aesthetics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 25 / Double Back</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-25</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2012 08:40:02 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-25</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most uncreative picture ever! But it’s suitable after &lt;a href=&#34;http://puzzle.cisra.com.au/&#34;&gt;CiSRA’s Puzzle Week&lt;/a&gt;. This might be the first time our AoPS team managed all four puzzles in a group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;…sigh, now I must handle the guilt for squeezing out so much time from my normal schedule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one of a bunch of &lt;a href=&#34;https://mellowmelon.wordpress.com/double-back/&#34;&gt;MellowMelon’s Double Backs&lt;/a&gt;. Briefly, draw a closed loop through all square centers visiting each bold-outlined area twice. Shaded cells do not influence solving, only aesthetics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle 24 / Double Back</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-24</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2012 08:26:11 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/puzzle-24</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Right, back to puzzles because I have nothing substantial to say. Circumstantial evidence suggests I created this one in June.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one of a bunch of &lt;a href=&#34;https://mellowmelon.wordpress.com/double-back/&#34;&gt;MellowMelon’s Double Backs&lt;/a&gt;. Draw a closed loop through all square centers visiting each bold-outlined area twice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
