<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Internet Strangers on Bounded-Error Log</title>
    <link>//blog.vero.site/tag/internet-strangers</link>
    <description>Recent content in Internet Strangers on Bounded-Error Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2012 09:32:45 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//blog.vero.site/tag/internet-strangers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>[IMO 2012 Part 3] Luggage Carriers and Language Barriers</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/luggage-language</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2012 09:32:45 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/luggage-language</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Who knew coming up with strangely cryptic and illogical but nice-sounding post titles was so much fun!?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, this break in storytelling is mainly brought to you by generic summer laziness, as well as possibly a tiny bit of chemotherapy adverse effect. There is only a little perfectionism involved, and that’s because this post contains a long awkward situation (you might have guessed already). I guess this is what it feels like to have oodles of stuff to blog about, but not enough motivation. Heck, these few days with running the TAIMC have long filled my list of rant topics with juicy stories until it’s near-bursting. But I need to end this self-pity party before I get carried away, so… back to the action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stranded in a foreign country at least 20 degrees Celsius below our comfort zone, having worn the same clothes for 36 hours of airplane travel, and still with less than 48 hours until the contest and &lt;em&gt;zero out of six compasses&lt;/em&gt;, we were running out of options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A quick inventory of clothes showed that, after including the vests and caps in the backpacks we got, we probably had just enough clothes to survive the cruel frigid environment. So, reluctantly, we left the games room and hit the street to hunt down some underwear and socks to change into. Not to mention toothbrushes and some T-shirts and jackets for good measure, because the inside of the hotel was not the right temperature for full cold-resistance gear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some haphazard wandering up and down the streets later, we found a store that suited our needs and picked up some clothes. The underwear came in two sizes: too loose and too tight. We picked the latter. Oh well, it would only be for a day or so… right?  And so that was our first day without our luggage. We survived. My iPod finally ran out of battery the second day while furiously refreshing my email, trying to stay connected and update everybody. The schedule marched ahead without us.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>