<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>immodesty on Bounded-Error Log</title>
    <link>//blog.vero.site/tag/immodesty</link>
    <description>Recent content in immodesty on Bounded-Error Log</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2012 19:22:49 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//blog.vero.site/tag/immodesty/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Coup de Grâce</title>
      <link>//blog.vero.site/post/coup-de-grace</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2012 19:22:49 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.vero.site/post/coup-de-grace</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yes, it’s official now. I’m on the 2012 International Mathematical Olympiad team bound for Argentina, and if I didn’t make a post about this I would be ashamed to call myself a blogger. So, a little moment of smug self-satisfaction should be justified, I hope? And not to mention, last year’s title of youngest Taiwan contestant is not yet passed? Let’s cue the evil laughter!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/toot.png&#34; alt=&#34;Obligatory xkcd where a guy pops up and toots a literal air horn&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;…or maybe not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a simple tabulation of our selection problems:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol type=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GA/GN/CG/GNC/NGA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AG/CA/NG/GCN/AGA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GA/GN/CA/GCN/AGC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Algebra x9, Combinatorics x7, Geometry x12, Number Theory x8. In other words a distribution in perfect negative correlation with my estimated ability in each subject. At least, that’s how I’ve always estimated them before about a month ago. Ouch, the last stage was the only one of the three where problem distribution for combinatorics actually reached its fair share. (Alternative interpretation: 2011’s distribution was majorly f123ed up with only one real geometry problem, which just means that this year’s battle will probably be difficult for me. (Alternative alternative interpretation: the evil, nasty, wicked, depraved windmill was actually an outrageous negative for me. Gee, I don’t know how to feel. But I should actually do stuff instead of wildly speculating; let’s get back to the topic.))&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>